<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide.atom"/>
  <title>Flybird Fitness - Guide</title>
  <updated>2022-05-14T00:32:15+08:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/get-workout-ready-with-flybird-adjustable-dumbbells</id>
    <published>2022-05-14T00:32:15+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-05-14T00:32:16+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/get-workout-ready-with-flybird-adjustable-dumbbells"/>
    <title>Get Workout Ready with Flybird Adjustable Dumbbells</title>
    <author>
      <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Workout preparation can easily cost you thousands of dollars, and even then, you may not be guaranteed to have the type of results that you want. So what is a person to do if they want to work out but don't want to spend this kind of money? They buy Flybird Adjustable Dumbbells!<p><a class="read-more" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/get-workout-ready-with-flybird-adjustable-dumbbells">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>If you are serious about working out, then being able to bring the gym to you is a must. That's why Flybird adjustable dumbbells have become so popular. They allow you to create a weight-training routine that will fit into your busy schedule, no matter where you are.<br><br>You're probably wondering why you should pay full price for a pair of dumbbells when you can buy an adjustable pair, such as the Flybird Adjustable Dumbbells. You'd be correct in that thinking! You see, having a pair of adjustable dumbbells actually provides many benefits for your workout. Over time, you get to slim down and sculpt your muscles and tone. Having adjustable dumbbells also means having a wide range of weight on hand. This makes it great in allowing you to choose which weight would work best for your goal.</p>
<p>Whether you're a beginner or a seasoned pro, Flybird Adjustable Dumbbells are the perfect tool to help you reach your fitness goals.<br><br>Flybird adjustable dumbbells are designed to give you the ability to workout more efficiently. Whether you're looking for a way to get stronger, tone up or lose weight, these adjustable dumbbells will help you achieve your goals faster than ever before.<br><br><strong>Here's how:</strong><br><br><strong>No more wasting time changing weights.</strong> Instead of spending valuable time loading your weights and then cleaning up after each exercise, simply set your desired weight and start working out. The Flybird dumbbells adjust from as low as 1 lb all the way up to 100 lbs per hand so you can change exercises with ease.<br><br><strong>Save money!</strong> Adjustable dumbbells are less expensive than buying multiple sets of fixed weight dumbbells. You'll also save money on storage space since they take up less room than multiple sets of fixed weight dumbbells. Plus, they're safer than traditional style dumbbells because they don't have any loose parts or sharp edges that can harm you or others nearby during use.<br><br><strong>Stay focused!</strong> With Flybird Dumbbells, it's easy to stay focused on what matters most - getting into great shape</p>
<p><a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/dumbbells" title="Flybird Adjustable dumbbells">Flybird Adjustable Dumbbells</a> are the perfect solution for those with limited space.<br><br>With adjustable dumbbells, you can get a full body workout in a small amount of space.<br><br>You can also use Flybird Adjustable Dumbbells to work out your arms, legs, back and chest.<br><br>The best part about these dumbbells is that they are so easy to use! Simply adjust them to the weight you need and start lifting!</p>
<p>Get Workout Ready with Flybird Adjustable Dumbbells<br><br>You can use Flybird Adjustable Dumbbells at home or the gym, wherever you need it.<br><br>The Flybird Adjustable Dumbbells are the best and most versatile dumbbells you can get for your home workout routine. The flybird adjustable dumbbells are great for both beginners and experienced lifters alike.<br><br>The Flybird Adjustable Dumbbells come in a set of two dumbbells that fit all sizes of people, from kids to adults. You can adjust them from 5 pounds to <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/products/flybird-55lbs-adjustable-dumbbell" title="Flybird 55lbs adjustable dumbbells">55 pounds</a> each, giving you a total of 110 pounds of weights that you can use to increase strength and tone up your body fast!</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/5-simple-ways-you-can-meal-plan-without-thinking-too-hard</id>
    <published>2022-05-10T21:03:15+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-05-10T21:03:16+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/5-simple-ways-you-can-meal-plan-without-thinking-too-hard"/>
    <title>5 Simple Ways You Can Meal Plan Without Thinking Too Hard</title>
    <author>
      <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[You really don't have to be a professional chef to whip up a delicious home-cooked meal. With these 5 simple tips you can Meal Plan without thinking too hard, and always have something new and interesting to look forward to.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/5-simple-ways-you-can-meal-plan-without-thinking-too-hard">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>I'm sure you've heard it countless times before. 'Eat balanced meals'. 'Maintain a healthy diet.' 'You need to meal plan.' But what are the easiest ways to do meal planning without thinking hard? Is there a way I can plan out my meals and not drag myself down and make it really simple? In other words, is there a way I can meal plan which doesn't take long but I'm still getting foods that are good for me?<br><br>It shouldn't be that hard to figure out what time you're gonna make dinner. But it can be, especially if you have date night with your boo, a girls night out, or just a good old fashioned sleepover with your BFF. </p>
<p>Meal planning is the secret to staying on track with your healthy eating goals. It can also take up a lot of time.<br><br>So if you're short on time, how do you meal plan without having to think too hard about it?<br><br>Here are five simple tips for meal planning:</p>
<h2>
<br>1. Keep a running list of your family's favorite meals.</h2>
<p>This is the easiest way to start meal planning — just look back at what worked last week and note it down. It might take a few weeks before you have a good sense of what works for your family, but once it's established, it'll be much easier to make decisions about what to eat each day.2. Plan around leftovers. Leftovers are awesome because they take less time to make than fresh meals, which means more time for relaxing!3. Stock up on staples when they're on sale or when you see them in the store and freeze them for later (like fruits and veggies).4. Cook extra portions of dinner so you have leftovers for lunch the next day (or vice versa). This is especially helpful if there's something that reheats really well (like soup or chili).5. Keep an eye out for recipe ideas online and pin them.</p>
<h2>2. Use what you have on hand.</h2>
<p>If you're starting from scratch, take inventory of what ingredients are already in your kitchen (and consider any staples that might be lurking in your pantry). Use this as a jumping-off point for creating meals and snacks, even if they seem random at first glance. For example, if there's one egg left in the carton and some leftover rice, it might be time for fried rice! If there's some tortilla chips in the pantry and some leftover vegetables from last night's dinner, it might be time for nachos! You get the idea.</p>
<h2>3. Pick one or two nights a week to get creative.</h2>
<p>Whether it's tacos or burgers, pizza or pasta, every now and then, we all need something different for dinner. Thankfully, there's no rule against mixing it up once in awhile — just make sure to stick with your usual grocery store rotation and include some staples like protein and veggies (and maybe even brown rice if you're going Asian). You'll have enough on your plate when it comes to having fun with your meals without worrying about what ingredients you'll need for the next seven days.</p>
<h2>4. Create a shopping list that matches your meal plan.</h2>
<p>When you know what you're going to cook for dinner each night, it's easier to create a shopping list that matches those meals. So if you have tacos on Monday night, buy the ingredients for tacos instead of just getting ground beef and tortillas. If you're having lasagna on Tuesday night (and who isn't?), buy all the ingredients for lasagna instead of just putting them in your basket at random. This will save both money and time in the long run because you won't need to go back to the store later on when all you really wanted was cheese or chicken broth but forgot about it when you were at the store last time.</p>
<h2>5. Don't be afraid to repeat your weekly menus throughout the year.</h2>
<p>Here's nothing wrong with having some "regular" meals on your menu — especially if they're ones your family loves. If you make tacos every week, there's no need to keep reinventing them; just add new toppings or fillings each time so they feel fresh and exciting again! You can even take this approach with breakfast or dessert — if your family loves pancakes or chocolate chip cookies, they'll probably enjoy them just as much if you have them once a week instead of twice or three times per month.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Just about everyone has meal plan ideas. Make lunches the night before. Always have frozen meals on hand for those busy days. Use Pinterest for recipes. Grill every weekend. The list goes on and on. The real challenge is making it easy and acting on these meal plan ideas, consistently and without fail. Here are 5 easy ways to do just that; you're ready to start cooking!</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/workouts-for-stay-at-home-moms</id>
    <published>2022-05-06T21:24:41+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-05-06T21:24:41+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/workouts-for-stay-at-home-moms"/>
    <title>Workouts for Stay at Home Moms</title>
    <author>
      <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[As a stay at home mom, you already know that exercise isn't the first thing on your mind every day. And I'm talking about some serious hard core exercise, not just a short walk or trip to the park.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/workouts-for-stay-at-home-moms">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>If you're a stay-at-home mom, you have the right to exercise and be healthy just like the rest of us. But with kids screaming and possibly other things that must be done around the house, it can be hard to find time to exercise on a regular basis. Ladies, no need to get stressed out! Here are some simple ways for you to get yourself moving every day!<br><br>Being a stay at home mom is hard work. Between raising your kids and helping keep the house in order, you may not have time to go to the gym and lift. Nevertheless, staying active is important for your overall health and wellness. One of the best things about <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/dumbbells" title="Flybird adjustable dumbbells">Flybird adjustable dumbbells</a> is that you can use them from home.</p>
<h2>Here are five workouts for stay-at-home moms</h2>
<h3>Plank</h3>
<p>Planks are great for strength training, particularly in your core and lower back. If you have any lower back pain or issues with your pelvis, a plank is a great way to strengthen and stabilize those areas. Planks also work on your shoulders, arms and chest.</p>
<p><strong>To do a plank:</strong></p>
<p>Get into a push-up position with your forearms on the ground, elbows bent at 90 degrees and your body forming a straight line from head to heels. Your feet should be about hip-width apart and toes should be pointed out slightly. Lower yourself down onto your forearms so that only your toes and forearms are touching the ground (if this is too difficult, you may also place your hands on an exercise ball). Hold this position for 30 seconds—or as long as possible—without dropping down onto your knees or losing form.</p>
<h3>Knee Press</h3>
<p>A great workout for your legs, this exercise requires no equipment and can be done anywhere. It will help you firm up your legs, butt and thighs while strengthening your core.</p>
<p><strong>How to:</strong></p>
<p>Stand with feet hip-width apart, knees slightly bent. Hold a 10-pound dumbbell in each hand, arms at sides (or use two 5-pound dumbbells).<br><br>Bend knees and lower body toward floor until thighs are parallel to floor; stop if your knees hurt. Pause for one count, then press back up to start position as quickly as possible; repeat for one minute.</p>
<h3>Leg Lift</h3>
<p>The leg lift is a great exercise for your abs, but it's also an easy way to tone your butt and thighs.</p>
<p><strong>To do this exercise:</strong></p>
<p>Lie on your back with knees bent and feet flat on the floor.<br><br>Hold weights in each hand and extend arms above head, palms facing each other.<br><br>Slowly lift one leg, keeping the knee straight but not locked. Lift until the leg is at a 90-degree angle from the body. Lower back down and repeat with the other leg.</p>
<h3>Lunge Twist</h3>
<p>The lunge twist will help you burn calories while toning your lower body muscles. It is a great workout for those who don't like to spend a lot of time in the gym! You will need an exercise mat or towel to complete this exercise.</p>
<p><strong>﻿How to do it: </strong></p>
<p>Stand with feet hip-width apart. Lunge forward with your right leg until your thigh is parallel to the floor. Twist your upper body toward the front leg and place your hands on the floor at shoulder height. Keep your core tight as you return to starting position. That's one rep; do 10 to 15 on each side.</p>
<h3>Dumbbell Swings</h3>
<p><br>This exercise is great for your backside and core because it works both hip adductors and abductors. It also strengthens glutes and hamstrings while improving balance and coordination.</p>
<p><strong>To perform dumbbell swings:</strong></p>
<p>Stand holding dumbbells at your sides with palms facing forward; keep feet shoulder-width apart with knees slightly bent (A). Lift one leg up so it's parallel to the floor; swing dumbbells back between legs as far as possible (B). Allow arms to swing forward between each repetition (C). Return arms to start position between each rep. That's one rep; do 15 reps with each arm before switching sides.</p>
<h3>Pushup with Rotation</h3>
<p>This exercise is a variation of the standard pushup, but it will work your core and shoulders more than the standard pushup does.</p>
<p><strong>How to do it: </strong></p>
<p>Start in pushup position with your hands directly under your shoulders. Lower yourself down until your chest nearly touches the ground then rotate your body so that one arm is parallel to the ground while the other lifts up and over your head. Push yourself back up and repeat on the other side.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>If you're unable to make it to the gym, don't forget that there are plenty of exercises you can do right at home. Be creative, be diligent, and don't get discouraged. Exercise is one of the best things you can do for yourself, so keep up with it.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/mothers-day-gift-ideas</id>
    <published>2022-05-04T21:08:27+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-05-04T21:08:27+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/mothers-day-gift-ideas"/>
    <title>Mother&apos;s Day Gift Ideas</title>
    <author>
      <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[It's time to tell the mom in your life how much she means to you. But let's be honest, buying a Mother's Day gift can be hard. It might actually make you feel guilty. Especially if you're someone who has it pretty easy when it comes to taking care of your parents. So, this holiday season we're giving you a guilt-free way to tell your mother how much you love and appreciate her: with Flybird Fitness gift cards!<p><a class="read-more" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/mothers-day-gift-ideas">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>If you're searching for Mother's Day gift ideas, then you're in the right place. We've got the best gift ideas for the active family. We have Flybird adjustable weight bench, Flybird adjustable dumbbells, and more.<br><br>Flybird Fitness is a well thought out and designed weight bench, that can be adjusted in many different ways. It allows for many great compound movements, as well as being a solid option for dumbbells.</p>
<p>Flybird is the best fitness equipment brand on the market.<br><br>Flybird is a small company that has been supplying fitness equipment to gyms and home users for over 20 years. We design and manufacture our own products, so we have full control over quality and delivery times.<br><br>We take pride in providing excellent customer service and support to our customers, which is why we have such a strong reputation in this industry.<br><br>If you are looking for new fitness equipment for your gym or home gym then Flybird is the perfect choice for you!</p>
<h2>Flybird adjustable weight bench is a wonderful gift for your mom. </h2>
<p><br><br>Mother's Day is just around the corner, and if you're shopping for your mom, we've got a gift idea that will make her feel like a queen.<br><br>The <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/weight-benches" title="Flybird adjustable weight bench">Flybird adjustable weight bench</a> is a wonderful gift for your mom. She'll get to work out at home in style and comfort with this versatile machine!<br><br>This bench is perfect for all types of workouts: strength training, cardio and more. It features an adjustable back pad that can be raised or lowered to fit any body type or height. The bench also has padded arm rests and an adjustable foot pad that locks into place so you can perform exercises like chest presses without having to worry about slipping off.<br><br>The Flybird Weight Bench comes with three attachments: two weight bars for dumbbells and two ankle straps for leg lifts. The weight bars are easy to attach and detach from the bench so you can quickly change from one exercise to another without having to spend time moving equipment around each time.<br><br>The Flybird Weight Bench weighs only 20 pounds when fully assembled — so it's easy enough for anyone in your household to move around while they're exercising on it!</p>
<h2>Flybird adjustable dumbbells are easy to use and effective at strengthening and toning muscles. </h2>
<p><br>They are suitable for all fitness levels, from beginner to advanced, and can be adjusted in weight up to 25lb each side. The Flybird pair of adjustable dumbbells have a unique design that allows you to change the weight quickly and easily with a simple twist of the wrist.<br><br>The ergonomic handles are comfortable to hold and fit into any fitness routine, whether you're looking for cardio or strength training or both! The <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/dumbbells" title="Flybird adjustable dumbbells">Flybird adjustable dumbbells</a> also come with a handy carry case so they're portable too.<br><br>Features:<br><br>- Lightweight, easy-to-use;<br><br>- Ergonomic handles for added comfort;<br><br>- Quickly change weights without having to re-adjust;<br><br>- Includes carry case for easy storage and transport;</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Living a healthy lifestyle gets more important as we get older. It's never too late to start making changes — but even if your mom is already fit and active, there are plenty of ways to encourage her to continue on that path.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/how-much-should-i-bench-for-my-weight</id>
    <published>2022-04-30T18:30:01+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-04-30T18:30:01+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/how-much-should-i-bench-for-my-weight"/>
    <title>How Much Should I Bench For My Weight?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[How much should you bench for your weight?Whether you're just starting strength training, or a gym veteran looking for a better workout, the answer to this question can have profound effects on your workout. Bench pressing is one of the oldest and most respected exercises in bodybuilding, and also one of the most common.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/how-much-should-i-bench-for-my-weight">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>How much should I bench for my weight? It's the wrong question. The real question is, how much force are your pectoral muscles able to produce? If you're interested in increasing the amount of force your pectoral muscles generate this article will help you figure out what weight to use when bench pressing.</p>
<h2>Bench Press Calculator: Set Your 1 REP MAX</h2>
<p><br>If you're new to benching, it can be hard to figure out a good weight to start with—and if you've been benching for a while, it can be difficult to figure out how much you should be lifting. This calculator will help you set your 1-rep max (1RM) or predict how much weight you should be able to lift based on a given number of reps, or vice versa. If you're new to benching, it can be hard to figure out a good weight to start with—and if you've been benching for a while, it can be difficult to figure out how much you should be lifting. This calculator will help you set your 1-rep max (1RM) or predict how much weight you should be able to lift based on a given number of reps, or vice versa.</p>
<h2>How Much Should I Be Able To Bench Press?</h2>
<p>As I've said before, the weight you use for bench press should be based on your goals. If you're primarily interested in building muscle while also increasing strength, use the higher end of the rep range and make sure you're training to failure at least once a week. If you're primarily interested in strength, use the lower end of the rep range and limit how often you train to failure (I recommend doing this once every two weeks). You can also choose something in between if your main focus is to get a little bit stronger (but not as strong as possible) without building much muscle. The most important thing is to find what works best for you!</p>
<h2>The Ideal Bench Press Max Percentage by Weight Class</h2>
<p>The ideal bench press max percentage by weight class is a question that cannot be answered with much precision. Bench press max varies greatly from person to person and depends on many factors, including age, weight, height, genetics, body type (mesomorph vs. endomorph vs. ectomorph), and more. The only way to find out what your ideal bench press max should be is to get in the gym and start lifting weights!<br><br>General guidelines for a good starting point are:<br><br>- Lightweight lifters aiming for 1.5 times their own body weight<br><br>- Middleweight lifters aiming for double their own body weight<br><br>- Heavyweight lifters aiming for 2.5 times their own body weight</p>
<h2>Find Your 1 Rep Max (1RM)</h2>
<p>Find a spotter who can help you lift the weight in case you get stuck. Warm up thoroughly before starting, and have someone spot you during the test to prevent injury.<br><br>Start with the bar and add small increments of weight until you get to your estimated 1RM. For example, if you think your current 1RM is 100 pounds (45 kg), put on 10-20 pounds (4.5-9 kg) at a time until you reach that weight.<br><br>Use a log book to write down how much weight is on the barbell and how many reps you can complete with that amount of weight. Record how many reps you complete with each amount of weight until you reach your 1RM.<br><br>Do not continue increasing the weight after failing to complete a rep because this can lead to injury.</p>
<h2>How to Calculate Your One-Rep Maximum (1RM) for Any Lift</h2>
<p>When it comes to evaluating your max bench press, one of the most popular questions people have is, "How much should I bench for my weight?"<br><br>The simple answer is that you should be able to lift 90 percent of your own body weight. But this is a bit misleading. It doesn't tell you how much you should be able to bench in one repetition—it tells you how much you should be able to bench for multiple repetitions. This is known as your "one-rep max," or 1RM.<br><br>So if your goal is to calculate your one-rep max, then the following formula will give you a very accurate estimate:<br><br>weight lifted × (1 + number of reps)/30 = estimated 1RM<br><br>For example, let's say you bench 225 pounds for 10 repetitions. Your calculation would look like this: <br><br>225 × (1 + 10)/30 = 255 pounds<br><br>Using this formula, it's easy to see that if you lift more than 275 pounds for one rep, you'll fit into the "excellent" category. And if you can only do 135 pounds for eight reps, that would put you in the "poor" category.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>If you are looking for an effective home gym, the <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/weight-benches" title="Flybird weight bench">Flybird Weight Bench</a> will meet your exercise needs. It's easy to set up, versatile, and sturdy. You will be able to lift weights and perform other exercises that you can do at a gym.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/5-dumbbell-workout-tips-for-beginners</id>
    <published>2022-04-29T16:50:05+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-04-29T16:55:54+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/5-dumbbell-workout-tips-for-beginners"/>
    <title>5 Dumbbell Workout Tips For Beginners</title>
    <author>
      <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Ready to take your dumbbell workout to the next level? We all start somewhere, and that's why as I see it, we all can be considered beginners. Today we're going to cover 5 dumbbell workout tips for beginners that you can use today!<p><a class="read-more" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/5-dumbbell-workout-tips-for-beginners">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p> </p>
<p>It's easy to get started with dumbbells and change your body for the better. But it's also easy to do dumbbell workouts wrong and have them backfire on you. You're probably wondering what kind of dumbbell workouts for beginners would be ideal for you or if even dumbbells are right for you at all. I started with dumbbells because they were a cheaper alternative to gym memberships and allowed me to invest in my health from home; you could say I'm a pretty big fan of fitness equipment that allows me to workout from the comfort of my own home.</p>
<p>You may have tried working out with <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/dumbbells" title="Flybird adjustbale dumbbells">adjustable dumbbells</a> before, but if you are a beginner it can be tough to know exactly how to use them or what exercises you should do. It is still important for beginners to find a workout routine that works for them, but there are a few dumbbell workout tips for beginners I think will help make it easier for you.</p>
<h2>1. Get a proper warm-up in.</h2>
<p>It's tempting to skip warming up when you're eager to start your workout, but it's a bad idea. Warming up is actually really important for beginners because it helps your body get ready for the kind of activity you're about to put through. If you skip warming up, your muscles and joints might not be as flexible, which can lead to injury. Think about how hard it is to bend over and try to tie your shoes first thing in the morning without doing a few stretches first—that's what working out without warming up is like. You don't have to spend a lot of time getting warmed up, though—you just need to do something that gets your heart rate going so the blood can flow more easily through your veins and into your muscles, increasing their flexibility and preventing injury. This could mean walking on the treadmill or going out for a jog around the block.<br><br>If you're new to working out or haven't lifted weights before, it's easy to injure yourself without proper warm-up exercises. This is true for all types of weightlifting, but especially so if you're using dumbbells.<br><br>A warm-up period should consist of dynamic stretches and some low-intensity exercise. This helps prepare your body for the more intense training session you have planned. It does this by increasing blood flow to your muscles and raising your heart rate, meaning that when you do get started with your workout, you'll be ready to go.<br><br>As a beginner, the best way to do this is with a five-minute jog or brisk walk on a treadmill before starting any other exercises. A quick jog is effective because it bypasses static stretching, which can shorten the length of muscles involved in active movement and actually decrease muscle performance during a workout.</p>
<h2>2. Use the right weight.</h2>
<p>The best way to get the most from your dumbbell workout is to use the right weight. This isn't necessarily the heaviest weight you can lift or the lightest one either. You want to challenge yourself, but not so much that you compromise your form. For example, if you're doing a set of bicep curls and your arm muscles are shaking and straining with each rep, the weight is too heavy. If you're using perfect form and you don't feel like your muscles are working hard at all, it's time to increase the weight. Your last two reps should be difficult but still manageable with good form.<br><br><br>As a general rule of thumb, choose a weight at which you can complete 8 to 12 reps for three sets with proper form. One set of 8 to 12 reps is considered one exercise session for strength-building purposes. You can increase the weight slowly over time as your muscles adapt and get stronger.</p>
<h2>3.  Practice your dumbbell movements.</h2>
<p>It may sound silly, but if you want to lift a heavy weight without hurting yourself, you should first practice your form with lighter weights until you feel comfortable and confident doing the movement. For example, if you've never done a biceps curl before, start with a lighter weight and practice the motion until it feels fluid and easy—this way when you pick up a heavier weight, it'll be easier and safer for your arms!<br><br>You know that the best way to learn a sport is by playing it, and the same is true for dumbbells. The more you practice them, the more familiar you'll be with their movements, and that will help you use them safely and effectively. If you're just starting out, practice with your lightest weight before trying heavier ones. Also, don't be afraid to ask for help! A qualified personal trainer can evaluate your form and show you how to make adjustments.</p>
<h2>4. Focus on quality not quantity.</h2>
<p>It's tempting to think that the more reps you do, the better your results will be—and while it's true that you have to challenge yourself if you're going to get stronger, it doesn't mean that you have to push your limits every time. It's actually better to stay within your comfort zone, at least at first.<br><br>The best thing you can do when you're new to strength training is to focus on form. This will help you get comfortable with the exercises without having any missteps along the way. If your form is correct and you feel like you're maintaining proper control of each exercise, then there's no need to worry about how many reps you're doing. If anything, it's good for beginners to keep their rep ranges and sets low in order to learn the right way of doing things before they take on more difficult challenges.<br><br>As a beginner, it's also important that you master all the basics—there are plenty of them! But once you've got those down and feel comfortable doing them with excellent form, then gradually build up your sets and reps as needed. There are plenty of other variables in a workout plan that can be modified as well so that workouts become increasingly more challenging over time.</p>
<h2>5. Take adequate rest.</h2>
<p>If you are new to weight training and the gym, the last thing you want to do is overdo yourself. There's no gold medal for working out even if your body is screaming at you to stop. The best way to avoid getting injured is by making sure you take enough rest between sets and workouts.<br><br>It is also important to get enough sleep at night, as that's when your body will do most of its rebuilding work. Aim for at least seven hours, if not more.<br><br>If you're looking to build muscle, it's important to remember that there is a difference between being sore from working out and being injured from overworking yourself. If your muscles are so sore that you can't finish a workout or feel pain in your joints, then it's time to take a break for a couple of days.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Learning to use a set of weights is easy, and the Dumbbell Workout Tips For Beginners will help take some of the frustration out of this learning process for you. Each tip can be used as is, or combined with others to create your own routine. Either way, commit these to memory, and you'll be working up a sweat in no time.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/10-tips-for-effective-home-exercises-when-youre-stuck-in-a-rut</id>
    <published>2022-04-28T21:48:08+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-04-28T21:48:09+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/10-tips-for-effective-home-exercises-when-youre-stuck-in-a-rut"/>
    <title>5 Tips for Effective Home Exercises When You&apos;re Stuck in a Rut</title>
    <author>
      <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[It can be so difficult if you are feeling like you are in a fitness rut in the comfort of your own home. You want to move on, but don't know how to break free. The following five tips offer suggestions that are easy and can make all of the difference. Keep reading to improve your fitness routine now!<p><a class="read-more" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/10-tips-for-effective-home-exercises-when-youre-stuck-in-a-rut">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>It's easy to feel stuck in a rut when living in your home for any length of time. When we're in a perpetual state of "home" it's easy to lose motivation for doing things that are both enjoyable and healthy. While there are many excellent fitness centers available to the general public, many cannot be joined if a person has physical limitations or mobility problems. But fear not! There are exercises you can do at home aside from household chores that can keep you active and improve your health.</p>
<p>The benefits of proper exercise are numerous. It can help ward off illness, reduce the risk of many chronic diseases and help you lose weight by burning calories. While many people understand the importance of exercise, they may wonder whether there is such a thing as exercising too much. Or they may wonder how much exercise they should do.<br><br>The Centers for Disease Control and Prevention recommend that all adults over age 18 get at least 150 minutes of moderate-intensity aerobic activity each week or 75 minutes of vigorous-intensity aerobic activity. In addition, the CDC recommends that adults do muscle-strengthening activities at least twice per week.<br><br>Exercise is only one part of a healthy lifestyle. You should also eat a balanced diet, manage your stress and sleep 7 to 8 hours every night to keep your body healthy and promote good health.<br><br>As the world evolves and technology becomes more of a staple in our everyday lives, people spend more time sitting down. Whether you're at work or play, you're likely to be stuck in a chair or on a couch for hours on end each day. The problem is that this type of sedentary lifestyle can drastically increase your risk of heart disease and other related ailments. Even if you don't smoke or have diabetes, you can still be at risk of serious health issues due to lack of activity. Fortunately, getting up and moving around can significantly reduce your chances of developing cardiovascular problems and other life-threatening conditions.<br><br>Exercise not only has many physical benefits, but it can also help improve your mood and mental state. Studies have shown that people who exercise on a regular basis experienced less depression, anxiety, and stress than those who didn't exercise regularly. Exercise can also improve sleep quality and help reduce insomnia. If you suffer from insomnia or other sleep disorders, try exercising for at least 30 minutes every day before going to bed to see if it helps improve your sleep patterns.</p>
<p>Whether you're a beginner or an experienced athlete, there are times when you may find your workouts getting boring and monotonous. For some people, this can lead to a workout rut, where they're not seeing results as quickly as they'd like.<br><br>To break out of that rut and start seeing progress again, here are five tips for effective home exercises:</p>
<h2>1. Add variety to your routine.</h2>
<p>If you're doing the same thing over and over again, it's going to get boring fast. Make sure to mix things up and try different workouts so that you don't get stuck in a rut.<br><br>If you've been doing the same routine over and over again, try mixing things up with some new moves. The internet is brimming with lots of great ideas for quick and easy home workouts that can mix things up while still getting your heart rate pumping.</p>
<h2>2. Find a balance between cardio and strength training. </h2>
<p>Cardio can help increase your heart rate while burning calories, while strength training increases muscle mass which helps burn more calories even when at rest! Try alternating between these two types of workouts during each session so that you don't get bored too easily!<br><br>Cardio workouts like running, cycling and swimming will help you burn calories, but if you want to get stronger, you need to add weights into your routine as well. And don’t worry about bulking up — building muscle doesn’t increase your size much at all because muscle is much denser than fat. What this means is that you can become stronger without looking too different from normal!</p>
<h2>3. Use the right equipment for the right purpose.</h2>
<p>The right equipment can make a huge difference when it comes to getting the most out of your workouts. However, if you're not using the right equipment for the right purpose, you could find yourself with less-than-ideal results — or even injuries. <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/dumbbells" title="Flybird adjustable dumbbells">Flybird adjustable dumbbells</a> are great tools for working out at home because they allow you to adjust the weight as needed — so you don't have to buy multiple sets of dumbbells for different exercises. If your gym has a lot of different machines and equipment, it might be tempting to do everything on those machines. But if you're trying to get a well-rounded exercise program in, it's important to mix up your routine so that different muscle groups get worked out.<br><br>You can get a perfectly good workout at home, but you have to make sure you have the right equipment for the job. The <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/weight-benches" title="Flybird adjustable weight bench">Flybird adjustable weight bench</a> is an excellent tool because it allows you to adjust the height and angle of the bench, making it ideal for a variety of exercises. You can even use it as a chair when not working out! If you're using the Flybird adjustable dumbbells, they will automatically adjust their weight based on which exercise you are doing so that your body gets maximum benefit without any risk of injury.</p>
<h2>4. Focus on what works for you.</h2>
<p>Focus on what works for you and your body type. Everyone has different strengths, so it makes sense that some exercises are more effective than others for different people. If something isn't working for you, don't do it anymore! Find exercises that help improve your weaknesses instead of making them worse and avoid injury by doing exercises that focus on your strengths instead of trying to fix weaknesses with bad form or improper techniques.</p>
<h2>5. Be consistent and track your progress</h2>
<p>One of the best ways to stay motivated is to keep exercising. It's easy to skip a day when you feel tired or unmotivated, but if you do that often enough, your progress will grind to a halt. Instead of skipping one or two days a week, aim for five or six days per week. That way, even if you miss one day, you'll still be able to make up for it later in the week.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>You might be surprised how much your muscles and joints adapt to a regular workout routine. Using home exercises to keep them strong while avoiding boredom is your best bet in preventing injury, pain and weakness as you age. Remember that variety is the spice of life and exercise should be no different. Vary the time of day you exercise, mix up the type of exercises completed in each workout, avoid using the same muscle groups in consecutive workouts, keep challenging yourself to use more resistance or increase the reps completed. And remember that time spent exercising could be quality time spent with friends and family while you develop strong lifelong bonds. Try keeping a journal or calendar of your workouts, track your progress and set goals to push yourself further as often as you can. Your body and mind will thank you for taking care of it this way! You don't have to spend hours at the gym to achieve success, nor do you need multiple costly pieces of equipment to make measurable changes for the better in strength and endurance. Use these tips for effective home exercises when you're stuck in a rut as motivation even when going out would mean spending money on gas and/or babysitting, not just spending valuable time on your fitness routine!</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/the-complete-beginners-guide-to-meal-planning</id>
    <published>2022-04-26T22:03:42+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-04-26T22:03:43+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/the-complete-beginners-guide-to-meal-planning"/>
    <title>The Complete Beginners Guide to Meal Planning</title>
    <author>
      <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Meal Planning an important part of living a healthy life. What you eat greatly influences the body you live in. So really, the health of your entire family is dependent on your meal planning skills. Surely this is one area where you don't want to reinvent the wheel. And that's why we built The Complete Beginners Guide to Meal Planning.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/the-complete-beginners-guide-to-meal-planning">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Meal planning - it's the key to a healthy, affordable and successful weight loss journey. It's important to be strategic about your food choices, whether you are looking to lose weight or gain muscle. To keep on track with your fitness goals, you will want to <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/how-meal-planning-can-save-money" title="How Meal Planning Can Save Money">meal plan</a> for success. Here is some practical advice that will help you take charge of your diet and get the most out of your grocery shopping trips.<br><br>Meal planning is often synonymous with restricting your food choices and stifling creativity. We've all heard the jokes: "I'm not an expert in nutrition — I don't know much about nutrition," or, "Is it fun to be a dietitian? You must eat crayons." That's where I'm going to stop you right there. You're right — meal planning doesn't always have to be cut and dry. It doesn't have to mean eating tofu and steamed broccoli every single day of the week. It doesn't always have to be boring.<br><br>Do you find the idea of meal planning a little overwhelming? This not only can be true for those who are just starting out but even seasoned budget meal planners as well. Meal planning can seem like hours of work and something that is unnecessary. However, this myth couldn't be further from the truth. Meal planning is easy and doesn't have to be time consuming at all.</p>
<h2>Meal planning is a valuable way to save time and money</h2>
<p>Meal planning is a valuable way to save time and money—and it's also the best way to make sure you're eating healthy. It's a simple skill that will help you throughout your life, but it might not be something your parents taught you. I didn't start meal planning until I was in college, but once I did, my health improved, my grocery bills went down, and I started to feel more confident in the kitchen. Here's everything you need to know to get started.</p>
<h2>Why should you make a meal plan?</h2>
<p>You may think this sounds like too much work, but hear me out: Meal planning saves money. When you're grocery shopping without a plan, it's easy to pick up things on impulse that are expensive or unhealthy—or both. When you sit down for just 15 minutes and plan out your week of meals ahead of time, it's easier to say no to those things. You'll spend less at the store because you've made a list of exactly what you need, and you'll only buy what's on that list (I know this because I've tried both ways).<br><br>Meal planning can be as simple or complex as you want it to be. Some people have elaborate charts and trackers, others just make a list of meals they want to eat that week. No matter which direction you go in, here are some tips on how to make your meal planning easier!</p>
<h2>How to plan your meals in 7 simple steps</h2>
<p>Planning meals is easy! Follow our step-by-step guide to creating a meal plan that works for you—and your family.</p>
<h3>1. Determine how many meals you'll need for the week (or month), and what kind of meals you want to make.</h3>
<p>When you first start meal planning, it can feel a little overwhelming. I remember when my friend was starting out and she asked me for some help. The first thing I told her to do was figure out how many meals she needed to plan for. She thought she had to plan for every single meal for an entire week. And I told her, if that's what she wanted to do—then sure! But that's not the only way to do it. If you want to plan all of your meals, then by all means plan 'em all! But if you want to just focus on planning dinners, then that's totally okay too! Some people like to get even more specific with their meal planning, and only plan dinners for Monday - Friday, but then leave weekends free. Others like to keep it simple and just plan dinners for the week. There are no rules about what's right or wrong when it comes to meal planning, except the ones you set for yourself. So figure out what kind of meal planner you want to be and go from there.</p>
<h3>2. Consider your schedule for the week.</h3>
<p>When will you have time to cook? Are there days when you'll be out of the house for lunch or dinner?</p>
<p>Before you start planning your meals, you need to consider your schedule. When do you have time to cook? Are there days when you'll be out of the house for lunch or dinner? This is where it's important to think of the practical issues. If you're busy on Mondays and Tuesdays, then it's likely that meals on those nights will need to be quicker and easier. Thursday is a great night for a more involved dinner if you've got time after work; if not, takeout might be the best bet. Whatever your schedule looks like, it's worth taking a moment to map out when you'll have time for cooking before you start thinking about what meals you're going to make for the week.</p>
<h3>3. Think about any special circumstances that need to be accommodated.</h3>
<p>For example, if someone in your family has a food allergy, or if you'll be out at a party one night where there will be food.</p>
<p>When you're planning meals for your family, it's important to consider any special circumstances that might affect what you're making. For example, if someone in your household has a food allergy, you'll want to make sure that meals can be prepared for them without extra hassle. If you will be out of the house one night because of a party or some other event where there will be food, plan accordingly and make something that can be left out at room temperature, such as a casserole or soup.</p>
<h3>4. Plan ahead for leftovers so that they don't go to waste.</h3>
<p>For example, if you know you'll want leftover lasagna for lunch three days in a row, plan on making enough so that there's extra from the beginning instead of having plain pasta one day because there isn't enough sauce left over from the previous day's lunch!</p>
<h3>5. Consider which ingredients can be used for more than one meal, so that you can buy them.</h3>
<p>Meal planning can be a chore. When you have to get everything down on paper and track what's available, it can be frustrating. But if you start slowly and make a plan to ease your way into it, you'll find that it's not as daunting as you think.<br><br>The first thing we recommend is to look at the meals you already make and take note of what they have in common. For instance, if you're making a steak dinner on Monday, consider which ingredients can be used for more than one meal, so that you can buy them with the intent of using them for multiple dinners throughout the week. You might have some leftover steak that could go into a salad. Or maybe you're making spaghetti on Tuesday—you can use the same tomato sauce for both dinners. These are just two examples; try to think about how many times you could repurpose an ingredient in a week before buying it so that when you do go shopping, everything is more efficient and cost-effective!<br><br>Try this process on your own menus and see what you come up with—it'll help create an easier meal planning experience!</p>
<h3>6. Make it a habit and be flexible.</h3>
<p>The best way to get started with meal planning is to make it a habit. It may not happen every week, and that's okay. If you can get into the routine of doing it consistently (even just once a month), the benefits will pay off.<br><br>To make it a habit, try to incorporate it into something you already do regularly, such as grocery shopping or paying bills. For example, if you shop on Saturday morning, set aside 30 minutes on Friday night to plan your meals, so you're ready to go first thing in the morning. If you pay bills every Wednesday evening, set aside 15 minutes to plan that evening's dinner while your computer is booting up and your bills are loading.<br><br>If it helps, write down the date and time that works best for you each week (or month), and stick to it like any other appointment. You can even set an alarm on your phone or computer for those times as a reminder.</p>
<h3>7. Don't forget about snacks!</h3>
<p>Don't forget about snacks! You probably think that meal planning is just for dinner, but you'd be wrong! Meal planning can be used to get your whole day organized. Some people like to plan out breakfast and lunch as well, while others like to plan out snacks throughout the day. If you're someone who needs a snack every few hours, you should definitely consider meal planning your snacks as well. This can help curb your hunger throughout the day which means you'll eat less overall and it will help to prevent you from buying something at the vending machine at work. It's a win-win!</p>
<h2>The ultimate grocery shopping list for meal planning success</h2>
<p>-Start with what you already have and rotate that into your meal plan.<br><br>-If you don't have a full supply of staples, then add those to your shopping list too.<br><br>-Once you have a good stock of staples, then start filling in the gaps by adding items that are on sale or items your family likes.<br><br><strong>Staples Checklist:</strong><br><br>Meat, poultry and seafood: meat, chicken, fish<br><br>Pasta: spaghetti, penne, lasagna noodles<br><br>Rice: wild rice, brown rice, white rice<br><br>Grains: barley, farro, bulgur wheat<br><br>Beans and lentils: chickpeas, black beans, kidney beans<br><br>Flour: whole wheat flour (or wheat free flour) all-purpose flour (white or unbleached)<br><br>Eggs and dairy products: eggs and milk or egg substitute and non-dairy milks<br><br>Spices: salt (sea salt), pepper (black peppercorns), cinnamon sticks</p>
<h2>Anyone can start meal planning with the right tools and mindset.</h2>
<p>Meal planning is more than just staying organized; it's also an easy way to save money, eat healthily and improve the quality of life. It takes a little bit of work up front, but this endeavor quickly builds into something that is empowering and rewarding. The tools and tips listed above will help you get started, but keep in mind that you can be as creative as you want with meal planning. You'll learn better ways to plan your meals through trial-and-error, and find the structure that works for you over time.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/adjustable-dumbbells-for-beginners</id>
    <published>2022-04-21T10:06:10+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-04-21T10:06:10+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/adjustable-dumbbells-for-beginners"/>
    <title>Adjustable Dumbbells For Beginners</title>
    <author>
      <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[If you're a beginner when it comes to weight training, the Flybird adjustable dumbbells may be just what you need to get started!<p><a class="read-more" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/adjustable-dumbbells-for-beginners">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>People who work out at home are often overwhelmed by the amount of equipment they need to buy. Even if you have a decent amount of free weights and an awesome bench, many times you don't even have space at home to store these items. So what's the solution? Adjustable dumbbells for beginners are the answer you've been looking for.<br><br>Adjustable Dumbbells are the best choice if you want to work out at home. This can be very cost-effective and save you a great deal of money every month when compared to getting a gym membership.</p>
<h2>What are Adjustable Dumbbells</h2>
<p>What are adjustable dumbbells? Adjustable dumbbell sets are a brand new way to work out at home and they make having your dumbbells with you wherever you go possible. They're great for beginners who don't know what pair of weight to buy because they have lots of options and easily stack on any number of plates.</p>
<p>Adjustable dumbbells are dumbbells that allow you to change the amount of weight that you lift. Instead of having a set weight, these dumbbells allow you to add or remove weight as needed. You can add or remove individual plates or change out a whole weight stack. This allows you to have one set of dumbbells that give you a full range of weights from which to choose.<br><br>You can find adjustable dumbbells with a large range of weights, from 5 pounds all the way up to 140 pounds. There are many different styles and sizes for these dumbbells, but most will allow you to change the weight quickly and easily without having to remove the handle from the stack and put it back on after adding or removing weight plates.</p>
<h2>Flybird Adjustable Dumbbells</h2>
<p><br>Flybird is a well-known brand that manufactures some of the best fitness equipment. If you’re looking for a pair of dumbbells that are strong and reliable, you should consider the <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/dumbbells" title="Flybird adjustable dumbbells">Flybird Adjustable Dumbbells</a>.<br><br>You can easily adjust the weight of these dumbbells between 5 and 50 pounds. The best part is that they come with a weight selector pin. So, they’re easy to adjust and change.<br><br>The Flybird Adjustable Dumbbells are made out of cast iron making them durable and sturdy. A common issue people have with fitness products is that they aren’t long-lasting.<br><br>However, these dumbbells are not prone to wear and tear so you can rest assured that your money won’t go to waste! They also come with a protective layer on them which ensures that the weights don’t damage your floor or walls.</p>
<h2>How to Use Flybird Adjustable Dumbbells</h2>
<p>Flybird Adjustable Dumbbells is a big step forward in adjustable dumbbell technology. It's designed to be very easy to switch weights. Just rotate the handle and you change weights in 1 second. It's a very easy to use system and it works great, allowing you to seamlessly transition from one workout to the next without having to fumble with plates and collars between sets.</p>
<h2>Benefits of Flybird Adjustable Dumbbells</h2>
<p><br>Flybird Adjustable Dumbbells are ideal for weight training at home, they are built to last with a durable cast iron core and chrome handles that have knurled grips to provide better traction.<br><br>With a simple adjustment, you can increase or decrease the weight of each dumbbell from 5lbs up to 50lbs. To adjust the Flybird Adjustable Dumbbells, simply pull the pin on each end of the dumbbell, slide it out from the base, place your chosen weight plates onto each side and then slide the pin back into place. Each dumbbell has an easy-to-read weight gauge that shows how much weight is loaded on each side.<br><br>Flybird Adjustable Dumbbells also come with particularly durable storage trays that can be stacked for convenient storage.</p>
<h2>Workout with Flybird Adjustable Dumbbells</h2>
<p>You can make your workout plan as a <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/4-simple-steps-to-create-a-beginners-workout-plan" target="_blank" title="4 Simple Steps to Create a Beginner's Workout Plan" rel="noopener noreferrer">beginner</a>, we suggest you start with a daily <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/workouts/20-minute-home-workout-flybird-55lb-adjustable-dumbbells-only" target="_blank" title="20-Minute Home Workout with Flybird 55 lb Adjustable Dumbbells" rel="noopener noreferrer">20-minute dummbell workout</a>. As you get used to the exercise, increase it to 45 minutes a day. Keep the weight light initially and gradually increase the load. We do not recommend working with heavier weights if you haven't worked out before.<br><br>Check out a few of our favorite dumbbell workouts:<br><br></p>
<ul>
<li>Upper body workout: Do two sets of 12 repetitions for each exercise.</li>
<li>Bicep curls</li>
<li>Wrist curls</li>
<li>Tricep kickbacks</li>
<li>Shoulder shrugs</li>
<li>Lunges</li>
<li>Step ups</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<p>Using a set of weight-adjustable dumbbells is a different experience from using fixed weights. The only difference is the amount of weight you can lift to a certain number of lbs. As with any equipment, this is a matter of personal preference and experimentation, but one thing's for sure: you can get a huge variety of workouts out of these wrist weights.</p>
<p>As a beginner, you could purchase <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/products/flybird-adjustable-dumbbell-25-lbs-2-pieces" title="Flybird 25lb adjustable dumbbells">Flybird 25lb adjustable dumbbells</a>.</p>
<p>And when you are an experienced weight lifter, you could update them to <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/products/flybird-55lbs-adjustable-dumbbells-pair" title="Flybird 55lb adjustable dumbbells">Flybird 55lb adjustable dumbbells</a>.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/a-beginners-guide-to-flybird-weight-bench</id>
    <published>2022-04-18T21:02:47+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-04-18T21:02:47+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/a-beginners-guide-to-flybird-weight-bench"/>
    <title>A Beginner&apos;s Guide to Flybird Weight Bench</title>
    <author>
      <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[A beginner's guide to a majority of the flybird weight bench. The product is designed for those that have never used a flybird weight bench in the past and are looking for a flybird weight bench overview.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/a-beginners-guide-to-flybird-weight-bench">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>One of the many features of the Flybird Weight Bench is that it helps anyone who exercises. Weight benches are gaining in popularity, and Flyrbird is a popular brand that is all-inclusive. These benches are ideal for home gyms and commercial gyms. Many attributes make Flybird bench worth the price. As you get fit at home or in a private gym, the Flybird bench is designed to improve your overall experience.</p>
<h2>What to Consider Before Buying a Flybird <strong>Weight</strong> Bench</h2>
<p>Quality is something you might be concerned about when buying a Flybird Weight Bench. Well, Flybird has been leading the fitness equipment industry for nearly 20 years. In comparison with other manufacturers, they have a long production timeline. It's not uncommon for them to produce a weight bench for two to three years before shipping it out. Before buying a Flybird weight bench, consider the following.</p>
<h3>Adjustable Design</h3>
<p>The Flybird bench can be used in a variety of positions. You can use it for incline, decline, and flat chest pressing. As an alternative, the bench can be adjusted to support the legs if you are performing an exercise without a backrest. With the leg attachment, you can perform leg curls and leg extensions.</p>
<h2>Material</h2>
<p>The Flybird weight bench is a smart buy if you're looking for an adjustable bench that can grow with your needs. The Flybird weight bench has a durable steel frame with padded foam to protect your back while you work out. The weight bench's leg extension/leg curl attachment is adjustable in three positions. The seat has four adjustment options so that the Flybird weight bench can accommodate any user's height and body size.</p>
<h3>The Backrest of the Weight Bench</h3>
<p>The backrest of the weight bench is an integral part of the whole Flybird weight bench. The reason for this is simple: the backrest on a weight bench will support your body during your exercises. You need to make sure that you're comfortable and have proper support to do all of your activities properly. The backrest should be made out of a material that is strong enough to support the weight of your body. A good backrest should also withstand any weight you may put on it.</p>
<h3>Size</h3>
<p>Consider how much space you have in your home for a workout area before you consider a weight bench. You need to be careful when buying equipment if you have a small amount of space to work with. Don't buy anything that will eat up all your space.</p>
<h3>Price</h3>
<p>It can be challenging to find a quality weight bench at a reasonable price. However, the Flybird weight bench is a high-quality product that will serve you for years to come. This is especially true if you consider the cost of other weight benches on the market that do not have the capabilities of the Flybird weight benches.</p>
<h2>How to Use a Flybird Weight Bench for Beginners</h2>
<p>A practical Flybird Weight Bench for Beginners allows for multiple exercises to be done simultaneously, which saves you space and time. This goes without saying that during your exercise session, you will be able to get rid of all your unwanted extra fat and improve your body's overall build. Here are things on how you can use a Flybird weight bench.</p>
<h3>Dumbbell Chest Press</h3>
<p>The dumbbell chest press is a classic exercise for beginners and experts alike, and it's an ideal workout to add to your schedule. Using a pair of dumbbells and the Flybird weight bench, lie flat on your back with your feet planted firmly on the ground. Hold the dumbbells over your chest with your elbows bent at a 90-degree angle, palms facing forward.</p>
<h3>Dumbbell Flyes</h3>
<p>The dumbbell flyes exercise targets your chest, shoulders, and upper back muscles. This exercise will also increase muscle strength and endurance throughout the entire body. Dumbbell Flyes are a great way to get started with the Flybird Weight Bench. The first step is to get a pair of dumbbells. Be sure that the weight of each dumbbell is equal to the other so you can perform this exercise correctly. You can find these at any local gym or sporting goods store.</p>
<h3>Dumbbell Shoulder Press</h3>
<p>The dumbbell shoulder press is an effective exercise for strengthening your shoulders, deltoids, and traps. Dumbbells provide a dynamic strength training routine that's versatile, easy to modify, and safe. If you're just learning how to use a Flybird weight bench, the dumbbell shoulder press is an excellent exercise to practice.</p>
<h3>Arm Blaster Biceps Curl</h3>
<p>Arm blaster biceps curls are a great way to isolate your biceps and make them swell. To perform this exercise, you need to use an arm blaster, which you can find in any gym or buy on Amazon. Start by grabbing the barbell with your hands at shoulder-width apart and holding it at waist height. Lift the bar while keeping your elbows pinned to your sides. Squeeze your biceps as you do so. Then lower the bar back down until your arms are straight again.</p>
<h3>Incline Push-ups</h3>
<p>Place your hands shoulder-width apart on the Flybird bench with the barbell at the back of the bench. You can use the adjustable seat to change how far you are from the ground, but most people will want to start their incline push-ups with a low incline. Slowly lower yourself down to the Flybird bench and push back up, raising your arms again. Keep your core tight, and be sure to keep your whole body in a straight line.</p>
<h2>Working Out the Shoulders with a Flybird Weight Bench as a Beginner</h2>
<p><br>You don't have to be an expert to start working out your shoulders. Flybird Weight benches are ideal for beginners and gym veterans alike, so it's easy to get started on a new exercise regimen. But if you're getting going with a weight bench, it's natural to wonder how to use one safely and effectively. Safety is key. When using a weight bench for the first time, make sure that the flat side is facing up that way; when you lie down, you'll be balanced against the surface. You'll want to adjust the height of the bench so that the barbell or dumbbells will be in line with your collarbone or shoulders. You can start by setting it at mid-chest height. To perform a shoulder press on a weight bench, lie down on your back with your head at the top and your feet flat on the floor. Then hold a dumbbell in each hand above your shoulders at arm's length.</p>
<h2>How to set up your Flybird Weight Bench?</h2>
<p>First, you will need to remove all the parts from the box.<br><br>Next, lay down your bench and install the base legs. You can do this by screwing in the pins into their holes.<br><br>Once you have these pins in place, you can now attach the seat and backrest to the bench. You can do this by lifting up your backrest and seat and then sliding them into their appropriate places on the frame.<br><br>Once you have these parts attached, your Flybird weight bench is ready to use!</p>
<p>If you want to learn more about the details about how to set up different Flybird weight benches, you can read our article <em><a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/how-to-assemble-the-flybird-adjustable-bench" title="How To Assemble the Flybird Adjustable Weight Bench">How To Assemble the Flybird Adjustable Weight Bench</a>.</em></p>
<h2>Importance of a Flybird Weight Bench</h2>
<p><br>If you are a gym-goer, you probably know the importance of a weight bench for your workout routines. However, what can you say about the quality of this equipment? Before choosing the weight bench for getting a particular workout session, it is vital to focus on essential factors. Here is some importance of <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/weight-benches" title="Flybird weight bench">Flybird weight bench</a>.</p>
<h3>
<br>Improving your strength in Bench Drive</h3>
<p>Most people do not know that you can improve the strength of your chest and arms by doing the bench drive. The flybridge weight bench is a great product to help you with this. It improves your strength in the bench press and will allow you to be stronger in this exercise.</p>
<h3>
<br>Posture Improvement and Stabilization</h3>
<p>This is one of the best benefits of a Flybird weight bench that many individuals might overlook. When you're training on a Flybird weight bench, you'll have to retract your shoulders back, which will allow you to keep your chest out and improve your posture, as well as stabilize your core and lower back. By simply using a Flybird weight bench for about 5-10 minutes per day, you can drastically improve your posture and stabilization, making you look like a super-strong individual who can lift crazy amounts of weight.</p>
<h3>
<br>Better Control of the Weight</h3>
<p>As well as being able to help users improve their posture, this type of weight bench can also help them with overall body control. Since most people do not have access to weights that are too heavy or too light, this exercise can help them increase their muscle mass without worrying about overdoing it.</p>
<h3>Makes You Look Good</h3>
<p>A slouchy posture makes you look less confident, while a tall and robust posture makes you appear confident and more assertive. People who have great posture always appear taller than they are. Flybird Weight Bench helps you train your muscles to develop a good posture.</p>
<h2>Which Muscles Does the Flybird Bench Exercise</h2>
<p>Finding the correct muscles worked by an exercise is why many people turn to bodybuilding forums and blogs. I don't blame them. Without a clear understanding of how a practice works, it can be challenging to know whether or not it's right for you. Here are some of the muscles.</p>
<h3>
<br>Pectoral Muscle</h3>
<p>The flybridge bench exercise targets your pectoral muscles or chest muscles. These are the muscles that make up your chest wall, and they're composed of two different sets of forces: the pectoralis minor and the pectoralis major. The flybridge bench exercise is a great way to work out various muscle groups in your upper body. It's easy to do, and it helps build strength-both things that make it an ideal exercise for new fitness enthusiasts and people who have to exercise at home because they don't have access to a gym.</p>
<h3>
<br> Lateral Pectoral Muscle</h3>
<p><br>The flybridge bench exercise targets the lateral pectoral muscle, which is one of the three heads of the chest muscle. The primary function of this muscle is to move the arm from the side to an overhead position with the elbow bent two bellies from the lateral pectoral muscle. The sternal head originates on the medial half of the clavicle, and its insertion point is on the anterior surface of the humerus. The clavicular charge of this muscle also stems from the clavicle but its superior surface. Its insertion point is also on the anterior surface of the humerus, in line with its same-name origin.</p>
<h3>
<br>Anterior Deltoid Muscle</h3>
<p><br>The Flybird Bench is a strength training machine that mimics the traditional bench press exercise but with various grips and angles, making it possible to target specific muscle groups for maximum growth. The anterior deltoid muscle is located in your shoulder and is responsible for helping to lift your arm away from your body. To work your anterior deltoid muscle with the Flybird Bench, begin by adjusting the seat so that you are sitting up straight. You can use either of the handles on the barbell to perform this exercise, but if this is your first time, we recommend using the narrower grip handle to get used to controlling the weight of the barbell.</p>
<h3>
<br>Triceps Brachial Muscle</h3>
<p><br>The flybridge bench is a popular home exercise used to tone and strengthen the triceps brachial muscles. The triceps are the muscles on the back of your upper arm, and they are involved in bending or straightening the elbow. The brachial triceps muscle is divided into the long head, lateral head, and medial head. The long head starts at the scapula and inserts at the back of your humerus. It helps extend your arm behind you, as when you are doing a flybird bench. The lateral head starts at the back of your humerus and inserts on the upper portion of your ulna bone, and helps with rotating your arm outward. The medial head begins at the back of your humerus and inserts on your ulna bone, close to where it meets the radius bone and helps to rotate your arm inward.</p>
<h2>How to Maintain the Flybird Weight Bench?</h2>
<p>The Flybird Weight bench is one of the most affordable weight lifting equipment you can find in the market. Like other benches, it has a limited life if not maintained carefully. The bench can become unusable or develop issues if proper care is not given. Here are some ways to keep the weight bench.</p>
<h3>
<br>Keep the Bench Clean</h3>
<p><br>The easiest way to keep your bench clean is to wipe it down before and after using warm water or a non-toxic cleaner. For example, you could use a simple dish soap and water solution in a spray bottle or a store-bought cleaning product like Simple Green. If you want to do a more thorough cleaning, you can wash the upholstery with a damp sponge or cloth and mild detergent such as laundry detergent. Once you've cleaned the upholstery, let it dry completely before using it again.</p>
<h3>
<br>Cover the Weights When Not in Use</h3>
<p><br>Cover the Weights When Not in Use. Keeping your weight bench clean and free from dust is essential for keeping your equipment looking new. The best way to do this is to cover your weights when you're not using them and keep them in a dry, dust-free environment.</p>
<h3>
<br>Don't Drop the Weights.</h3>
<p><br>One of the most important ways to maintain your Flybird Weight Bench is not to drop the weights. Falling weights can cause lasting damage to your equipment, so always make sure that you re-rack the consequences on the stand after each exercise. If you're doing a full-body workout, it's also essential to clean up each area after completing an activity. Doing so can help you avoid injury and keep all of your equipment in top shape for years.</p>
<h3>
<br>Keep It Away from Moisture</h3>
<p><br>Since the Flybird Weight Bench is made from sturdy steel, keeping it from moisture is essential. The bench can be used indoors or outdoors, but if you use it outdoors, make sure you bring it inside when not in use because moisture can cause rust and other damage to the weight bench.</p>
<h3>
<br>Don't Leave It Outside</h3>
<p><br>The Flybird weight bench is designed for indoor use. While it isn't cumbersome and is quite portable, it doesn't have the same durability as a model made for outdoor use. If you are using the weight bench in your backyard or patio, there is a risk of damage to the interior components if they are exposed to water.</p>
<h2>Types of Flybird Weight Bench</h2>
<p>When looking for the flybird weight bench, you should consider yourself a beginner or an intermediate lifter. It differs from others because it is more suitable for beginners and intermediates in weightlifting. With this kind of weight bench, you will get the maximum in your workouts. Here are some types of Flybird weight bench.</p>
<h3>Adjustable Weight Bench</h3>
<p><a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/weight-benches" title="Flybrid adjustable weight bench">Flybrid adjustable weight benches</a> are perfect for your home gym. This type of weigth bench fits in any room with a compact foldable design and can be stored in any closet. The weight benches are built to last, with a sturdy steel frame guaranteed to hold up to 1000 lbs and use premium-quality padding. Adjustable weight bench will take up little space in your home gym, but it delivers an incredible amount of versatility. You can do flat, incline, and decline barbell training or dumbbell training on this kind of bench.</p>
<h3>Flat Weight Bench</h3>
<p>The best flat weight bench is made with sweat-proof and tear-resistant materials and is manufactured to last. It also has a backrest, is easy to assemble, and includes a lifetime warranty. You want to make sure that your <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/products/flybird-foldable-flat-weight-bench" title="Flybird flat weight bench">Flybird flat weight bench</a> is tough enough to withstand heavy use, which means it must be durable. Ideally, it should be made using sweat-proof and tear-resistant materials built to last. Additionally, you'll want a bench with a backrest so that you have the option of sitting up rather than lying down for specific exercises.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Flybird weight bench is a good solution for home gym. As you know, Flybird is known for its best-quality product. If you are looking bench for your home gym, then Flybird Weight Bench is the right choice. It is not very expensive equipment, and it has high-tech features that can meet your need to exercise many parts of the body while helping to improve your health and body posture.</p>
<h3></h3>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/best-upper-body-strength-exercises</id>
    <published>2022-04-15T18:42:13+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-04-15T18:42:14+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/best-upper-body-strength-exercises"/>
    <title>Best Upper Body Strength Exercises</title>
    <author>
      <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[If you want to build a rock-hard set of pecs, you need to do a lot of pressing. There are any number of excellent pressing exercises you can use to get big and strong chest muscles. However, there's a handful of upper body strength exercises that will achieve this much quicker than others.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/best-upper-body-strength-exercises">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>When you think of upper body strength exercises, what comes to mind? Maybe it's push-ups and bench pressing. Both of these exercises have their place in a well-rounded strength routine. They are great for building big bulky muscles. But let's be honest, that is not why we're here! We are here because we want to build a strong chest, back, shoulders, and arms — not huge bulky muscles, but a lean and mean upper body.</p>
<p>If you're new to exercise, or returning after a long hiatus, it can be intimidating to look at all the different exercises you can do for your upper body. This article will give an overview of some of the best upper body strength exercises that you can add to your routine today.</p>
<h2>Incline Push-Ups</h2>
<p><br>Incline push-ups are great for beginners to start working out their upper body. They are also a great exercise for anyone that is unable to do a regular push-up. The incline push-up will help build strength and endurance in the pecs, triceps, shoulders, and upper back muscles. This will help improve your regular push-ups and help you progress to more difficult exercises.</p>
<h2>
<br>Bicep Curls</h2>
<p><br>This workout is effective at building bicep strength and endurance. Bicep curls are an essential part of any upper body workout since they work on one of the most noticeable muscle groups on the upper body.<br><br>If you have access to free weights, you can use <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/dumbbells" title="Flybrid adjustable dumbbells">dumbbells</a> or barbells to do this exercise. However, if you do not have access to free weights, then you will need an alternative way to do this exercise. To make your own weights at home, simply fill up two water bottles and tie them together with a rope or string so that they stay in place. You can also use soup cans or other canned goods as weights instead of water bottles.</p>
<h2>Diamond Push-Ups</h2>
<p><br>Diamond push-ups are great for working the triceps (the muscle on the back of your upper arm). It's a variation of the standard push-up that compresses the muscle against your forearm.<br><br>Here's how to do it: Get into a standard push-up position, but instead of placing your hands flat on the ground, put them in a diamond position with your thumbs touching and index fingers touching. The knuckles of both hands should form a point aimed towards your feet. Lower yourself down until your chest almost touches the ground then squeeze back up to create tension in the triceps. Do 3 sets of 10 reps with 30 seconds rest between each set.</p>
<h2>Tricep Extension</h2>
<p><br>Stand with your feet shoulder width apart and bend at the knees. Keep your back straight and your head up. Lift a dumbbell in your right hand and stand with your arm straight above you, locking it into position. Bend your elbow to bring the weight down behind your head, allowing only your forearm to move. Hold for a moment, then return to the starting position. Do reps for each arm.</p>
<h2>Staggered Push-Ups</h2>
<p><br>This exercise requires you to keep your body straight, with only the tips of one foot and one hand touching the floor. The other parts of your body are suspended in the air. You start this exercise by getting into a push-up position, then moving one leg forward so that it forms a 90 degree angle with your body. Now move the other leg as far back as possible so that it is also at about a 90 degrees angle from your body. You should look like a triangle now. Do a push up, then repeat this same sequence on the opposite side. Perform 2 sets of 8 reps each for this exercise.<br><br></p>
<h2>Lateral Pulldown</h2>
<p>The lateral pulldown is a great exercise for a strong back.<br><br>Start with your feet firmly on the ground, straddling the machine and placing your hands on the bar slightly wider than shoulder-width apart. Slowly pull the bar down until it reaches your chest, feeling the muscles between your shoulder blades tighten. Hold this position for a second before slowly returning to the starting position.<br><br>Repeat this movement until you have completed three sets of eight to 10 reps at a weight that is challenging but allows you to maintain control throughout each rep.</p>
<h2>Upright Row/Front Raise Combo</h2>
<p>This combo works both the front and back of your shoulders, as well as your traps. It also works your grip, which can be a weak point for many people. You may find that you have to reduce the weight when you add the front raise or use dumbbells instead of a barbell.<br><br>Start with a barbell held in front of your thighs. Your hands should be just outside your hips, palms facing you.<br><br>Raise the bar up to around chin level with a vertical motion, keeping your elbows out to the sides at all times.<br><br>Lower it under control back to the starting position.<br><br>Without pausing, raise the bar straight in front of you to shoulder level, then lower it under control.</p>
<h2>Seated Dumbbell Shoulder Press</h2>
<p>A seated shoulder press is a classic exercise for building overall shoulder strength. This exercise targets your entire shoulder, including the front and middle deltoids and the triceps.<br><br>To complete this exercise, sit on a <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/weight-benches" title="Flybird adjustable weight bench">weight bench</a> with an upright back support and grab a pair of dumbbells. Hold the dumbbells by your shoulders with your elbows bent and palms facing out. Push the weights above your head until your arms are almost straight, then slowly lower them back to your shoulders.</p>
<h2>Seated Row</h2>
<p>The seated row targets the rhomboids, which are a pair of muscles that connect your thoracic vertebrae to the spine of your scapula (shoulder blade). It also engages the trapezius or upper back muscle.<br><br>To complete this exercise, sit down at a cable row machine with a straight back and plant both feet firmly on the ground. Pull in both handles next to your sides with your arms extended straight in front of you and lower them in a slow and controlled motion until they reach waist level.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>In any case, these are the best upper body strength exercises. If you're looking to bring up your biceps and triceps, then these exercises should help you get there. Just remember, these are all compound exercises, which means they work multiple muscle groups at once. This means that the more muscle groups involved in an exercise, the better it is for building overall strength and size. That's not to say you can't build good size through isolation exercises—you certainly can—but that shouldn't be your only focus.<br><br>The best upper body strength exercises are the key to upper body fitness as they target every upper body muscle group in a manner that allows all of these muscles to perform to their full potential, when combined with lower body exercises. The three exercises highlighted above should be performed at least once, preferably twice a week as part of an effective upper and lower body workout regime. If you want to get the most out of your workouts, it is important that you come up with a routine that suits your personal fitness goals and target areas.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/are-all-processed-foods-bad-for-you</id>
    <published>2022-04-06T21:02:22+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-04-06T21:02:23+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/are-all-processed-foods-bad-for-you"/>
    <title>Are All Processed Foods Bad for You?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[While preparing meals can be more time consuming, it is also safer and healthier than grabbing a processed food product. Are all processed foods bad? The answer is surprisingly simple — "No".<p><a class="read-more" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/are-all-processed-foods-bad-for-you">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Not all processed foods are bad for you. Many are in fact good for you. The term processed food can seem to be a bit misleading. Essentially, it's a pretty broad description for any type of food that has been changed from its original form for preservation purposes. However, there is a common misconception that all processed foods are terrible. This couldn't be further from the truth. Processed foods are actually an important part of a healthy diet, assuming they're used in moderation and consumed in proper portions!</p>
<h2>What are processed foods?</h2>
<p>Processed foods are those which have been altered in some way through cooking, canning, freezing, dehydration, or milling.<br><br>Processed foods often contain added ingredients such as salt, sugars, or fats that aren't necessarily needed to turn the wholefoods into the final product.</p>
<h2>What does “processed” mean?</h2>
<p>The use of the word “processed” may be a little confusing because it can mean different things depending on who you’re talking to. When I refer to processed foods, I mean foods that are altered from their natural state in some way. For example, cleaning a vegetable is a processing step. So is cooking it, or grinding it into flour.<br><br>Other people might use the term “processed food” to refer to foods that are prepared with chemicals or additives that don’t occur naturally – the kinds of foods you find on the outer edges of the grocery store, where all of the processed foods live (salad dressings, chips, cookies).<br><br>For me, both kinds of processing are relevant; we should try to eat as many minimally-processed whole foods as possible for health reasons, and we should avoid highly-processed fake foods and junky additives – but only for health reasons as well.<br><br>So let’s talk about why processed food is “bad for you” – or at least why we all think it is.</p>
<h2>Why are processed foods bad for you?</h2>
<p>You might think that all processed foods are bad for you because they contain ingredients like fat and salt, but it's not so simple.<br><br>For example, some foods have to be processed to make them safe to eat or to keep them from going off before we have a chance to eat them. Pasteurizing milk and bottling fruit juice are both examples of processes that improve the safety of our food without changing its natural nutrition too much.<br><br>However, some processing methods do add a lot of extra fat, sugar, or salt - the three things we're advised to cut down on for a healthy diet. This is because people tend to prefer eating these ingredients.</p>
<h2>Not all processed foods are bad for you.</h2>
<p>Processing isn't always bad. Some foods are processed to add nutrients, such as vitamins and minerals. That's the case with enriched grains like white bread and pasta, which may be made from whole-grain products but stripped of some of their natural nutrients during processing. The vitamins and minerals are then added back in to make the food more nutritious. It's best to read the ingredient list on any processed food you buy to know what it contains.<br><br>Processed foods aren't always unhealthy, either. In fact, many processed foods can be a part of a healthy diet — as long as they're eaten in moderation.<br><br>Nutritious versions of processed foods do exist, such as canned fruits and vegetables without added salt or sugar, canned tuna fish without salt, frozen fruits and vegetables without added sauces, and 100% whole-grain bread or cereals that provide fiber. Check the Nutrition Facts label for sodium content when selecting canned foods; choose those with less than 140mg per serving.<br><br>Some people think that all processed foods are bad for you, but that's not true. The danger of highly processed foods is that they contain a lot of added sugar, which can lead to weight gain if you eat too much of it. High intakes of saturated fat and sodium also aren't healthy, as these nutrients may contribute to heart disease (1Trusted Source).<br><br>However, there are several other types of processed foods that contain little or no added sugar and can be part of a healthy diet, such as:<br><br></p>
<ul>
<li>Nut butter</li>
<li>Canned fruits and vegetables</li>
<li>Dried fruits</li>
<li>Canned beans and legumes</li>
<li>Yogurt</li>
<li>Cheese</li>
<li>Some breakfast cereals</li>
</ul>
<p><br>Processed foods can be beneficial because they ensure a consistent supply of certain nutritious fruits and vegetables year-round. They also provide a convenient source of key nutrients, like protein and fiber, while helping reduce risk of diet-related disease.</p>
<h2>Is there a difference between processed and ultra-processed foods?</h2>
<p>Processed food is any food that has undergone a transformation that changes it from its original state. The most common examples of processed foods are canned vegetables, fruit juice, and flour.<br><br>Ultra-processed foods represent a subgroup of processed foods that go through several more steps to create highly palatable products with long shelf lives. They contain added flavors, colors, sweeteners, preservatives, and other ingredients such as emulsifiers, humectants, and texturizers. Examples include breaded chicken nuggets, breakfast cereals, sodas, and pizza.<br><br>There is a difference between processed and ultra-processed foods. Foods that are minimally processed — such as refrigerated or frozen vegetables and fruits, bagged lettuce, dried fruit, roasted nuts, canned beans and fish, cured meats, and cheeses — are generally fine to consume, so long as they don't contain added sugar.<br><br>Ultra-processed foods include sugary cereals, sodas, pastries, and packaged snack foods like chips and crackers. They often have a long list of ingredients, flavor enhancers, and preservatives. These foods can be high in calories and low in nutritional value.<br><br>The American Heart Association recommends eating more whole grains, fruits, and vegetables in place of refined grains, sugars, and saturated fats from processed foods.</p>
<h2>How to eat healthy, even when eating processed foods.</h2>
<p>Processed foods often get a bad name. They’re often high in sugar, salt, fat, and calories — and low in fiber, vitamins, and minerals.<br><br>But some processed foods can be part of a healthy diet.<br><br>In fact, many packaged foods are processed but still good for you. Examples include canned vegetables, frozen fruit and vegetables, canned tuna or salmon, 100% fruit juice, and pre-made salads.<br><br><br>Some foods are minimally processed, such as bagged spinach, cut vegetables, and roasted nuts. Other highly processed foods include bacon, smoked salmon, ice cream, and hot dogs. When you're shopping for processed foods, choose those made with whole grains, low-fat dairy products, and fruits and vegetables. Avoid products that contain partially hydrogenated fats or high-fructose corn syrup.<br><br>Most Americans consume too much sodium — about 3,400 milligrams per day — which can raise blood pressure. You should limit your daily sodium intake to 2,300 milligrams or less.<br><br>Sugar is another area of concern with processed foods because it's added to many packaged foods and beverages to improve their taste. Too much added sugar can lead to weight gain, diabetes, and heart disease. Be aware of the total amount of sugar in the food you eat. Look for different types of sugar, such as sucrose, fructose, and glucose in the ingredients list on the nutrition facts label. Eat only small amounts of foods that contain added sugars.</p>
<p>When looking for processed foods to add to your diet, make sure they meet these criteria:<br><br></p>
<ul>
<li>They don't come in a box or package that has more than five ingredients listed on the label.</li>
<li>They aren't fried.</li>
<li>They aren't full of sugar or high-fructose corn syrup.</li>
<li>They have no hydrogenated or partially hydrogenated oils (trans fats).</li>
<li>They are low in sodium — less than 140 milligrams per serving.</li>
</ul>
<h2>Follow healthy eating criteria to make sure what you eat is good for you.</h2>
<p>So really, there is no need to demonize all processed foods. You just have to do your homework and make sure whatever food you are eating meets the healthy eating criteria that would be used by scientists. But if it's fast, easy and cheap just eat it sometimes even if it's "processed".</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/10-answers-to-your-questions-about-flybird-weight-bench</id>
    <published>2022-04-03T23:44:35+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-04-03T23:44:36+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/10-answers-to-your-questions-about-flybird-weight-bench"/>
    <title>10 Answers to Your Questions About Flybird Weight Bench</title>
    <author>
      <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[If you're not sure whether the Flybird Weight Bench is right for you or your needs, this post will help. I<p><a class="read-more" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/10-answers-to-your-questions-about-flybird-weight-bench">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p> </p>
<p>f you are interested in Flybird Bench, I believe that you are one of the people who like to get good things. In this case, you will get an appropriate product. In addition, it should be a product that can provide benefits for you. You might be curious about what these benefits or features are. Of course, you can get several benefits and features when saving money and getting the best goods, but it all began with asking questions. This article will give answers to your questions about <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/" title="Flybird Fitness">Flybird Fitness</a>.</p>
<h2>
<br>Could I Do Incline Situps on This Bench?</h2>
<p><br>Yes, you can do incline situps on this bench. This bench is sturdy and stable enough to handle any exercise you put it through. It is also rated for 600lbs weight capacity. It is a solid piece of equipment. You can do incline situps on this bench. The decline position offers an easier way to perform decline situps (also known as reverse crunches). If you want to do incline situps, you can constantly adjust the bench and use it in a flat position.</p>
<h2>
<br>What Is the Size of Flybird Bench When Folded?</h2>
<p><br>The foldable weight bench is the most convenient and practical feature of this workout bench, for you can fold it up and store it under the bed or closet when you finish the workout. It saves so much space for you and is easy to carry out. The exact folded dimension is 31" x 11 ", which lets you quickly put it in your car. The lightweight makes it easy to carry out or move around. This is why so many people choose it as their home gym equipment.</p>
<h2>
<br>Can Flybird Bench Be Used for Bench Presses?</h2>
<p><br>You can do a bench press on the Flybird Bench, but it isn't designed for this exercise. The bench is designed to be stationary and bolted to the ground to don't slide around on you while doing activities like squatting or shoulder pressing. It also has a narrow seat because it is designed for those exercises. If you want to do a bench press, the best bet is to get an <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/weight-benches" title="Flybird adjustable weight bench">adjustable weight bench</a> specifically designed for this exercise.</p>
<h2>
<br>Would I Reach the Floor If I'm Only 5'2?</h2>
<p><br>The answer is yes, with the bench at its lowest setting (height of 16"), a person of 5'2" should have no trouble reaching the floor to do pushups. We have found that people tend to overestimate what height they need to get to the bottom while performing pushups. This is because reaching full extension on a pushup requires less size than one might think. Most people, their arms will only extend about 6-8" from their body when performing a pushup. So if you are 5'2" tall and your arms are 6", you would only need 10" of height for your hands to reach the floor at full extension in a pushup position.</p>
<h2>
<br>How Can I Adjust the Angles of Workout Flybird Bench?</h2>
<p><br>The Flybird Bench is designed to support the most common angle settings (incline, decline, and flat), which are great for various exercises on , <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/dumbbells" title="Flybird adjustable dumbbell">Flybird adjustable dumbbell</a>. Here are steps to adjust the angle:</p>
<p> </p>
<ul>
<li>Unfold the bench to its full upright position and place it on a flat surface.</li>
<li>Find each of the four tension knobs located on the underside of the bench facing down. Then insert your fingers or an Allen wrench into each knob and turn them counterclockwise until they're entirely loose.</li>
<li>Lift on the bench and set it at an angle (incline, decline, or flat). You can move it to any custom angle between these three positions to find your preferred setting for working out, but we recommend keeping the back pad at a 90-degree angle to avoid injury.</li>
<li>Once you've found your desired angle, hold the back pad in place with one hand and tighten each knob by turning it clockwise with your other hand or with an Allen wrench until they're snug but not too tight.</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<h2>
<br>How Stable Is Flybird Bench? Does It Wobble Even a Little?</h2>
<p><br>Fly bird benches are designed to be stable and wobble-free at all times. It is tough to force the bench to move out of position with the backrest in place. If you push on the seat while sitting on it, you will create a wobble (as with any bench), but that is not how Flybird benches are intended to be used. To achieve maximum stability and safety, the backrest should always be upright. If you want to lie horizontally on the bench, remove the backrest (it can be attached in seconds). The result of this design is a bench that has excellent stability and a rock-solid feel.</p>
<h2>
<br>Can You Store This in Covered Patio/Balcony? Will It Last?</h2>
<p><br>This bench is weather resistant but not waterproof. Storing it on an uncovered patio or balcony will expose it to rain and moisture, which will damage the wood. The top is made of solid Acacia wood with a natural, distressed look and is weather-resistant. Wood has natural color and grain pattern variations and may differ from the photo shown here. If you're storing it outside all year round, investing in a cover to keep it dry or bringing it inside during wet weather is recommended.</p>
<h2>Does This Foldable Flybird Bench Have Wheels?</h2>
<p><br>No, this foldable fly bird bench doesn't have wheels. It is unnecessary to have wheels. The bench's surface is very smooth, and the bar is already very light, so it is easy to move. The weight of the fly bird court is about 30 pounds. This bench can be moved around without wheels. It's not too heavy to carry around, and it has handles. If you need to move it from one room to another room or outside in your backyard for a workout, it's no problem.</p>
<h2>
<br>How Do You Set up the Foot Rest of Flybird Bench?</h2>
<p><br>It's straightforward to set up the footrest. You need to screw the feet on. The feet have been pre-installed on the bottom tube of the bench already, so you don't need to use washers during assembly. Here are steps to Set up the Foot Rest of Flybird benches:</p>
<ul>
<li>Unscrew one of the two screws that hold the bottom tube in place.</li>
<li>Take off the plastic cover and insert one of the footrests into the pre-drilled holes.</li>
<li>Put back on the plastic cover and screw it back into its original position.</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<h2>
<br>Could I Do Decline Situps on Flybird Bench?</h2>
<p><br>The answer is Yes. Decline situps help develop your lower abdominal muscle fibers. They also help stretch and strengthen the hip flexors in your upper legs. Because of the limited range of motion, you have on the bench, you should perform fewer repetitions per set than you would with a standard situp. Here are how to do situps on a Flybird bench:</p>
<ul>
<li>Position yourself on a decline bench to secure both feet into the footrest. Hold onto the sides of the bench for support as you lie flat on your back and then raise your arms above your head.</li>
<li>Slowly raise your torso toward your knees by contracting the abs. Pause for a moment, then slowly return to starting position and repeat.</li>
</ul>
<p> </p>
<h2>
<br>Wrapping Up</h2>
<p><br>The Flybird bench comes with a full range of height, width, and depth options to suit the dimensions of any shower. Other features include an extra-large molded seat for added comfort, an optional recessed deck for easy cleaning, <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/weight-benches" title="Flybird weight bench">Flybird weight bench</a>, and superb durability. The curved vertical support bars allow you to take a seat from either side without ever feeling squeezed or confined. All in all, your purchase is risk-free when you go with the Flybird bench.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/april-2022-best-workout-plan-for-you</id>
    <published>2022-04-01T15:00:01+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-04-01T15:00:01+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/april-2022-best-workout-plan-for-you"/>
    <title>April 2022 – Best Workout Plan For You</title>
    <author>
      <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Looking for the best workout plan for April 2022? Check out the flybird weight bench. The flybird weight bench helps to improve your repetitions and strength. Perfect for beginners and advanced alike, this is a great way to get starting that new workout routine.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/april-2022-best-workout-plan-for-you">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>First off, in <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/2022-march-best-workout-plan-for-your-type" title="March 2022 - Best Workout Plan For Your Type">March</a>, you laid the groundwork for your fitness journey. You got yourself off to a great start in March by learning about some simple tips that will make you want to work out and get fit. As such, you will feel good about what is happening with your body.<br><br>When you start working out in April, you will also feel good. You may even feel better than you did before because you know what to expect and what to do. You will have a much better idea of how your <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/4-simple-steps-to-create-a-beginners-workout-plan" title="4 Simple Steps to Create a Beginner's Workout Plan">workout plan</a> is going to work. This will make it easier for you to focus on what is happening with your body and with your workouts. Obviously, this is going to be much better for you. It will help improve your results and make you want to keep going.</p>
<p>If you're looking to get in shape for the upcoming summer but don't want to pay an arm and a leg for equipment, then this is the month for you. <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/" title="Flybrid Fitness">Flybird Fitness</a>, one of the best home fitness brands around, has discounts on a bunch of their best-sellers for the Spring Sale. There's a situp bench that lets you do a ton of core exercises that'll strengthen your abs and lower back and get you ready to show off at the beach this summer. And Flybird has adjustable dumbbells that let you change weight easily so you can focus on getting stronger and building muscle instead of wasting time constantly switching plates out.<br><br>If you haven't gotten started yet or need some new gear to replace your old stuff, check out these deals now before they expire!</p>
<h2>The Scientific Approach to the Best Workout Plan for You</h2>
<p>It's the end of March and the start of April, which means it's a great time to take stock of your fitness goals and consider whether your workout plan is working for you. As we approach summer, we can't help but think about what comes next.<br><br>First, we'll have to admit that whatever exercise we're currently doing isn't working. Maybe it's not as effective as we'd like, or maybe it no longer excites us. Whatever the case, it's important to evaluate our current routine and consider what changes need to be made in order to achieve better results.<br><br>Next, we'll have to think about what kind of person we want to be. Are you the type who likes getting up early and going for a run? Or maybe you're more of an evening exerciser. Whatever your style, there are workouts that will suit your personality type.<br><br>Finally, we'll have to decide on a goal. What do you want from your workout? Do you want to lose weight? Get stronger? Increase endurance? Establishing a clear objective will make all the difference when it comes time to put together a workout plan that works for you!</p>
<p>If you're looking to bulk up, you can't beat Flybird's home gym equipment. In fact, right now Flybird Fitness has got a deal on <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/weight-benches" title="Flybird adjustable workout bench">Flybird adjustable weight bench</a> and <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/dumbbells" title="Flybrid adjustable dumbbells">Flybird adjustable dumbbells</a>.<br><br>But if you're not sure what exercises to do, check out our guide to the best workout routines for each month. With April fast approaching, it's time to get serious about lifting.<br><br>You'll need at least three days a week for this routine — ideally more like five. We recommend alternating between the following muscle groups:<br><br></p>
<ul>
<li>Chest - pec deck</li>
<li>Shoulders - overhead press</li>
<li>Back - seated row or pullup</li>
<li>Triceps - overhead extension with rope handle or lying triceps extension</li>
<li>Biceps - barbell curl or hammer curl</li>
<li>Legs - leg press or leg extension</li>
<li>Abs - hanging leg raise or ab roller</li>
</ul>
<p>In order to build a strong base, you will want to focus on the major muscle groups: legs, chest, and back.<br><br>This is what the foundation of your program will look like for the month of April.<br><br></p>
<ol>
<li>Chest: Incline Dumbbell Bench Press 3 sets of 10-12 reps</li>
<li>Back: Bent Over Barbell Row 3 sets of 8-10 reps</li>
<li>Legs: Back Squat 3 sets of 6-8 reps</li>
<li>Shoulders: Military Press 3 sets of 10-12 reps</li>
<li>Biceps: Standing Barbell Curl 3 sets of 8-10 reps</li>
<li>Triceps: Close Grip Bench Press 3 sets of 10-12 reps</li>
</ol>
<p>The best workout plan for you is the one that combines getting stronger with better body mechanics.<br><br>Getting stronger is a good idea because it can help you build more muscle mass and also because it can improve your overall health and fitness.<br><br>However, if you are not working out correctly you may be missing out on some of these benefits.<br><br>For example, by building stronger shoulder muscles you can become more flexible and agile as well as less prone to injury. If you have weak shoulders then when lifting heavy weights or doing any type of overhead activity like overhead presses or barbell rows they will be compromised by this weakness.<br><br>Other benefits include:<br><br>• Increased strength and power output from your muscles<br><br>• Improved coordination between different muscle groups such as your shoulders, arms, and legs<br><br>• Increased range of motion for joint movements like squats and deadlifts with less risk of injury due to overuse injuries like tendonitis or bursitis (these types of injuries usually occur when performing exercises incorrectly).<br><br>Before you start your shoulder workout, it's important to warm up. This helps reduce injury and increase flexibility and strength. A simple warm-up involves walking or jogging for five minutes, followed by doing 10 jumping jacks and 10 bodyweight squats. If you have extra time, you can also do some light stretching before your workout.<br><br>The next step is to do some resistance training. The best way to do this is to choose one exercise from each of the following categories: push, pull, squat, and hinge. Perform three sets of eight to 12 reps for each exercise.<br><br>Push exercises include push-ups, dips, and overhead presses. Pull exercises include dumbbell rows and pull-ups. Squat exercises include goblet squats and lunges. Hinge exercises include deadlifts, kettlebell swings and hip thrusts.<br><br>To finish your workout, do a cool down routine that involves light stretching for five minutes or more.</p>
<p>Aside from all of the tips mentioned above, remember to keep it slow and steady.  Don't worry about overdoing it, or pushing through exercise pains—that is going to be counterproductive. Take the time to learn from, take your time doing each individual exercise, and make sure you're relieving any tightness in your muscles as you go. This is a good way of making sure that you're getting all of the full workout benefits while simultaneously avoiding bad habits and unnecessary strain on your musculoskeletal system.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/how-do-i-register-my-work-bench-for-warranty</id>
    <published>2022-03-30T14:40:44+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-03-30T14:43:14+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/how-do-i-register-my-work-bench-for-warranty"/>
    <title>How do I Register My Flybird Weight Bench for Warranty?</title>
    <author>
      <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Previous buyers have confirmed many times over that the Flybird Weight Bench has a wonderful warranty. Even so, you may find certain aspects of it to be unclear, or you might be wondering how exactly you go about using it. In a nutshell, the process is easy and uncomplicated, which is good news for buyers and sellers alike.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/how-do-i-register-my-work-bench-for-warranty">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>We know that accidents happen and sometimes the bolts or parts may break or fall off after long periods of use. This is why we ensure that all our weight benches come with a 1 year warranty, so you can feel at ease knowing that if your bench suffers any defects in using, you will be able to claim against it. <br><br>You don't need to register your weight bench for warranty service, it's already covered by the 1-year warranty that covers any defects in materials and workmanship. All Flybird weight benches arrive with a 1-year warranty from the day of delivery. This means if anything goes wrong within the next year, we will repair it free of charge or replace it completely at no cost to you.</p>
<p>Anyone can ask a question such as "How do I register for warranty?" and expect a detailed answer. The only problem is that you must provide every single detail about your purchase in order to get the help you need. </p>
<h2>Ordered from Flybird Fitness website</h2>
<p> We offer a 12-month warranty period on all of our equipment. If you have any issues with your new equipment please contact our customer service team by sending an email request to <a href="mailto:service@flybirdfitness.com" title="Contact Flybird support team">service@flybirdfitness.com</a> or leave message at <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/pages/contact-us" title="Contact Flybird Fitness">Contact Us</a> page.<br><br>Please include the following information in your email to help us resolve your issue as quickly as possible:<br><br></p>
<ul>
<li>Your order number (can be found on your confirmation email)</li>
<li>Order date</li>
<li>Your first and last name</li>
<li>Your shipping address</li>
<li>Issues you meet</li>
<li>Any photos or videos(if applicable)</li>
</ul>
<p>We will always do our best to provide a quick resolution to your issue as quickly and efficiently as possible.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Ordered from Amazon</h2>
<p>To claim your Flybird Weight Bench for warranty, you'll want to provide us with the following information:<br><br></p>
<ul>
<li>Your Amazon order number</li>
<li>Order date</li>
<li>Your first and last name</li>
<li>Your shipping address</li>
<li>Issues you meet</li>
<li>Any photos or videos(if applicable)</li>
</ul>
<p><br>If you bought a Flybird weight bench from Amazon, please send an email to <a href="maito:flybirdfitness.com" target="_blank" title="Flybird Amazon Support" rel="noopener noreferrer">flybirdfitness@gmail.com</a> with the above information so that we can arrange a return/refund or replacement. We will respond within 24 hours and make sure you get a satisfactory solution.</p>
<h2>Order from other Retailers</h2>
<p>If you have purchased your <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/weight-benches" title="Flybrid Adjustable weight bench">Flybird weight bench</a> through a local fitness retailer, please contact them directly. They will be able to submit a warranty claim on your behalf and provide you with further assistance. For warranty claims submitted directly on the website, they will be processed within 24 hours. You will receive an e-mail confirmation once the claims has been processed, or if there are any issues with the claim that must be addressed. If the issue cannot be resolved through warranty coverage, then Flybird Fitness will handle this in a higher level of service by reaching out to customers directly during normal business hours Monday through Friday.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>We hope that this article has provided you helpful information on how to register your Flybird bench for warranty. If you would like to contact us with further questions, you can do so by calling 253 733 1752 or emailing service@flybirdfitness.com.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Related Articles</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/how-to-get-a-flybird-weight-bench-replacement-pin" title="How to Get a Flybrid bench Replacement Pin"><em>How to Get a Replacement Pin</em></a></li>
<li><em><a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/how-to-assemble-the-flybird-adjustable-bench" title="How To Assemble the Flybird Adjustable Weight Bench">How To Assemble the Flybird Adjustable Weight Bench</a></em></li>
</ul>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/5-reasons-why-you-should-incorporate-a-flybird-workout-bench-into-your-fitness-routine</id>
    <published>2022-03-28T19:17:03+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-03-28T19:17:03+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/5-reasons-why-you-should-incorporate-a-flybird-workout-bench-into-your-fitness-routine"/>
    <title>5 Reasons Why You Should Incorporate a Flybird Workout Bench into Your Fitness Routine</title>
    <author>
      <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[The number one reason you should invest in a Flybird weight bench is to improve your health and overall well-being. They are great for strength training and core conditioning. They are also incredibly versatile and you can use them for any type of exercise you are doing.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/5-reasons-why-you-should-incorporate-a-flybird-workout-bench-into-your-fitness-routine">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>The use of a workout bench or exercise equipment improves strength and muscle definition during exercise by providing additional support. Thankfully, you can find a wide variety of benches that are suitable for your style and needs. However, I would like to introduce a more basic and innovative product called the <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/weight-benches" title="Flybird workout bench">FlyBird Workout Bench</a>.<br><br><br><br>What is the Flybird Workout Bench? The Flybird Workout Bench is a special type of <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/weight-benches" title="Flybird weight bench">weight bench</a> that allows you to have your own gym at home. This product is suitable for individuals because it has a wide range of benefits, from having an effective workout of your muscles to keeping your household fit and active. Below are 5 top reasons why you should have the FlyBird Workout Bench in your home.</p>
<h2>Comfort</h2>
<p><br><br>A lot of folks are intimidated by the idea of lifting weights. If you aren't a pro bodybuilder, the whole scene can seem a bit daunting. Many people I talk to about fitness have concerns about getting hurt in the gym or feeling out of place among more experienced lifters.<br><br>I think one of the best ways to alleviate this discomfort is by building a home workout space with simple, approachable equipment. That's where the <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/weight-benches" title="Flybrid adjustable weight bench">Flybird Adjustable Weight Bench</a> comes into play. This bench is built with versatility and comfort in mind, allowing you to perform a variety of exercises in your own home. With convenient design features like an adjustable seat and removable leg hold-down bar, it's never been easier to get an effective weight-training session in your own home.</p>
<h2>Adjustability</h2>
<p>The Flybird Workout Bench is one of our most popular and best-selling products for a reason. It's not just that it's affordable, easy to store, and can be used for a wide variety of exercises. It's that it's adjustable to accommodate the needs of so many different people.<br><br>Most workout benches have a single position, which inevitably makes them good for some exercises, but not others. If you've ever tried bench pressing and found your feet hanging off the end of your bench, you know what we're talking about!<br><br>Flybird's Adjustable Weight Bench is the perfect addition to any fitness routine. It offers a wide range of adjustments that allow you to work out from multiple angles. These range from flat, incline, and decline positions, all the way up to 90-degrees for upright rows.<br><br>You can also adjust the leg support as well as the height of the backrest to accommodate your size and fitness level. This adjustability lets you perform a variety of exercises across your entire body for an efficient workout.</p>
<h2>
<br>Affordability</h2>
<p><br><br> One of the biggest advantages of incorporating a flybird workout bench into your fitness routine is that it's affordable. It's not too expensive, so finding a good one at an affordable price is doable. This makes it easy for anyone to add this piece of equipment to their home gym without breaking the bank.<br><br>Unlike other brands, <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/" title="Flybird Fitness">Flybird</a> offers competitive prices on fitness equipment and provides free shipping on most products. One of their main benefits is the ability to transform your home into a gym without breaking the bank. The Flybird adjustable weight bench is under $150, an unbeatable price for this type of product. And unlike their competitors, Flybird doesn't cut corners when it comes to quality or customer service.</p>
<h2>Storage</h2>
<p>One of the most common complaints customers have about workout equipment is that it takes up far too much space. What use is a good piece of equipment if you can't store it anywhere?<br><br>Well, the Flybird Adjustable Bench has a solution to that problem. <br><br>Even if you're short on space at home, you can still fit a workout bench into your space. These benches are designed to fold up and take up a tiny footprint when not in use. Or, you can simply lean the Flybird Bench against the wall to store it out of the way.<br><br>The Flybird Adjustable Weight Bench is a solid choice for those who want to work out at home but don't have much space. It's simple to use and easy to store. And, it's priced so that anyone can incorporate this versatile piece of equipment into their fitness routine.<br><br>It's also worth noting that the bench comes with a strip so that you can hang it on the wall!</p>
<h2>Built to Last</h2>
<p>One of the biggest issues with most workout equipment is that it's cheaply made. You might get a couple of months out of it, but eventually, the stitching will come apart, or the foam will wear through, and you'll have to buy another one.<br><br>The good news is that the Flybird adjustable weight bench is built to last, and it's backed by a lifetime warranty. This means no matter what happens over the years, you'll be covered.<br>If you've ever spent much time with a bench press, you know that most are leaky pieces of junk that bend and break under the slightest pressure. Not only can this become a huge safety hazard if you're doing heavy squats or bench presses, but it also hurts your progress because you have to be extra careful of your form and weight. This is why Flybird's bench is built from solid steel rods with reinforced plates and a durable high-quality vinyl cover.</p>
<p>As more and more people realize the benefits of purchasing new equipment, fitness promoters are beginning to push the envelope when it comes to what they can offer at the gym. Luckily, weight benches like the Flybird provide excellent value for your money, and should be considered seriously by all fitness enthusiasts.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/how-to-get-a-flybird-weight-bench-replacement-pin</id>
    <published>2022-03-25T19:11:29+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-03-26T10:36:27+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/how-to-get-a-flybird-weight-bench-replacement-pin"/>
    <title>How to Get a Replacement Pin</title>
    <author>
      <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Just one pin breaks on your weight bench and it can be extremely difficult to find a replacement. This guide will walk you through the steps needed to get a replacement pin for your weight bench.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/how-to-get-a-flybird-weight-bench-replacement-pin">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>We often get asked how our customers can get a replacement pin for their Flybird weight bench. So, I thought it would be a good idea to write a blog post about it (Thanks for the suggestion Dave).</p>
<p>Most people don't realize that <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/weight-benches" title="Flybird adjustable weight bench">Flybird weight benches</a> can be outfitted with a replacement pin. This is why your Flybird weight bench is no longer sitting flat and giving the support you need. The best way to get your Flybird weight bench back up and running again is to install a replacement pin assembly.<br><br>Have you lost or damaged the pin for your Flybird Weights bench? It happens. When you need a replacement pin for your Flybird weights bench, start by contacting customer service.</p>
<p>You can request a replacement pin from Flybird's website or directly from Amazon, depending on where you bought the bench.</p>
<h2>Ordered from Flybird Fitness website</h2>
<p><strong>1. Contact us</strong><br><br>If you need a replacement pin for your weight bench, contact our customer service team by sending an email request to <a href="mailto:service@flybirdfitness.com" title="Flybird Customer Service">service@flybirdfitness.com</a><br><br><strong>2. Send us a picture of the damaged pin</strong><br><br>Once you've contacted us, we'll need some information from you. For your convenience, you can include a picture of the damaged pin in your description so we can ensure you get the exact replacement pin you need.<br><br><strong>3. Details about the size of your weight bench</strong><br><br>Next, you'll need to provide details about the weight bench where you lost the pin, including its make, model and size. We'll use this information to find a compatible replacement pin.<br><br><strong>4. Wait for the arrival of your replacement pin</strong><br><br>After we confirm that you have a compatible pin, we'll ship it out to you within 24 hours and provide tracking information so you can follow its progress.</p>
<p>The best way to do this is to write an email message using the format provided below. The email must include the following information:<br><br>1) Your name, address, and phone number.<br><br>2) Order information (purchase date and order number if possible).<br><br>3) A brief explanation of what happened. This can include your original order information, pictures of the part, or any other factors that were relevant.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Ordered from Amazon</h2>
<p> To get a replacement pin:<br><br>If you ordered from Amazon, please send an email to <a href="mailto:flybirdfitness@gmail.com" title="Flybird Amazon Team">flybirdfitness@gmail.com</a> with the following information:<br><br>- Your Amazon order number (starts with 'D01-' and can be found on your order confirmation email)<br><br>- Your first and last name<br><br>- Your shipping address<br><br>The replacement pin will be shipped to your address under the original shipping method (standard or expedited).</p>
<p><strong> Amazon Order Example:</strong></p>
<div style="text-align: start;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0444/1256/7702/files/Amazon_Order_File_70dcfca5-f1bd-4170-a62c-3a07ebab7c1d.png?v=1648205977" alt="Flybird Fitness Amazon Order"></div>
<p> </p>
<p>All our products come with a one-year warranty, and if your order meets the conditions, we will send a replacement pin for free. A fee will be charged if it is beyond the warranty period or purchased elsewhere.</p>
<p>Hopefully, this will make getting a new pin much easier. If you have any other tips or suggestions to add, please feel free to reach out and let me know. Alternately, if you have any photos or videos of your bench, I'd love to see them! You can email them directly to me at service@flybirdfitness.com</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/why-are-adjustable-dumbbells-so-expensive</id>
    <published>2022-03-23T18:55:26+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-03-23T18:57:31+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/why-are-adjustable-dumbbells-so-expensive"/>
    <title>Why are Adjustable Dumbbells so Expensive</title>
    <author>
      <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Adjustable dumbbells have been around for a long time. In fact, I believe they pretty much started the ‘fitness' craze in America. If you're not familiar with adjustable dumbbells, let me explain to you how they work and then we can dive into why these errbody-friendly tools are so expensive.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/why-are-adjustable-dumbbells-so-expensive">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>No matter what your situation is, whether you're as rich as Richie Rich or struggling to make ends meet in your one-bedroom apartment, it's nice to have equipment that can work for anyone. It's nice to be able to train with weights that you can adjust and don't need a specialized machine. This is exactly why Adjustable Dumbbells are great options for everyone.<br><br>Why are <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/dumbbells" title="Flybird adjustable dumbbells">adjustable dumbbells</a> so expensive? Don't they all do the same thing? Is one brand better than another brand? Let's take a look and see if Flybird adjustable dumbbells are right for you!<br><br>One of the most popular home gym tools in existence is the adjustable dumbbells. They are used for beginners, advanced trainers, bodybuilders, and even physical therapists. You may have asked yourself at one point or another, why adjustable dumbbells can be so expensive? There is a good reason for that. They are not cheap with a standard professional set coming in now at over 1000 dollars and a complete set of adjustable dumbbells can cost you 5000 dollars or more. Buying your own set just doesn't make sense when you can buy them for so cheap now thanks to FlyBird Adjustable Dumbbells.</p>
<h2>Adjustable Dumbbells are Ingenious</h2>
<p>Adjustable dumbbells are ingenious. They allow you to change the weight you're lifting with just a turn of a dial or a slide of a selector pin.<br><br>If you're looking to buy adjustable dumbbells — and chances are, you are — you've probably noticed that they don't come cheap. Sets of Flybird <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/products/flybird-adjustable-dumbbell-25lbs" title="FLYBIRD Adjustable Dumbbell 25 LBS">25lbs</a> adjustable dumbbells, maybe the most popular adjustable dumbbells on the market, cost $189. Other brands sets run even higher — some sell for $500 or more.</p>
<p><iframe width="1182" height="665" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/GKsHpZCpZr8" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p><br>Why do adjustable dumbbells cost so much? Why not just buy a set of fixed-weight dumbbells? The answer is simple: Adjustable dumbbells save space and time, and that's worth putting your money down for.</p>
<h2>The Design of Adjustable Dumbbells Is Expensive</h2>
<p> </p>
<p>Adjustable dumbbells are expensive because the design is expensive. There are a lot of moving parts and the need for high-quality materials and manufacturing techniques.<br><br>Adjustable dumbbells can be broken down into two basic categories:<br><br>Adjustable dumbbells that use a turn-adjustment system. These have been around for decades and are still the most popular type of adjustable dumbbell set. The weights adjust by turning a dial or some other mechanism that allows you to select which weight plates to lift. This style of adjustable dumbbell is heavy, bulky, and unsightly, but they have been around a long time so it's an easy design to manufacture with low tooling costs so they are relatively inexpensive compared to other styles of adjustable dumbbells<br><br>Adjustable dumbbells that use a selector pin style system. These have become very popular in recent years due to their compact size, simple design, and ease of use. The weights adjust by selecting a plate setting on the handle with a selector pin that only allows those weight plates to lift (like lifting only one plate on each side of the traditional dumbbell). The advantage here is that you can easily lift any weight up to your maximum weight setting in 5-pound increments with minimal effort.</p>
<p>The Flybird Adjustable Dumbbell features an easy-to-use dial system and a handle design that makes it easy to adjust your weight without taking your eyes off the mirror or pausing mid-workout.</p>
<h2> Space Saving</h2>
<p>Adjustable dumbbells are a great alternative to clunky, old-school weights. They enable you to quickly and easily change the weight being lifted without having to load and unload a barbell or switch between different sets of fixed dumbbells. Adjustable dumbbells are also convenient because they let you do a variety of different workouts — from cardio to strength training — with just one set of weights.<br><br>"They're simple, reliable, and versatile," said David Jack, director of Teamworks Fitness in Acton, Massachusetts, and creator of the Men's Health 60-Day Transformation. "You can do a lot with them."<br><br>One advantage is that adjustable dumbbells take up less space than other types of weights, making them ideal for people with limited storage areas such as apartments or dorm rooms. And because they don't have any moving parts like pulleys or levers, they're safer than machines and less likely to break down over time.</p>
<h2>It Depends on the Type of Material Used</h2>
<p>While most adjustable dumbbells offer similar uses, there are some subtle differences between them. The price of an adjustable dumbbell is determined by the type of material used, which affects the durability and weight capacity.<br><br>The price of an adjustable dumbbell is determined by the type of material used, which affects the durability and weight capacity. Here is a list of materials used to make adjustable dumbbells:<br><br>Iron: Iron is the most common material used in adjustable dumbbells because it provides a good combination of durability and weight capacity. However, iron is also heavier than other materials so some models may be too heavy if they are not designed with a handle that makes them easier to lift.<br><br>Cast Iron: Cast iron is a more durable version of iron that has been cast into molds to create shapes such as hexagonal bars or round plates with holes drilled through them for handles or weights on either side. It’s best suited for those who want something that will last longer but aren’t looking for anything too heavy-duty in terms of weight lifting capabilities.</p>
<p>Flybird adjustable dumbbells are made of cast iron but sell at the price of iron.</p>
<h2>You Get What You Pay For with Adjustable Dumbbells</h2>
<p> Overall, adjustable dumbbells are a good investment for the serious home exerciser. They're versatile and offer a wide range of weight choices to help you target different muscle groups or give yourself a total body workout. While they can be fairly expensive, for the money you get what you pay for with adjustable dumbbells—you'll feel like you have a complete gym in your home.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/how-to-assemble-the-flybird-adjustable-bench</id>
    <published>2022-03-22T16:53:24+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-03-22T16:53:25+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/how-to-assemble-the-flybird-adjustable-bench"/>
    <title>How To Assemble the Flybird Adjustable Weight Bench</title>
    <author>
      <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Now that you've purchased the Flybird Weight Bench, it's time to start using it and building those muscles! I'll show you how to put it together and you'll be bench pressing in no time.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/how-to-assemble-the-flybird-adjustable-bench">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>You’ve finally arrived to buy your Flybird adjustable bench. You’re eager to get home as soon as possible and start exercising with it! But before you can do that, there is one last thing you have to do — assemble it. Worse yet, there are several different pieces (yes, several!) that need to be assembled.</p>
<p>Anyone can say that the product is good, and anyone can also say Flybird weight bench is also good. But we know that the goods are good as long as they are not used, but if they can be used for a long time, it can prove to be a very good one. Don't worry, the above are some wrong descriptions. In fact, the Flyird weight bench can be said to be ready to use out of the box, if you don't believe it, read on.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2></h2>
<p>The Flybird Adjustable Bench is one of the most popular fitness benches in the world. Out of six different current Flybird benches, three of them can be adjusted (the other three are fixed models), each having its own unique features. Now, do you know how to assemble these adjustable models? This guide will demonstrate how to assemble each Flybird dumbbell bench step-by-step, thus making it easier for you to assemble the adjustable benches correctly.</p>
<h2>Flybird Adjustable Workout Bench FB149</h2>
<p>This bench is very easy to set up. <br> <br>It won't even take you five minutes and you don't need the instructions at all in order to take it out of the box and get it ready to go. It's pretty self-explanatory, but all you need to do is take the foot support out as well as the entire rest of the product, and you basically just unfold it, set it to the height that you want to be, install that little foot support, and you're good to go.<br> <br>There is one more little piece thatFlybird gives you that you put into the back of the bench in order to provide more support for the bench. <br><br>Overall, when doing things with dumbbells without them, you might not have the structural integrity.<br><br>So I do recommend putting this pin in to ensure that the bench is properly supported.</p>
<p>  </p>
<p><iframe width="978" height="550" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/8BgNgT1QvZc" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p> </p>
<h2> Flybird Adjustable Weight Bench FB139</h2>
<p>So just like the Flybird weight bench FB149, FB139 comes nearly complete right out of the box. You kind of just pick it up and spread out the adjustable bench and then you can kind of set the heights as you need to.<br><br>And there's not much else you need to do besides adding things like ankle supports and maybe a few other nuts and bolts here and there.<br><br> <br><br> <br>In total, it will take you seven minutes to do this. You don't really go for speed on setting it up. Just kind of take it out of the box, take out all the packaging, put on that ankle support, and really from there you're good to go.<br><br> <br><br>There are no real other things you need to put on. You can take out the other pins that they have.<br><br>But just so you know, you really have everything you need. There's not much you have to do in terms of setting it up. It will take you again a little over seven minutes to go from box to completed product.</p>
<p> <iframe width="978" height="550" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/bjSQydWgc00" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<h2>Flybird Adjustable Weight Bench with Waist Pad</h2>
<p> This bench has a waist pad that helps prevent back injuries while working out. Finish the assembly and set up of Flybird Adjustable Weight Bench with Waist Pad. It will be simple and easy to do, everything was very well labeled.</p>
<p> </p>
<div style="text-align: start;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0444/1256/7702/files/Weight_Bench_with_Waist_Pad_100_6b369613-9fce-4cfe-a236-e8a59dc21b32_480x480.jpg?v=1647938027" alt="Flybird Weight bench with waist pad" style="margin-right: 156px; margin-left: 156px; float: none;"></div>
<p>The assembly process of this dumbbell bench is the same as that of the FB139. You just need to take all the accessories, insert the bolt, then install the foot support and you are ready to go.</p>
<h2>Flybird Adjustable Weight Bench FB299</h2>
<p> The Flybird Adjustable Weight Bench FB299 is a great all-around bench for home use. It's well built, comfortable, and it can take a beating.<br><br>The bench also has a lot of versatility, with eight different backrest positions and three seat positions. This makes it very easy to adjust the angle of the bench to target specific muscle groups and get the best out of your workouts.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0444/1256/7702/files/Flybird_adjustable_workout_bench_FB299_8af70eb9-cd8f-4d1e-9089-9fbcaf2e28da.jpg?v=1647938628" alt="Flybird Adjustable Weight Bench FB299"></p>
<p><br><br>1)Take out all of the parts from the box.<br><br>2)The assemble the back rest to the main frame, align the holes and insert the bolt.<br><br>3)Attach four legs to the main frame using a wrench to lock bolts.<br><br>4)Then take out four wheels and put them into each corner of the bench.<br><br>5)Finally, stand up Flybird bench and adjust it to proper angle.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>We are confident that you will find the assembly of your new Flybird Adjustable Bench both easy and enjoyable. <br><br>We've broken the assembly down into four simple steps that should make the process easier to understand. If you have any questions after following these steps, feel free to contact us. We'll be happy to help you out!</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/12-dos-and-donts-for-a-successful-flybird-adjustable-bench</id>
    <published>2022-03-21T19:54:50+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-03-21T19:54:50+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/12-dos-and-donts-for-a-successful-flybird-adjustable-bench"/>
    <title>12 Tips for a Successful Flybird Adjustable Bench</title>
    <author>
      <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Since Flybird Fitness Bench has been on the market, shoppers can get a new and better experience while they do some physical therapy at home and even save money too.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/12-dos-and-donts-for-a-successful-flybird-adjustable-bench">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>If you're thinking about getting your own Flybird Adjustable Bench, then here are some dos and don'ts to help you get the most out of your purchase. The Flybird Adjustable Bench provides quality and comfort at an affordable price, and this <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/weight-benches" title="Flybird adjutable weight bench">Flybird workout bench </a>can be used in gyms, homes, and offices, as well as outside on the patio or deck. But if you don't take into account these dos and don'ts when installing or using your bench, you might not be getting the most out of your investment. Here are 12 dos and don'ts for a successful Flybird weight bench.</p>
<h2>1. Follow the Manufacturer's Installation Instructions</h2>
<p><br><br>Every weight bench for sale should have thorough installation instructions that include every possible precaution, hardware needed, and illustrated steps. As with any project, if you don't understand something or if there is something missing from your manufacturer's instructions-call them! <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/pages/contact-us" title="Contact Flybrid Fitness">Flybird's customer service</a> is top notch and will ensure that you are well-informed for a successful installation.</p>
<p>If at all possible, get in touch with someone who has recently installed one of these benches; they will be your best resource for tips and tricks for DIY projects. A little advice from an expert can go a long way! You need to carefully consider space requirements before buying an adjustable workout bench because most weight lifting benches take up a significant amount of floor space (typically between 3 and 5 feet wide). </p>
<h2>2. Choose an Adjustable Bench in a Neutral Color</h2>
<p><br><br>While many companies sell outdoor benches in vibrant, bold colors that are sure to fit into any space, it's best to choose an adjustable bench in a neutral color such as gray or black. Neutral colors blend seamlessly with existing outdoor furnishings and decor.</p>
<h2>3. Choose an Adjustable Bench with Non-Slip Foot</h2>
<p><br><br>Most benches have non-slip padding to help keep you steady while doing your exercises. It is important that your bench has non-slip arm grips because it will keep you steady. However, with non-slip foot, you don't have to worry about slippage or sliding as you are working out. <br> <br>If you buy an adjustable bench without non-slip foot, then every time your grip slips during a workout, it can be dangerous. When choosing an adjustable weight bench, make sure it has non-slip foot caps so that you can focus on your exercise, instead of worrying about falling off or slipping off.</p>
<h2>4. Choose an Adjustable Gym Bench with Multiple Settings</h2>
<p><br><br>The single most important factor to consider when choosing an adjustable bench is how many positions it can be set at. While there are benches that provide between five and ten settings, we recommend only those that offer between eight and twelve. <br> <br>This range provides you with enough options to give your entire body a thorough workout while still letting you select height settings appropriate for each exercise. It also gives you options when two or more people work out on the same bench at once.</p>
<h2>5. Setup Before Workout</h2>
<p><br>Prepare before you begin your workout. Adjust the bench to a comfortable position. Keep your feet flat on the floor, with knees at 90 degrees. Use good form and focus on strength during each set of repetitions. Push yourself and work hard. Use a spotter when necessary for safety and heavier weights.</p>
<h2>
<br>6. DON'T Expect Perfection on Your First Try</h2>
<p><br>One of Flybird bench's most convenient features is its ability to be easily adjusted. Be sure to allow enough time for fine-tuning during installation. You may have to make a few adjustments before you find a comfortable setting, but with patience, you'll find it! Fidgeting with your position on an adjustable bench can help reduce fatigue, improve focus and increase productivity. <br><br>Everyone will sit differently, so we encourage everyone to experiment until they find their preferred seating style! We love that Flybird Adjustable Benches are extremely adaptable-the possibilities are endless!</p>
<h2>7. Try Different Locations</h2>
<p><br><br>To get the most out of your workouts, it is important to vary your exercises. Try different locations and angles to target your muscles from different angles and make sure you're working for all muscle groups.<br><br>The Flybird Adjustable Bench can be used for both upper and lower body exercises. You can change positions on the bench to do different exercises for different parts of your body<br><br>Keep in mind that if you want to do high-intensity exercises, such as high-intensity interval training (HIIT), then you will need a good level of fitness. If you are just starting out with exercise or are not very fit, then HIIT may not be an option for you.</p>
<h2>8. Track Your Progress</h2>
<p><br>One of the best ways to stay motivated is by tracking how far you have come. This will lead you to realize how much progress you have made and give you the fuel you need to keep pushing yourself further!<br><br>Doing these three things will help keep your workouts interesting so they don't become boring over time!</p>
<h2>9. Try New Exercises</h2>
<p><br>You can also fight boredom by doing different exercises with your Flybird adjustable bench. You can look up exercise videos on Youtube or refer to the exercise chart that came with your Flybird adjustable bench. These exercises will help you target different muscle groups which will, in turn, lead to better results overall.</p>
<h2>10. Be Sure to Pick the Right Bench Height</h2>
<p><br><br>This is especially important if you're short or tall, but regardless of your height, the bench needs to be high enough to avoid any chance of hitting the ground with your butt on an exercise like a bench press or squat. If you're doing an overhead press, however, the bench should be at a height that allows you to easily lift the weight over your head without having to reach up high.</p>
<h2>11. Pick a Weight that's Challenging but Manageable</h2>
<p><br>It's tempting to try to lift too much weight at first, especially when you're new to strength training or when people are watching you in the gym. But picking a weight that's too heavy is almost worse than not lifting anything at all; it'll inhibit the formation of muscle fibres and increase your injury risk. Start light, then work your way up over time as you get stronger and more comfortable with each exercise movement pattern.</p>
<h2>12.Choose Flybird Adjustable Dumbbells</h2>
<p><br>Flybird adjustable dumbbells are a great investment for your home gym. They take up very little space but can offer you a full range of dumbbell weight options. You can quickly switch things up between exercises and sets by adjusting the weight on each side.<br><br>Flybird <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/dumbbells" title="Flybird adjustable dumbbells">adjustable dumbbells</a> are sold in pairs and can go up to a 55-pound weight on each side. That's roughly equivalent to <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/products/flybird-adjustable-dumbbell-25lbs" title="Flybrid 25lb adjustable dumbells">25lb </a>or <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/products/flybird-55lbs-adjustable-dumbbell" title="Flybird 55lb adjustable dumbbells">55lb</a> on each side. The Flybird bench is made out of high quality steel and plastic. The steel parts are painted black while the plastic parts are gray.<br><br>The weights adjust in 5-pound increments which is a good amount of weight to add at a time. You can increase the weight in one set and decrease it in the next set if you need to, without having to remove any weights from the dumbbells.<br><br>The weights are made of iron with a semi-gloss finish, so they look quite nice. The handles have four slots for the weights so they can fit properly into place when setting them up, which ensures that the weights don't slide around during use.<br><br>You simply twist the handle to adjust the weight, which is easy enough to do without any help from others.</p>
<h2>Final Thoughts</h2>
<p><br>The health benefits associated with bench press are undeniable. And if you are looking for one that not only comes with multiple setting options but also provides a solid build, you'll need to take your time when making your choice. All our recommended models offer different weight capacities, adjustability settings and other beneficial characteristics. So now it's up to you to find out which one will work best for your specific needs.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/8-reason-why-we-love-flybird-adjustable-dumbbell-and-you-too-should</id>
    <published>2022-03-20T01:22:30+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-03-22T17:41:47+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/8-reason-why-we-love-flybird-adjustable-dumbbell-and-you-too-should"/>
    <title>8 Reasons Why We Love Flybird Adjustable Dumbbell</title>
    <author>
      <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[FlyBird Adjustable Dumbbell is perfect for you to enhance your strength training. Whether you are a beginner or workout enthusiast, you will find these dumbbells to be what you need in the daily workouts.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/8-reason-why-we-love-flybird-adjustable-dumbbell-and-you-too-should">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>The Flybird Adjustable Dumbbell is a functional and effective piece of equipment that's small enough to fit in any home gym. It's easy to use, easy to store, and great for a wide range of exercises.<br><br><br>Here are eight reasons why we love the <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/dumbbells" title="Flybird Adjustable Dumbbell">Flybird Adjustable Dumbbell</a> (and we think you should, too!).</p>
<h2>1. It Has 5 Weight Settings with a Single Dial</h2>
<p><br><br>Changing weights on the dumbbell is as simple as turning a dial, which makes it easy for people who want to switch up their workouts or are sharing the equipment with a partner or group.<br><br><br>The dial can be used to choose from 5 weight settings of 5, 5, 10, 15, 20, 25 lb per hand in 10-lb increments.<br><br><br>It's easy to use, you just turn the dial on the end of each dumbbell handle to choose the amount of weight you want from 5 to 50 pounds in 5-pound increments. Therefore, most gym enthusiasts consider <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/products/flybird-adjustable-dumbbell-25lbs" title="FLYBIRD Adjustable Dumbbell 25 LBS">25lbs dumbbells</a>, <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/products/flybird-55lbs-adjustable-dumbbells-pair" title="Flybird 55 lb Adjustable Dumbbells">55 lb dumbbells</a>, <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/weight-benches" title="Flybird weight bench">Flybird bench</a> and dumbbells set.</p>
<h2>2. They Feature Adjustable Systems</h2>
<p><br><br>The Flybird Adjustable Dumbbell is one of the best-selling products on the market, and there's a reason why: they're hands-down the easiest dumbbells to use. They feature a quick-change weight adjustment system that makes it easy to switch between weights fast and with just one hand!<br>This allows you to focus on your workout and not fiddle around with weights. With just one dumbbell, you can do any weight training exercise, rather than having to buy tons of different weights for your home gym.</p>
<h2>3. They're Small and Easy to Store</h2>
<p><br><br>If you're looking for an easy way to store these dumbbells, look no further: they've got you covered. These dumbbells come with a tray that makes them easy to stack, so you don't have to worry about them taking up too much space in your home gym or workout room.</p>
<p>They're fit well in small spaces. If you live in an apartment or a small home, you probably don't have space to dedicate to a set of dumbbells. Dumbbells take up a lot of room, especially if you start getting into heavier weights. But Flybird adjustable dumbbells are compact and can easily fit into even the smallest of spaces.<br><br><br>The Flybird Adjustable Dumbbell not only saves you money but also allows you to get in shape at home with minimal equipment needed! All this can be critical to being environmentally friendly and saving space!</p>
<h2>4. They're Made from Durable Cast Iron</h2>
<p><br><br>Another huge benefit of the Flybird Adjustable Dumbbell is that it's made from durable cast iron, which means it will last for years and years without chipping or cracking. No matter how many times you drop this baby on the floor when you're doing squats or deadlifts, it'll keep coming back for more!<br><br><br>When buying this product, you'll want to know whether or not it has been designed to last for a very long time. Many people buy this type of product because they think that it will last for years but the truth is that there are many types of products on the market today that do not last for very long. Flybird adjustable dumbbells are made with high-quality materials so they will be able to last for a very long time without breaking down or wearing out.</p>
<h2>5. Anti-Roll Design</h2>
<p><br><br>One of the problems with most adjustable dumbbells is that they are prone to rolling around when they aren't in use. This can be frustrating and annoying, especially if you want to leave them out in plain sight. Flybird has addressed this problem by giving their weights an anti-roll design that prevents them from sliding off your desk or table when they aren't in use.</p>
<h2>6. They Allow You to Lift Heavier Than Traditional Dumbbells</h2>
<p><br><br>Traditional dumbbells only go up to 20 lbs and that's only if you get the heaviest ones. With Flybird adjustable dumbbells, though, you can lift as much as <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/products/flybird-55lbs-adjustable-dumbbell" title="Flybird 55 lb adjustable dumbbells">50 lbs</a>! That's 2.5 times as much as traditional dumbbells! If you want to increase your muscle mass and strength, lifting heavier is a must.<br><br></p>
<h2>7. They Don't Need You to Have Another Equipment</h2>
<p><br><br>With traditional dumbbells, you need several pairs of different weights so that you can rotate through them during your workout. And those pairs take up valuable space in your home! Flybird adjustable dumbbells are perfect for any home gym because they don't require additional equipment or storage space-just use the easy-to-use dial to switch.<br><br><br>When you have this equipment, you'll get a total-body workout with this one piece of equipment, it's perfect for strength training, building muscle, toning, and sculpting your arms, chest, back, shoulders, legs, and core.</p>
<h2>8. They're Comfortable</h2>
<p><br><br>The handle of the Flybird Adjustable Dumbbell is very comfortable, feels great in your hands, and just gives you a smooth workout experience. It is much better than other adjustable dumbbells because the handles are not too small or too big but they are just made to feel comfortable in your hands which is what everybody wants from a dumbbell.<br><br><br>It doesn't make you feel like you're holding something heavy but instead, it just feels like you're lifting something that's as light as air and gives a comfortable workout experience.<br><br><br>To ensure maximum comfort, these adjustable dumbbells come with anti-rolling plates so they won't roll away when you put them down on the floor after your workout - they stay in place until you pick them up again next time you exercise or need extra weight for doing chores around the house or yard work.</p>
<h2>Final Words</h2>
<p><br><br>FlyBird Adjustable Dumbbell is very easy to use, attractive look, convenient to carry and has a variety of models. If you are looking for an adjustable dumbbell that is easy to use, portable and fashionable then you should buy Flybird Adjustable Dumbbell.<br><br><br>This can help you increase the strength of the body to prevent muscle degeneration. There are many types of adjustable dumbbells in the market, but my personal favorite is Flybird Adjustable Dumbbell. It has a lot of benefits when compared to other normal dumbbells.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/how-to-position-flybird-bench-for-different-movement</id>
    <published>2022-03-16T00:53:02+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-03-23T14:23:08+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/how-to-position-flybird-bench-for-different-movement"/>
    <title>How to Position Flybird Bench for Different Movement</title>
    <author>
      <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[With Flybird Bench we want to share with you the way to position your bench for different movement. The adjustment is suitable for all your body types and makes your bench a truly custom piece of workout equipment.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/how-to-position-flybird-bench-for-different-movement">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Flybird adjustable benches are designed to cater to people with different fitness needs. To get the most benefits from your workout, you can adjust a Flybird bench to different positions. Whenever you want to build muscles on your chest, shoulders, arms, triceps, back, or abs, you need to make sure the bench is in the right position. Flybird benches usually offer three different positions: flat, incline, and decline. Depending on your needs, you can adjust the positions for different movements.</p>
<p>Recently, many people have been asking about how to adjust the Flybird bench positions since it comes with multiple pre-positioned holes for multiple leg positions. We have received a lot of feedback from our customers about their beautiful Flybird bench and how to do different kinds of movements. This article will provide an in-depth guide, step by step, on how to set up Flybird benches.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Flybird Adjustable Workout Bench FB149</h2>
<p>The Flybird <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/products/flybird-adjustable-workout-bench" title="Flybird adjustable weight bench FB149">FB149</a> weight bench is a versatile adjustable weight bench that allows you to perform a variety of exercises, including flat bench press, incline bench press, and military press. The Flybird Weight Bench Adjustable can be assembled in either flat or incline positions. There are seven adjustment angles (0°, -10°, -35°, 23°, 37°, 51°, 85°) for the back pad and three adjustment angles (0°, 12°, 13° ) for the seat.</p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0444/1256/7702/files/FLYBIRD_Adjustable_Workout_Bench_FB149_16_a824c63c-9075-4c74-acaf-8a22ab808f82_480x480.jpg?v=1647847461" alt="Flybird Adjustable weight bench FB149" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<p>To adjust the backrest, you need to pull the safety pin, then move the backrest to the position you want and lock it in place by inserting the pin into one of the holes on the horizontal bar.<br><br>To adjust the seat, you need to pull the safety pin, then move the seat to the position you want and lock it in place by inserting the pin into one of the holes on the vertical bar.</p>
<p> <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Im1uiA3KvLA" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<h2>Flybird AdjutableWeight Bench FB139</h2>
<p> The Flybird Weight Bench <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/products/flybird-adjustable-weight-bench" title="Flybird Adjustable Workout Bench FB139">FB139</a> can be adjusted to six different positions, from flat to an incline of 76degrees. The bench features comfortable high-density foam padding and a durable steel frame capped with end caps. The bench is also compact, making it easy to store out of the way when not in use.<br><br>1.Place the Flybird Weight Bench on a flat, stable surface within your workout area. If you have the optional fly attachment, place this on top of the bench so it is centered on the rear edge.<br><br>2.Grasp the backrest in both hands and slide it up or down so that it locks into position at one of six settings as indicated by a numbered hole in the backrest and corresponding hole in the frame. For example, setting 2 is approximately 20 degrees from vertical and setting 6 is approximately 80 degrees from vertical. A small button inside each hole must lock into place for the backrest to be secure at that position.<br><br>3.Move the seat section if necessary by grasping the seat in both hands and sliding it up or down so that it locks into position at one of five settings as indicated by a numbered hole in the seat and corresponding hole in the frame. A small button inside each hole must lock into place for safety.</p>
<p> </p>
<div style="padding: 75% 0 0 0; position: relative;"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/688437873?h=527b914819&amp;badge=0&amp;autopause=0&amp;player_id=0&amp;app_id=58479" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen="" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%;" title="FB139 adjustable.mp4"></iframe></div>
<script src="https://player.vimeo.com/api/player.js"></script>
<h2> Flybird Adjustable Weight Bench with Waist Pad</h2>
<p> </p>
<p> The <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/products/flybird-adjustable-weight-bench-with-waist-pad" title="Flybird adjustable weight bench with waist pad">Flybird Adjustable Weight Bench with Waist Pad</a> is one of the most popular weight benches on the market. It's highly rated, inexpensive, and ships free.<br><br>The bench is adjustable to several different positions including flat, incline, and decline. The seat is also adjustable to several different positions.<br><br>To change the position of the bench, first start with it in the flat position. Then find two locking pins that secure the bench to the frame. These can be found underneath each side of the seat where it meets the frame. The part that is inserted into the hole is a half-inch round pin with a knob on top.<br><br>Pull out each pin to release the seat from its current position. Slide it up or down to raise or lower it and then reinsert each pin back into place to lock it into its new position.</p>
<div style="text-align: left;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0444/1256/7702/files/Flybird_waist_pad_adjustment_480x480.png?v=1647362797" alt="Flybird weight bench with waist pad" style="float: none;"></div>
<h2>Flybird Adjutable Weight Bench FB299</h2>
<p>Flybird Adjustable Weight Bench <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/products/flybird-adjustable-weight-bench-fb299" title="Flybird versatile bench FB299">FB299</a> is a multi-functional adjustable bench, which can be used in full body exercises. </p>
<p> This is a typical pin pulling adjustment system and it works really well.<br><br>You get eight different backrest positions going from decline to fully upright at 90 degrees.<br><br>And the seat pad itself has three different adjustable positions.<br><br>There is also a foot rest which comes in handy for decline exercises, and it has three height adjustments.</p>
<p><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/J-KmX9Awjl0" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/how-much-protein-do-you-actually-need</id>
    <published>2022-03-09T18:00:01+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-03-22T15:30:59+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/how-much-protein-do-you-actually-need"/>
    <title>How Much Protein Do You Actually Need</title>
    <author>
      <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Protein is an incredibly important part of any diet - but how much exactly do you actually need? The answer to that question might surprise you.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/how-much-protein-do-you-actually-need">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Protein is essential to health. The word comes from the Greek protos, meaning "first," and its origin reflects the supremacy of protein in human nutrition. You need it to grow flesh on your bones, make hair, blood, connective tissue, antibodies, enzymes, and more. It's common for athletes and bodybuilders to consume large amounts of extra protein to build up their physiques. But the message the rest of us often get is that we are consuming too much protein each day.<br><br>The Recommended Dietary Allowance (RDA) for protein is a modest 0.8 grams of protein per kilogram of body weight.The RDA is the amount of a nutrient you need to meet your basic nutritional needs. In a sense, this is the minimum amount you need to avoid getting sick, not the specific amount you should eat each day.<br><br>To determine your daily protein intake, you can multiply your weight by 0.36 pounds or use this online protein calculator. For a 50-year-old woman who weighs 140 pounds and is sedentary (not exercising), that equates to 53 grams of protein per day.<br><br>But using the RDA to determine how much protein you need each day actually causes a lot of confusion. Nancy Rodriguez, a registered dietitian and professor of nutritional sciences at the University of Connecticut in Storrs, says: "There are misconceptions about the RDA not only among the public, but in our profession as well." "People usually think we all eat too much protein."<br><br>Rodriguez was one of more than 40 nutritionists who gathered in Washington, D.C., for the Protein Summit to discuss research on protein and human health. The summit was organized and sponsored by the beef, egg, and other animal-based food industry groups, but it also produced a set of scientific reports that were independently published in a special supplement to the June issue of the American Journal of Clinical Nutrition (AJCN).</p>
<h2>
<br>Protein: The more the merrier?</h2>
<p><br>For a relatively active adult, daily protein intake to meet the RDA requirement provides only 10% of his or her total daily calories. In contrast, the average American consumes 16% of his or her daily calories in the form of protein, which comes from both plant and animal sources.<br><br>The Protein Summit on AJCN reports that 16.6 percent is definitely not an excess. In fact, the report suggests that Americans may be consuming too little protein, not too much. These researchers believe that the potential benefits of a higher daily protein intake include maintaining muscle strength in the face of aging and maintaining a lean, fat-burning physique. Some of the studies described in the Summit report suggest that protein is more effectively consumed at regular meals and snacks throughout the day than when many Americans wolf it down at dinner.<br><br>Based on all of the research presented at the summit, Rodriguez estimated that consuming more than twice the RDA for protein "is a safe and appropriate target range." This amounts to about 15 to 25% of your total daily caloric intake, though it may be higher or lower depending on your age, gender, and level of exercise.<br><br>Over the past few years, however, the public health message has shifted from the desired percentages of protein, fat, and carbohydrates. For example, current dietary guidelines for Americans emphasize the importance of eating healthy protein-rich foods rather than focusing on a specific daily protein content.</p>
<h2>
<br>What should you do?</h2>
<p><br>Research on how much protein to eat to stay healthy is ongoing and far from certain. For example, the value of a high-protein diet for weight loss or cardiovascular health remains controversial.<br><br>Before you start increasing your daily protein intake, there are a few important things to consider. First, don't read "get more protein" as "eat more meat." Beef, poultry, and pork (as well as milk, cheese, and eggs) certainly provide high-quality protein, but so do many plant-based foods, including whole grains, beans, and other legumes, nuts, and vegetables. The table below provides some of the healthier sources of protein.<br><br>It is also important to consider the "mix" of protein—the fats, carbohydrates, vitamins, minerals, and other nutrients that always come together with protein. Aim for a protein source that is low in saturated fat and processed carbohydrates and rich in multiple nutrients.<br><br>One more thing: If you add protein, dietary calculations require you to eat less of something else to keep your daily calorie intake steady. The changes you make can affect your nutrition, for better or worse. For example, eating more protein instead of low-quality refined carbohydrates, such as white bread and candy, is a healthy choice, although the healthiness of the choice also depends on the total amount of protein.<br><br>Kathy McManus, registered dietitian and director of nutrition at Harvard-affiliated Brigham and Women's Hospital, says: "If you're not eating a lot of fish, but you want to increase your fish intake, yes, that may improve your overall nutrition and, in turn, your health." "I think the data argues against a significant increase in red meat and processed meat to get protein."<br><br>If your main concern is weight loss, it makes sense to try a high-protein diet, but don't expect it to be a cure-all. Patients come to me all the time and ask me if consuming more protein will help them lose weight. I tell them that the verdict is still out. Some studies support it, some don't. "</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Good sources of protein</h2>
Food Protein (Grams)<br><br>3 ounces of cod or trout, 21 grams.<br><br>19 grams cooked turkey or chicken, 3 oz.<br><br>6 ounces Greek yogurt, plain17 grams.<br><br>12 cup shredded white cheese14 grams<br><br>8 g cooked beans, half a cup<br><br>8 g milk, 1 cup<br><br>8 gram cooked Italian pasta<br><br>1/4 cup nuts (mixed)7 grams<br><br>6 g from one egg
<div style="text-align: start;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0444/1256/7702/files/Cream__Pink__and_Yellow_Simple_Weekly_Menu.png?v=1647934234" alt="Weekly Menu" style="margin-right: 81.5px; margin-left: 81.5px; float: none;"></div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/how-to-get-and-stay-fit-on-saint-patrick-s-day</id>
    <published>2022-03-07T17:48:41+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-03-07T17:48:41+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/how-to-get-and-stay-fit-on-saint-patrick-s-day"/>
    <title>How To Get And Stay Fit On Saint Patrick’s Day</title>
    <author>
      <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[St. Patrick’s Day is right around the corner, and we all know what that means — time to party hard. But, if you’re like me, you also don’t want to feel like a swollen, hungover mess after your night of fun! So here are some tips that will ensure you can get and stay fit on Saint Patrick’s Day.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/how-to-get-and-stay-fit-on-saint-patrick-s-day">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Let’s start this off by saying there’s no doubt about it — drinking beer is a big part of the Irish culture. While we normally think of Guinness, you don’t have to be Irish to enjoy the world’s favorite stout. However, there’s no doubt that Guinness packs a caloric punch — a pint is around 200-250 calories. When you add it up over the year, those calories can really add up and make a difference in your waistline, especially since you might be planning on drinking beer more than one day a year. The good news is that drinking beer doesn’t have to fill your gut while adding extra pounds to your waistline. Here’s my quick 4 step lesson on how to get and stay fit on Saint Patrick’s Day. All without cutting Guinness out of your diet!</p>
<h2>Eat Something Healthy Before You Go Out</h2>
<p>It’s not difficult to make healthy choices about what you eat. It is, however, difficult to get drunk and make healthy choices about what you eat. If you plan on drinking on Saint Patrick’s Day, it’s a good idea to eat something before you go out.<br><br>Before you head out for Saint Patrick's Day celebrations make sure you have a healthy meal first. Drinking on an empty stomach increases your alcohol tolerance and makes it more likely that you'll overindulge. Eating something healthy beforehand will also keep you full longer so you don't order as many drinks or snacks or get drunk as fast. It may be hard to convince yourself of this when all you want is a Guinness but eating healthy beforehand will help mitigate the effects of the day.<br><br>This is a great way to keep your blood sugar up and prevent yourself from getting too drunk too fast. It’s also beneficial because it will help you make better food choices. Instead of eating greasy foods that are horrible for your stomach, you might be more inclined to eat something like a salad or bowl of soup.</p>
<h2>Drink a Full Glass of Water Between Each Beer</h2>
<p>Drink a full glass of water between each beer or mixed drink. This is good for two reasons: First, it keeps you hydrated; second, it forces you to slow down and think about what you’re doing to yourself. Drinking water between drinks is also a good way to keep from over-imbibing when it comes time for bed.<br><br>Drink one beer or mixed drink an hour at the most, and try not to go more than three hours without having something nonalcoholic. Whatever your limit is — whether it’s one drink an hour, or once every two hours — make sure you stick to it. You can use that time between drinks to mingle, talk to people and get involved in any fun activities around you instead of just drinking yourself silly.</p>
<h2>Exercise Early In The Day And Later At Night</h2>
<p>Scheduling a workout early in the morning will help you burn off those calories before you begin to consume them. It will also give you more energy throughout your day, and make it easier to avoid poor eating choices later on.<br><br>If you can’t get your workout in early in the day, try to do it later at night. If you’re going out, once again, don’t starve yourself before going out. Just eat healthier options throughout the day and try to eat a little lighter before going out. This way when you exercise later that night, your body will be burning off the fat instead of what is stored by the food you just consumed that night.</p>
<p>If you’re still tipsy at 10 pm, do a circuit training workout with <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/weight-benches" title="Flybird adjutable weight bench">Flybird adjustable weight bench</a>.</p>
<h2>Get the Whole Family Involved</h2>
<p>Saint Patrick’s Day doesn’t have to be just about the adults. Get your kids involved with celebrating Irish culture or just making it an active day in general. If you don't want to take them out in public (and deal with all the temptations that come along with it), organize a home celebration centered on crafts, games, or other activities that don't involve food or booze.<br><br>Make it a group challenge to eat a variety of vegetables — especially green ones. You can have fun creating meals that include spinach, broccoli, kale, collard greens, and other nutritious options. Or try making a "Saint Patty's Day Salad" full of greens and topped with a dressing made of olive oil and balsamic vinegar.<br><br>Try something new. If you've never had kale chips before, now is the time to try them! They're easy to make — just bake kale at 400 degrees for 10-15 minutes until they're crispy. Then sprinkle them with a little sea salt and enjoy!<br><br>Make it social. Take advantage of the day to spend time with friends or family by taking an evening stroll together or playing an active game like touch football or Frisbee in the park.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/how-you-can-relieve-stress-with-exercise</id>
    <published>2022-03-05T20:30:00+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-03-05T20:30:00+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/how-you-can-relieve-stress-with-exercise"/>
    <title>How You Can Relieve Stress with Exercise</title>
    <author>
      <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[You may have heard that physical exercise is important for reducing stress. It's not just common sense. This claim is supported by research. In fact, studies show that exercise can be as effective at relieving stress as some anti-depressant medications.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/how-you-can-relieve-stress-with-exercise">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Stress relief is important for everyone, but it is a particular concern for those who work out and push their bodies to the limit at the gym. Excessive amounts of stress are bad for your health, but this doesn’t have to be the case. Here’s how you can relieve stress with exercise.</p>
<h2>Avoid the Gym When You are Stressed</h2>
<p>Exercising is a helpful way to feel positive, but it’s not always the most effective coping mechanism. Think about it — if you go to the gym when stressed or overwhelmed, and you exercise too much or too intensely, your body could still be in “fight-or-flight” mode when you get home. You won’t experience the feel-good endorphins that come with working out at a moderate intensity for 30 minutes or more.<br><br>Instead of spending an hour in the gym, take a brisk walk around your neighborhood or run up and down every staircase in your home for 15 minutes. These activities will help you burn off some steam without completely draining yourself. By <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/beginners-guide-to-fitness-how-to-start-working-out-1" title="Beginners' Guide to Fitness - How to Start Working Out">working out </a>at home, you can avoid this. I personally chose to use the <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/weight-benches" title="Flybird weight bench">Flybird workout bench</a> and <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/dumbbells" title="Flybird adjustable dumbbell">Flybird adjustable dumbbells</a> for extra workouts at home! Hope that helps!</p>
<h2>The Best Type of Exercise for Stress Relief</h2>
<p>Walking, running, swimming, biking, and other aerobic activities are considered effective forms of exercise for stress relief because they increase the flow of oxygen to your body.<br><br>Yoga is another great form of exercise that helps relieve stress. It combines gentle movements with deep breathing to help focus the mind and strengthen the body.<br><br><a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/getting-stronger-with-a-weight-bench-at-home" title="Getting Stronger with a Weight Bench at Home">Strength training</a> is also an effective way to reduce stress because it releases endorphins in your brain that make you feel good.</p>
<h2>The Best Time to Exercise for Stress Relief</h2>
<p>Is there a best time to exercise? Are some days better than others? Should you work out in the morning, afternoon, or evening? Here are a few things to consider:<br><br>If you are not a morning person, don't expect that you will suddenly become one just because you want to sweat it out in the morning. If you feel better working out after work, then do it! The key thing is that you do it.<br><br>Some people believe that working out in the morning is best because your body is low on fuel. Therefore, it is more likely to use fat for energy vs. carbohydrates. There may be something to this for some people, but the reality is that most of us can only get up early enough to get ready for work without having time for an effective workout. So if getting up early just isn't an option, don't beat yourself up over it; sleep in instead!<br><br>The best time to exercise for stress relief depends on your schedule and when you're most likely to stick to it. Exercising in the morning may give you a boost for the rest of the day, but maybe you don't have time before work. If so, consider exercising during lunch or after work.</p>
<h2>Do Regular Exercise </h2>
<p>Doing regular exercise even for a short time can help keep stress under control.<br><br>The reason this works is that when you are stressed your body releases cortisol, which triggers your fight-or-flight response. Exercising gives you an outlet for this energy and helps calm down your body's response to stress.<br><br>Not all stress is bad. Some is normal and even beneficial. The key is to recognize when stress has become unhealthy. Take steps to reduce stress before it affects your health and well-being if that happens.<br><br>Exercise is just one way to do that. It doesn't have to be complicated or expensive, either. The benefits of exercise come from making it a part of your routine and also focusing on intensity when you do exercise.</p>
<h2>Work Out with a Friend</h2>
<p>Working out with a friend is a great way to relieve stress. Having someone to talk to while you do your routine can make it much more enjoyable. You will feel more relaxed and comfortable going through the motions with a friend than by yourself.<br><br>Exercising with other people will also help you stay motivated and accountable. If you're trying to get fit or lose weight, knowing that people are counting on you will give you the extra push that you need to succeed.<br><br>Find an exercise buddy, set up a schedule and commit to working out together regularly.<br><br>For example, if you're running on the treadmill every day at 5 mph for an hour and not seeing any results, try bumping up the intensity by going faster or adding hills for 30 minutes instead. You'll see far better results this way than you would if you continued doing the same thing every day without changing it up at all, even though you're spending less time exercising overall.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>Above all else, staying active is the most important thing you can do to relieve stress and prevent other conditions like depression. Exercise, physical activity, and a physically active lifestyle all go hand in hand when it comes to overall health, and all things being equal you should consider increasing your activity level if you’re looking to improve your mental well-being. No matter what kind of physical activity you enjoy, or how much time or energy you have to commit, staying active is always worth the time investment while reducing stress symptoms in the process.</p>
<p> </p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/best-adjustable-benches-for-home-gym</id>
    <published>2022-03-01T15:27:41+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-03-01T15:28:56+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/best-adjustable-benches-for-home-gym"/>
    <title>Best Adjustable Bench for Home Gym</title>
    <author>
      <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[If you are looking for the best adjustable weight bench, check out the article below. This article will help you find the right adjustable weight bench for your home gym.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/best-adjustable-benches-for-home-gym">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Have you ever entered a home gym looking for a place to workout? And walked away confused because there was more than one model of adjustable benches? It’s easy to get overwhelmed when looking for the best adjustable bench for your home gym. This article will help you sink your teeth into the different features and models so you can confidently choose the best adjustable bench for your home gym.</p>
<p>If you don't know much about weight benches, the previous article <em><a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/the-complete-guide-to-weight-benches-and-their-benefits" target="_blank" title="The Complete Guide to Weight Benches and Their Benefits" rel="noopener noreferrer">The Complete Guide to Weight Benches and Their Benefits</a></em> can help you.</p>
<h2>Things to Look for When Buying an Adjustable Bench for your Home Gym</h2>
<p><br>If you want to pick the best weight bench for you, then you need to consider the following factors.</p>
<h3>Build Quality: Check the Construction</h3>
<p><span>This is by far the most important aspect of choosing a bench, particularly if you plan to use heavyweights. Some benches are built with plywood and metal coatings. Others are made of steel. If you choose a bench made of plywood instead of steel, it will be more affordable but it won't last as long. Steel is sturdier and more durable.</span></p>
<h3><span>Adjustment Options and Range of Motion</span></h3>
<p><br>A good bench should offer an adjustment range of between -20 and 80 degrees, giving you enough of a range to work with barbells, <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/dumbbells" title="Flybrid adjustable dumbbells">dumbbells</a>, and other equipment.<br><br>Once you’ve decided on the range of motion that you need, you’ll have to determine how you want it adjusted. Many benches use pins or levers to adjust the angle, while others utilize a crank system that lets you adjust on the fly.<br><br>There are pros and cons to both systems. Pins and levers tend to be simpler and cheaper, making them a good option if your budget is tight. But they aren’t as fast as cranks since you have to stop your workout so you can get off the bench and adjust the angle by hand.</p>
<h3>Maximum Capacity or Load Limit</h3>
<p>If you plan to use your adjustable weight bench for heavy lifting sessions, it is important to find one with a high maximum load or weight limit. Most benches are rated for about 250 pounds to 500 pounds, but models for semi-professional and professional use can support weights of up to 1,000 pounds.</p>
<p><br>You should also keep in mind that the maximum capacity rating applies to both the user and the amount of weight he or she is using. Therefore, if you weigh more than 250 pounds and lift 400-pound loads, you will need a bench with a minimum capacity of 650 pounds.<br><br>Lastly, if you plan to lift with a partner, you must also consider their weight when determining the maximum capacity of the bench.</p>
<h3>Compactness and Portability</h3>
<p><br>First things first, adjustability is the key here. Adjustable benches are available in a variety of options such as seat (flat, incline or decline), backrest (flat, incline or decline) as well as the number of positions. The more the options, the better it is for your workout.<br><br>If you are looking for the best adjustable bench for home gym, you should go for the one that is very compact in size and highly portable.<br><br>This will ensure that you can easily carry it from one place to another and that it doesn't take up much space in your home gym.</p>
<h3>Comfort and Ergonomics</h3>
<p><br>When you're choosing a bench for home use, it's important to consider comfort and ergonomics. You may be using it for shorter periods of time, but if the bench you choose isn't comfortable or feels too flimsy, it may not motivate you to keep up with your workouts.<br><br>Choose a bench that has enough padding to make your workout comfortable. Some benches have only one inch of padding and others have two or more inches of high-density foam padding. The thicker the padding, the more likely the bench will remain comfortable for a longer period of time. The thickest padding is usually found in commercial benches designed for gyms as opposed to home use, but you can still find a thick-padded bench for personal use.<br><br>Select a bench that has an angled back and seat that allow you to sit upright with your back straight during your workout. Look for a bench that has an angle between 45 and 65 degrees; this angle helps support your body during certain exercises and ensures your weight is evenly distributed over the entire surface of the bench. Choose a bench that has at least one leg extension, which offers added stability during exercises like squats or when lifting heavy weights.</p>
<h3>Warranty and Customer Support</h3>
<p>Even the best adjustable bench can break down over time. If there’s a manufacturer’s defect, you should be able to return or exchange the bench for a new one.</p>
<p><br>Some companies will let you return the bench for any reason, but others won’t. Make sure you understand their <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/pages/refund-return-policy" target="_blank" title="Flybird Fitness Return Policy" rel="noopener noreferrer">return policy</a> so you don’t waste your money on an adjustable bench that doesn’t work out.<br><br>It also pays to see if they have good customer support. See if they have a phone number and email address where you can reach them to ask questions or get help with problems.</p>
<h2>Best Adjustable Bench for Home Gym</h2>
<p>Most homeowners have limited space to work out at home, and usually the first things they get rid of are their bulky gym equipment. Getting rid of a bulky abdominal bench and buying an adjustable bench is a great way to save space and money when building your home gym.</p>
<p>Flybrid Adjustable Bench is one of the best exercise benches you can get if you are on the lookout for a top quality and reliable adjustable bench. The design, the sturdiness and the other features that this adjustable bench is made with make it stand out in such congested market.</p>
<p>There are currently six different workout benches available at <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/" title="Flybird Fitness website">Flybird Fitness</a>. You can <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/compare-flybird-weight-benches" title="Compare Flybird weight benches">compare all Flybird weight bench models</a> to find the one that works best for you.</p>
<h3>Flybird Adjustable Weight Bench FB149</h3>
<div style="text-align: start;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0444/1256/7702/files/Flybird-Adjustable-Workout-Bench_600x600.jpg?v=1645875777" alt="Flybird adjustable workout bench FB149" style="float: none;" width="600x600" height="600x600"></div>
<div style="text-align: start;">Flybird FB149 is a best-seller adjustable bench with a few extra features to make it great for home weight training and a must-have on your gym essentials list.</div>
<br>
<h4 style="text-align: start;">Features:</h4>
<h5 style="text-align: start;">Full Body Workout</h5>
<div style="text-align: start;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0444/1256/7702/files/03_480x480.png?v=1618570187" alt="Full Body Workout " width="480x480" height="480x480" style="float: none;"></div>
<div style="text-align: start;">With 7 baskrest positions, 3 seat positions, and 2 footpads, you can exercise your entire body! Suitable for up to 10 different exercises.</div>
<br>
<h5 style="text-align: start;">Save 80% Space</h5>
<div style="text-align: start;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0444/1256/7702/files/Flybird_Bench_FB149_save_more_place.png?v=1645876308" alt="Flybird bench save place"></div>
<div style="text-align: start;">Flybird Adjustable Bench FB149 will help you save 80% more space in your training room than a normal weight bench. You can put it in the corner or under the Sofa/Bed.</div>
<br>
<h4 style="text-align: start;">Materials</h4>
<ul>
<li>Frame: Heavy duty commercial quality steel</li>
<li>Backrest Cushion: 2 inches thick, soft foam cushion, covered in layer of PVC leather</li>
<li>Adjust the place with an automatic lock</li>
</ul>
<h4>Product Specification</h4>
<p> </p>
<style type="text/css"><!--
.tg  {border-collapse:collapse;border-spacing:0;}
.tg td{border-color:black;border-style:solid;border-width:1px;font-family:Arial, sans-serif;font-size:14px;
  overflow:hidden;padding:10px 5px;word-break:normal;}
.tg th{border-color:black;border-style:solid;border-width:1px;font-family:Arial, sans-serif;font-size:14px;
  font-weight:normal;overflow:hidden;padding:10px 5px;word-break:normal;}
.tg .tg-zowd{background-color:#FFF;border-color:inherit;color:#1A1B18;text-align:center;vertical-align:middle}
--></style>
<div style="text-align: start;">
<div style="text-align: start;">
<div style="text-align: start;">
<table class="tg">
<thead>
<tr>
<th class="tg-zowd"><strong>Regular Dimensions (L x W x H)</strong></th>
<th class="tg-zowd">49.2 X 15.7 X 21 (Inches)</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Folded Size (L x W x H)</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">30 X 16 X 9 (Inches)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Back Positions</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">7</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Back Options</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">23°, 37°, 51°, 85°, flat, -10°, -35°</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Seat Positions</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Seat Options</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">flat, 12°, 23°</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Backrest Length</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">31 inch / 79 cm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Weight Capacity</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">700 lb / 318 kg</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Suitable for User's Height</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">6'2'' / 188 cm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Product Weight</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">28.5 lbs / 12.9 kg</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p> </p>
<h4>Review</h4>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0444/1256/7702/files/FLYBIRD_Adjustable_Workout_Bench_FB149_3_a4b45467-debf-4371-991e-3b20c282e40a_480x480.jpg?v=1646049445" alt="Flybird adjustable dumbbell bench FB149" width="480x480" height="480x480" style="float: none; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Great combination of Price, Size and Sturdiness. I like how both the bench and seat can be inclined, with a nice little foot rest to keep stationary. It folds up when not using it as well. Good bench, peeps!   --- Greg T</p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong><a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/products/flybird-adjustable-workout-bench" title="Flybird adjustable workout bench FB149">Learn more about Flybird adjustable weight bench FB149</a></strong></p>
<p> </p>
<h3>Flybird Adjustable Weight Bench FB139</h3>
<p> </p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0444/1256/7702/files/Flybird_adjustable_bench_FB139_600x600.jpg?v=1645877409" alt="Flybird adjustable workout bench FB139"></p>
<p>Flybird Adjustable Weight Bench FB139 is perfect to get in a high-quality gym workout at home. It can be used to target multiple muscle groups for a full-body workout.</p>
<h4>Features:</h4>
<h5>Unique Triangle Structure</h5>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopifycdn.net/s/files/1/0444/1256/7702/files/Flybird_adjustable_bench_FB139_2_600x600.png?v=1645877867" alt="Flybird adjustable bench FB139" style="float: none;"></p>
<p>Take a new look at your fitness! FB139 comes with an innovative triangle-shaped design that is perfect for abs, back, chest and arms. The sturdy design supports a maximum weight capacity of 600 pounds. Get a professional workout environment right at home!</p>
<h5>Adjustment in a Simple Way</h5>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopifycdn.net/s/files/1/0444/1256/7702/files/Flybird_adjustable_bench_FB139_3_600x600.png?v=1645878043" alt="Flybird adjustable bench FB139"></p>
<p>With 6 back positions and 4 seat positions, you can work your whole body, just pull the support bar, adjust it to fit yourself, and you are done! </p>
<h4>Materials</h4>
<ul>
<li>Frame: 1.5 mm thicken heavy-duty commercial quality steel pipe</li>
<li>Backrest Cushion: 1.8" thick soft foam, covered in layer of PVC leather</li>
<li>Four anti-skid rubber feet</li>
</ul>
<h4><span>Product Specification</span></h4>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<style type="text/css"><!--
.tg  {border-collapse:collapse;border-spacing:0;}
.tg td{border-color:black;border-style:solid;border-width:1px;font-family:Arial, sans-serif;font-size:14px;
  overflow:hidden;padding:10px 5px;word-break:normal;}
.tg th{border-color:black;border-style:solid;border-width:1px;font-family:Arial, sans-serif;font-size:14px;
  font-weight:normal;overflow:hidden;padding:10px 5px;word-break:normal;}
.tg .tg-zowd{background-color:#FFF;border-color:inherit;color:#1A1B18;text-align:center;vertical-align:middle}
--></style>
<div style="text-align: start;">
<div style="text-align: start;">
<table class="tg">
<thead>
<tr>
<th class="tg-zowd"><strong>Regular Dimensions (L x W x H)</strong></th>
<th class="tg-zowd">42.3 X 15.1 X 16.5 (Inches)</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Folded Size (L x W x H)</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">31.5 X 12.6 X 11.8 (Inches)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Back Positions</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">6</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Back Options</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">19°, 32°, 44°, 58°, 76°,flat</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Seat Positions</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">4</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Seat Options</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">flat, 9°, 17°, 26°</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Backrest Length</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">29 inch / 74 cm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Weight Capacity</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">600 lb / 272 kg</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Suitable for User's Height</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">5'9'' / 175 cm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Product Weight</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">21.3 lbs / 9.66 kg</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p> </p>
<h4>Review</h4>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0444/1256/7702/files/Flybird_weight_bench_FB139_279_1feb17b2-7102-4623-8de4-418a5585db9b_480x480.jpg?v=1646049541" alt="Flybird adjustable workout bench FB139" width="480x480" height="480x480" style="float: none; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Honestly this is the best bench to get if you have a squat rack that is ready to use for benching , bent over rows, and shoulder press. It has great adjustments from decline to incline to shoulder press, as mentioned.  --- Juan R</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/products/flybird-adjustable-weight-bench" title="FLYBIRD Adjustable Weight Bench FB139"><strong>Learn more about Flybird adjustable weight bench FB139</strong></a></p>
<h3></h3>
<h3>Flybird Adjustable Weight Bench with Waist Pad</h3>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0444/1256/7702/files/Flybird_adjustable_workout_bench_with_waist_pad_600x600.jpg?v=1645879650" alt="Flybird adjustable workout bench with waist pad"></p>
<p>The Flybird Adjustable Weight Bench with Waist Pad is a highly rated adjustable weight bench that can be used in the home, at the gym, or while traveling. It provides you with a safe place to perform upper and lower body workouts with free weights. This fully assembled weight bench is made of high-quality materials and designed to increase strength, build muscle, lose weight and enhance physical fitness. The padded seat and back provide comfort during workouts.</p>
<h4>Features</h4>
<h5>Distinctive Waist Pad</h5>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0444/1256/7702/files/Flybird_Weight_Bench_with_Waist_Pad_600x600.png?v=1645880207" alt="Flybird Weight Bench with Waist Pad"></p>
<p>😉 The waist pad will protect your waist during fitness, it is designed with a wide and soft foam, ergonomic design offer more comforts</p>
<h5>Adjustable Foot Support</h5>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0444/1256/7702/files/Adjustable_Foot_Support.jpg?v=1646048879" alt="Flybird weight bench with adjustable leg extension"></p>
<div style="text-align: start;"></div>
<p>An extended footpad with three adjustable positions is suitable for different people. Full foam protects your feet and is more comfortable. Non-slip Foot Caps increase stability.</p>
<h4>Materials</h4>
<ul>
<li>Frame: Heavy-Duty Commercial Quality Frosted Steel</li>
<li>Backrest Cushion: 2" thick soft foam, covered in layer of PVC leather</li>
<li>Unique Waist Cushion with 2" soft foam padding</li>
</ul>
<h4>Product Specification</h4>
</div>
</div>
<style type="text/css"><!--
.tg  {border-collapse:collapse;border-spacing:0;}
.tg td{border-color:black;border-style:solid;border-width:1px;font-family:Arial, sans-serif;font-size:14px;
  overflow:hidden;padding:10px 5px;word-break:normal;}
.tg th{border-color:black;border-style:solid;border-width:1px;font-family:Arial, sans-serif;font-size:14px;
  font-weight:normal;overflow:hidden;padding:10px 5px;word-break:normal;}
.tg .tg-zowd{background-color:#FFF;border-color:inherit;color:#1A1B18;text-align:center;vertical-align:middle}
--></style>
<div style="text-align: start;">
<div style="text-align: start;">
<table class="tg">
<thead>
<tr>
<th class="tg-zowd"><strong>Regular Dimensions (L x W x H)</strong></th>
<th class="tg-zowd">42.3 X 15.1 X 16.5 (Inches)</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Folded Size (L x W x H)</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">31.5 X 12.6 X 11.8 (Inches)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Back Positions</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">6</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Back Options</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">19°, 32°, 44°, 58°, 76°,flat</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Seat Positions</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">4</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Seat Options</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">flat, 9°, 17°, 26°</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Backrest Length</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">29 inch / 74 cm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Weight Capacity</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">650 lb / 295 kg</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Suitable for User's Height</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">5'9'' / 175 cm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Product Weight</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">20.9 lbs / 9.5 kg</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p> </p>
<h4>Review</h4>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0444/1256/7702/files/Weight_Bench_with_Waist_Pad_22_020d877a-3040-46ee-bb4a-4b02fadb1be4_480x480.jpg?v=1646049018" alt="Flybird ajdustable weight bench with waistpad" width="480x480" height="480x480" style="float: none; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>I have been using it for a while, and I am quite satisfied with this bench. First of all, it is very easy to assemble. Simply follow the instruction and you should be good. Second, it is of great quality. I was recommended by my coach to have Flybird. And he is right, this bench is as sturdy as those benches in the gym. I am sitting comfortably on the bench with two 25lb dumbbells. Third, it is foldable and easy to store. It is a small piece when folded which won't take much space in the room. I am so glad that I get my own little gym in my house.   ----Jarh</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/products/flybird-adjustable-weight-bench-with-waist-pad" title="FLYBIRD Adjustable Weight Bench with Waist Pad"><strong>Learn more about Flybrid adjustable weight bench with waist pad</strong></a></p>
<h3></h3>
<h3>FLYBIRD Adjustable Weight Bench FB299</h3>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0444/1256/7702/files/FLYBIRD_Adjustable_Weight_Bench_FB299.jpg?v=1646036662" alt="FLYBIRD Adjustable Weight Bench FB299"></p>
<p>Customers love FLYBIRD Adjustable Bench because it delivers flawless results every time. It’s also extremely solid and stable. Best of all, it maximizes your home workouts by keeping you motivated and focused on the goals in front of you. This handy piece of workout equipment is vital to get the maximum results from your strength training or home gym-based workout. You can use it for weightlifting, bodybuilding, dumbbells, lifting exercises, and more.</p>
<h4>Features</h4>
<h5>Newly Upgraded Flybird Adjustable Weight Bench</h5>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0444/1256/7702/files/FLYBIRD_Adjustable_Weight_Bench_FB299_ccdc395d-d058-4f14-a6b6-54e190fefe72.jpg?v=1646038277" alt="FLYBIRD Adjustable Weight Bench FB299"></p>
<p>This new version of Flybird Adjustable Weight Bench is the ultimate multi-purpose training bench. The padded seat provides comfort during exercises, while the full-size seat gives more room for maneuvering your legs on exercises like glute kickbacks. Equipped with multiple adjustment positions for various exercises, plus an adjustable weight bar handle. This product is suitable for everyone from <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/beginners-guide-to-fitness-how-to-start-working-out-1" target="_blank" title="Beginners' Guide to Fitness - How to Start Working Out" rel="noopener noreferrer">beginners</a> to athletes.</p>
<h5>Weight Bench for Full-body Exercise</h5>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0444/1256/7702/files/FLYBIRD_Adjustable_Weight_Bench_FB299_2.png?v=1646037931" alt="FLYBIRD Adjustable Weight Bench FB299"></p>
<p>8 backrest positions and 3 seat positions meet your requirements for different kinds of workouts, such as incline &amp; decline dumbbell press. The quick-adjusting system and the locking mechanism are extremely convenient.</p>
<h4>Material</h4>
<ul>
<li>Frame: 2mm thickened steel frame</li>
<li>Backrest Cushion: 2" soft multi-layered padding, quality PU leather and dense stitches</li>
<li>Top-notch spring locking mechanism</li>
</ul>
<h4>Product Specification</h4>
</div>
</div>
<style type="text/css"><!--
.tg  {border-collapse:collapse;border-spacing:0;}
.tg td{border-color:black;border-style:solid;border-width:1px;font-family:Arial, sans-serif;font-size:14px;
  overflow:hidden;padding:10px 5px;word-break:normal;}
.tg th{border-color:black;border-style:solid;border-width:1px;font-family:Arial, sans-serif;font-size:14px;
  font-weight:normal;overflow:hidden;padding:10px 5px;word-break:normal;}
.tg .tg-zowd{background-color:#FFF;border-color:inherit;color:#1A1B18;text-align:center;vertical-align:middle}
--></style>
<div style="text-align: start;">
<div style="text-align: start;">
<table class="tg">
<thead>
<tr>
<th class="tg-zowd"><strong>Regular Dimensions (L x W x H)</strong></th>
<th class="tg-zowd">46.5 X 13.8 X 18.9 (Inches)</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Folded Size (L x W x H)</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">30.1 X 13.8 X 9.5 (Inches)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Back Positions</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">8</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Back Options</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">24°, 38°, 52°, 70°, 90°, flat, -9°, -30°</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Seat Positions</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Seat Options</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">flat, 12°, 23°</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Backrest Length</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">31 inch / 79 cm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Weight Capacity</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">700 lb / 318 kg</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Suitable for User's Height</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">6'2'' / 188 cm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Product Weight</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">29.8 lbs / 13.5 kg</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p> </p>
<h4>Review</h4>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0444/1256/7702/files/Flybird_adjustable_workout_bench_FB299_480x480.jpg?v=1646042840" alt="Flybird adjustable workout bench FB299" width="480x480" height="480x480" style="float: none; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>I really like this bench. First, the bench comes in a fairly compact box. The bench is easy to assemble with clear instructions. Once complete, the bench is very sturdy especially for how much the bench weighs. The range of incline is great. If you are looking for a very specific angle, this will get you there.<br>I don't really use decline, but it also has a ton of angles. The position of the foot hold is perfect to stay in place while in decline. While we are on the foot hold; it has a nice range of motion too with a locking pin. It is sturdy and simple.<br>This bench surprised me. It is really good for the price and perfect for anyone lifting with a full set of dumbbells.    --- McKinnon</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/products/flybird-adjustable-weight-bench-fb299" title="FLYBIRD Adjustable Weight Bench FB299"><strong>Learn more about Flybird adjustable weight bench FB299</strong></a></p>
<h3>Flybird Pro Weight Bench</h3>
<p> </p>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0444/1256/7702/files/Flybird_Pro_Weight_Bench.jpg?v=1646043224" alt="Flybird pro weight bench"></p>
<p>Flybird Pro Weight Bench is the most durable, the most easy-to-use, and the choice of pro gym instructors. It's ideal for home or commercial use.</p>
<h4>Features</h4>
<h5>Commercial Grade Steel Frame</h5>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0444/1256/7702/files/Flybird_Pro_Weight_Bench_2.png?v=1646046102" alt="Flybird Pro Weight Bench"></p>
<h5>Comfort and Stability</h5>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0444/1256/7702/files/Flybird_Pro_Weight_Bench_3.png?v=1646046573" alt="Flybird Pro Weight Bench"></p>
<p>Featuring a comfortable high-density foam padding and seat, this workout bench provides you a more comfortable and safe experience during your workout.</p>
<h4>Material</h4>
<ul>
<li>Frame: Commercial grade 40*80mm square steel and 4mm iron sheet</li>
<li>Backrest Cushion: 2.5" thick padding, durable PU leather, perfect stitches</li>
<li>Heavy-duty materials and one-piece solid steel structure</li>
</ul>
<h4>Product Specification</h4>
</div>
</div>
<style type="text/css"><!--
.tg  {border-collapse:collapse;border-spacing:0;}
.tg td{border-color:black;border-style:solid;border-width:1px;font-family:Arial, sans-serif;font-size:14px;
  overflow:hidden;padding:10px 5px;word-break:normal;}
.tg th{border-color:black;border-style:solid;border-width:1px;font-family:Arial, sans-serif;font-size:14px;
  font-weight:normal;overflow:hidden;padding:10px 5px;word-break:normal;}
.tg .tg-zowd{background-color:#FFF;border-color:inherit;color:#1A1B18;text-align:center;vertical-align:middle}
--></style>
<div style="text-align: start;">
<div style="text-align: start;">
<table class="tg">
<thead>
<tr>
<th class="tg-zowd"><strong>Regular Dimensions (L x W x H)</strong></th>
<th class="tg-zowd">48 X 13 X 17.7 (Inches)</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Folded Size</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">One-piece steel frame</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Back Positions</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">6</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Back Options</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">24°, 40°, 54°, 69°, 90°, flat</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Seat Positions</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">3</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Seat Options</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">0°, 13°, 25°</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Backrest Length</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">34.25 inch / 87 cm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Weight Capacity</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">1100 lb / 500 kg</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Suitable for User's Height</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">Unlimited</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Product Weight</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">49.8 lbs / 22.6 kg</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p> </p>
<h4>Review</h4>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0444/1256/7702/files/Flybird_Pro_weight_bench_a969bd94-11e8-4de9-9c9e-28dbdb6f8932_480x480.jpg?v=1646046810" alt="Flybird utility weight bench" width="480x480" height="480x480" style="float: none; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>I know this is not a cheap workout bench, but this thing is totally worth it. This bench is gym grade equipment. Quality materials, very well made + a few cool features such as adjustable legs to level with floor, a handle that helps recline the back, non slip pads under legs, soft and breathable padding. The back inclination has 6 levels and the seat has 3. Very versatile if you ask me. One thing I really like and shows the craftsmanship of this bench is the thickness of the frame. I know it might sound silly, but I love it.<br><br>If you’re serious about your home gym (or even your gym business), definitely consider the Flybird workout bench.  ---MyProductPortraits</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/products/flybird-pro-weight-bench" title="Flybird Pro Weight Bench"><strong>Learn more about Flybird pro weight bench</strong></a></p>
<h3>Flybird Foldable Flat Weight Bench</h3>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0444/1256/7702/files/Flybrid_flat_weight_bench.jpg?v=1646032899" alt="Flybird foldable weight bench"></p>
<p>Bigger and stronger, Flybird Foldable Workout Bench can support up to 1000 lbs. The legs and backrest are foldable, making the workout bench quite space-saving.</p>
<h4>Features:</h4>
<h5>No assembly &amp; Folding storage</h5>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0444/1256/7702/files/Flybird_flat_weight_bench.png?v=1646035183" alt="Flybird flat weight bench"></p>
<p>No assembly required, save your precious time. You can easily fold the bench up after your workout and put it in the corner or under the Bed. It saves you plenty of space.</p>
<h5>Comfortable Long Cushion</h5>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0444/1256/7702/files/Flybird_flat_weight_bench_2.png?v=1646035270" alt="Flybird flat weight bench" style="float: none;"></p>
<p>The bench frame is constructed with heavy-duty commercial quality steel, which ensures safety for your workout. The whole frame is processed with the best surface treatment to achieve a refined texture.</p>
<h4>Materials</h4>
<ul>
<li>Frame: Strong Construction and excellent Commercial Quality Steel</li>
<li>Seat Cushion: 2.5" thick padding, durable PU leather, perfect stitches</li>
<li>Four Non-slip foot caps</li>
</ul>
<h4>Product Specification</h4>
</div>
</div>
<style type="text/css"><!--
.tg  {border-collapse:collapse;border-spacing:0;}
.tg td{border-color:black;border-style:solid;border-width:1px;font-family:Arial, sans-serif;font-size:14px;
  overflow:hidden;padding:10px 5px;word-break:normal;}
.tg th{border-color:black;border-style:solid;border-width:1px;font-family:Arial, sans-serif;font-size:14px;
  font-weight:normal;overflow:hidden;padding:10px 5px;word-break:normal;}
.tg .tg-zowd{background-color:#FFF;border-color:inherit;color:#1A1B18;text-align:center;vertical-align:middle}
--></style>
<div style="text-align: start;">
<table class="tg">
<thead>
<tr>
<th class="tg-zowd"><strong>Regular Dimensions (L x W x H)</strong></th>
<th class="tg-zowd">45.3 X 11.8 X 16.93 (Inches)</th>
</tr>
</thead>
<tbody>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Folded Size (L x W x H)</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">45.3 X 11.8 X 8 (Inches)</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Bench Height</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">16.9 inch</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Bench Length</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">45.3 inch / 115 cm</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Weight Capacity</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">1000 lb / 455 kg</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Suitable for User's Height</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">Unlimited</td>
</tr>
<tr>
<td class="tg-zowd"><strong>Product Weight</strong></td>
<td class="tg-zowd">17.2 lbs / 7.8 kg</td>
</tr>
</tbody>
</table>
<p> </p>
<h4>Review</h4>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0444/1256/7702/files/Flybird_flat_weight_bench_480x480.jpg?v=1646047558" alt="Flybird flat weight bench" style="float: none; display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" width="480x480" height="480x480"></p>
<blockquote>
<p>This IS THE BENCH I WAS LOOKING FOR! I needed something that could support my 350+ lbs and foldable for easy storage Yet not risky and a waste of cash and time. When you want to get your “beast Mode” on at home THIS is the bench to buy and use! ---John M.</p>
<p> </p>
</blockquote>
<p><strong><a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/products/flybird-foldable-flat-weight-bench" title="FLYBIRD Foldable Flat Weight Bench">Learn more about Flybrid flat weight bench</a></strong></p>
<h3>Conclusion</h3>
<p>Flybird Fitness has serviced more than 1 million families and received thousands of positive <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/pages/reviews" title="Flybird Fitness review">reviews</a> from customers. The Flybrid weight bench is a great tool for people who want to exercise at home. It allows you to create your own home gym without much effort. <br><br>It’s sturdy and durable and can be customized to work well for all members of your family. Plus, the price is reasonable compared to other brands that don’t offer the same versatility or durability. So if you’re looking to purchase a weight bench for your home gym but haven’t yet settled on a model, you should consider Flybird.</p>
<p><strong> Relevant Articles:</strong></p>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/how-is-flybird-adjustable-bench-going-to-help-you-get-in-shape" title="How is Flybird Adjustable Bench Going to Help You Get in Shape?">How is Flybird Adjustable Bench Going to Help You Get in Shape?</a></li>
<li><a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/exercise-tips/4-popular-exercise-you-can-do-with-flybird-adjustable-dumbbells" title="Flybird Weight Bench: How to Use It To Lose Weight">Flybird Weight Bench: How to Use It To Lose Weight</a></li>
<li><a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/getting-stronger-with-a-weight-bench-at-home" title="Getting Stronger with a Weight Bench at Home">Getting Stronger with a Weight Bench at Home</a></li>
<li><a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/why-you-should-invest-in-a-flybird-fitness-weight-bench" title="Why You Should Invest In A Flybird Fitness Weight Bench">Why You Should Invest In A Flybird Fitness Weight Bench</a></li>
<li><a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/why-choose-flybird-weight-benches" title="Why Choose Flybird Weight Benches">Why Choose Flybird Weight Benches</a></li>
<li><a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/12-steps-to-finding-the-perfect-flybird-adjustable-bench" title="12 Steps to Find the Perfect Flybird Adjustable Bench">12 Steps to Find the Perfect Flybird Adjustable Bench</a></li>
<li><a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/10-compelling-reasons-why-you-need-flybird-weight-bench" title="10 Compelling Reasons Why You Need Flybird Weight Bench">10 Compelling Reasons Why You Need Flybird Weight Bench</a></li>
</ul>
</div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/2022-march-best-workout-plan-for-your-type</id>
    <published>2022-02-26T18:25:12+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-02-26T18:25:14+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/2022-march-best-workout-plan-for-your-type"/>
    <title>March 2022 - Best Workout Plan For Your Type</title>
    <author>
      <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[March 2022 - Best Workout Plan For Your Type always fighting with your partner about how much time you take in the gym? Find great resources here.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/2022-march-best-workout-plan-for-your-type">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Choosing the best <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/4-simple-steps-to-create-a-beginners-workout-plan" title="4 Simple Steps to Create a Beginner's Workout Plan">workout plan</a> for your type can be a bit challenging. It seems like everywhere you look, someone says that their workout program is the only option for getting fit. To make it even more confusing, they may not even be in the same industry as you are. This article will discuss the best workout plan for your type.</p>
<h2>
<br>Strength Training</h2>
<p><br>Strength Training is the most effective workout plan for you if you want to improve your strength and muscle definition. <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/weight-benches" title="Flybird adjustable workout bench">Flybird workout bench</a> allow you to build lean, sculpted muscles while reducing body fat and giving your body that athletic look. Strength training works by increasing the amount of lean muscle mass in your body while reducing excess fat tissue. This allows all of your workouts to be more efficient and effective and improves your metabolic rate. The high intensity of strength training workouts will make you less likely to burn out or become bored with your exercise routine.<br>When choosing a strength training workout plan, it is essential to find one that is structured well and caters to the goals you have for yourself. A personal trainer can help you choose which exercises work best for your needs based on their knowledge of your current abilities and limitations.</p>
<h2>
<br>High-Intensity Interval Training</h2>
<p><br>The best workout plan to help you meet your fitness goals is High-Intensity Interval Training. This workout routine has three components: aerobic exercise, anaerobic exercise, and resistance training. A team of experts developed the program at the NCAA, who have used this training regiment to help student-athletes gain the upper hand in strength and speed. When you try High-Intensity Interval Training for yourself, you will work to improve your endurance and cardiovascular health by building on your endurance and increasing your speed and agility. Along with these benefits, you will also <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/exercise-tips/4-popular-exercise-you-can-do-with-flybird-adjustable-dumbbells" title="Flybird Weight Bench: How to Use It To Lose Weight">lose weight</a> and feel more energized throughout the day.<br>Through the course of this workout plan, you will not only see significant changes in your physical appearance but also notice a huge difference in how you feel physically. As a bonus, you will find that you have more energy throughout the day than you did before to complete daily tasks without becoming winded or tired if you are looking to increase your stamina while shedding unwanted pounds.</p>
<h2>
<br>Jumping Rope</h2>
<p><br>This is one of the best workouts for your heart. It increases your heart rate and makes your blood flow faster. This means the body will be able to utilize oxygen better, which will also help you recover more quickly. If you have joint problems, jumping rope is a great alternative workout for you. It will let you exercise without causing further pain to the area. This can increase the intensity by adjusting the speed as well as the height of the jump.<br>Jump rope is also often used as part of various sports conditioning programs because it improves agility and coordination, which is crucial for sports performance.</p>
<h2>
<br>Aerobics</h2>
<p><br>Aerobics is a top-rated workout plan because it's so versatile. You can do it almost anywhere or in <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/weight-benches" title="Flybird Workout Bench">Flybird workout bench</a> with others to help <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/exercise-tips/5-ways-to-easily-stay-motivated-to-exercise" title="5 Ways To Easily Stay Motivated to Exercise">motivate</a> yourself and hold yourself accountable. You'll need an aerobic band, which you can get at any sporting goods store or online. You may want to get a mat as well to help protect your knees, ankles, and feet. You'll need to be wearing comfortable clothing that's not too restrictive so you can have free range of motion during your workout. The best way to get started with aerobics is to find an instructor comfortable within a class setting. It will allow you to see exactly how the instructor conducts their class and help you to figure out if it is the right atmosphere for you.</p>
<h2>
<br>Swimming</h2>
<p><br>Swimming is an excellent workout for people of all ages. It can be a low-impact exercise, even for people with joint pain, and it's easy on the eyes-no gym equipment is needed. The best swimming workout for you depends on your goals and what your body type is like. For example, if you want to build endurance, a swimming workout that incorporates drills might be appropriate. If you're trying to lose weight, swimming laps could help you with that since it burns so many calories. If you have joint pain, swimming might not be a good choice because repetitive motions can cause pain in your joints. Choosing the right workout plan is key to getting the most out of your time in the pool.</p>
<h2>
<br>Cycling or Spinning</h2>
<p><br>Cycling is suitable for body types that are pear-shaped or hourglass-shaped, or hips are more comprehensive than your waist and shoulders, and your thighs are more significant than your arms. This type of body is best suited for Cycling because most work will be done in the lower abdominal area. Cycling involves using a stationary bike, and the instructor will usually encourage you to use both legs to pedal. If a person with this body type attempts Spin class, they will experience discomfort in their knees and ankles due to the increased time spent in the air while cycling downhill. This could cause serious injury. Spinning is better suited for those with this body type because most of the time spent during a Spin class is on a stationary bike, which requires less movement from the knees and ankles than Cycling does.</p>
<h2>
<br>Yoga</h2>
<p><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0444/1256/7702/files/yoga-ga17241a31_1920.jpg?v=1645870550" alt="Yoga"></p>
<p><br>There is an ancient form of exercise, which has been enjoying a resurgence in popularity as people search for ways to reduce their stress, improve their focus, and strengthen their bodies. Practitioners often describe yoga as a mental practice that encourages them to focus on the present moment instead of thinking about their worries or regrets. It uses physical poses called asanas to build strength and flexibility with the mind, giving practitioners the tools to better deal with life's obstacles. Yoga can be divided into two main styles:</p>
<ul>
<li>Hatha Yoga focuses on body alignment and breathing techniques.</li>
<li>Ashtanga Yoga focuses on applying specific poses in a sequence.</li>
</ul>
<h2>
<br>Weight Lifting</h2>
<div style="text-align: left;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0444/1256/7702/files/sellscarsliftsbars.jpg?v=1645869810" alt="Weight Lifting with Flybird weight bench" style="float: none;"></div>
<p>Weight lifting is one of the most effective ways to stay in <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/how-is-flybird-adjustable-bench-going-to-help-you-get-in-shape" title="How is Flybird Adjustable Bench Going to Help You Get in Shape?">shape</a>, but it can be hard to know where to start. There are so many different styles of weight lifting and so many rules to ensure a safe workout can be hard to figure out what you should be doing and how you should be doing it. While some styles of weight lifting are better suited for certain people than others, some general rules apply to everyone, no matter what their body type. Always make sure you have a spotter when working out, and avoid lifts where you're putting your body weight in danger. Avoid charges that involve holding weights above your head or bending forward at the waist. These can overstrain your back and put unwanted stress on other areas like your knees or hips. Weightlifting using just your arms is also not recommended. you can try to weight lift on <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/weight-benches" title="Flybird adjustable weight bench">Flybird weight bench</a>.</p>
<h2>
<br>Pilates</h2>
<p><br>Pilates is a full-body workout that can help you improve your flexibility and strength. It's also been known to reduce stress and improve your mental focus. The exercises typically include a mix of both mat-based work and equipment-based work. They are designed to be safe enough for anyone to do but challenging enough for those who want an extra challenge. Pilates into your workout routine can improve your overall health and well-being in many ways:</p>
<ul>
<li>Improves breathing and respiration</li>
<li>Improves posture</li>
<li>Promotes better sleep</li>
<li>Reduces back pain and sciatica</li>
</ul>
<h2>
<br>Jogging</h2>
<p><br>The best workout plan for you depends on your body type. If you're tall, you might want to jog, but if you're short, your body probably isn't designed for jogging, and you'd be better off doing something else. Jogging is a type of exercise that uses the large muscles in your legs to move your body forward very quickly. Jogging is excellent for people looking to lose weight or get into shape. It's also great for people who have a lot of stress and need a form of exercise that's less intense than power walking but still gets their heart rate up. And it's also great if you have a condition like asthma because you can run outside to help treat your symptoms and still get in a good workout at the same time.</p>
<h2>
<br>Resistance Machines</h2>
<p><br>There are many types of resistance machines. The best workout plan for your type depends on the results you want to achieve and the equipment available to you. There are two main types of resistance machines: hydraulic and cable machines. Both types work similarly, but hydraulic machines use hydraulic pressure to create resistance, while cable machines use an extensive line and pulley system.</p>
<h2>
<br>Cable machines</h2>
<p><br>These are more portable than hydraulic ones because they don't require as much machinery or space to set up, but they can only be used with one specific weight at a time.</p>
<h2>
<br>Hydraulic and cable resistance machines</h2>
<p><br>These both use cam-based resistance systems activated by pulling or pressing handles on either side of the machine. If you want to get the most out of your workout, you should choose a device that allows for various exercises that target different muscle groups, such as chest press and triceps extensions. Hydraulic and cable resistance machines can help you build muscle mass and tone your muscles, in addition to increasing your strength. They may also help you improve balance, agility, flexibility, coordination.</p>
<h2>
<br>Conclusion</h2>
<p><br>Workout Plans are the cornerstone of any exercise program since they provide a step-by-step method that leads to a goal that is more of a way of life. The more we live by a plan and not just try to lose fat, tone muscle or increase stamina once in a while, the happier we are as far as results are concerned. And you can try you workout on Flybird workout bench.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/how-meal-planning-can-save-money</id>
    <published>2022-02-25T20:00:01+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-02-25T20:00:01+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/how-meal-planning-can-save-money"/>
    <title>How Meal Planning Can Save Money</title>
    <author>
      <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[When you start workout with <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/weight-benches" title="Flybrid weight bench">Flybird weight bench</a> or <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/dumbbells" title="Flybrid adjustable dumbbells">Flybird adjustable dumbbells</a>, don't forget to make a meal plan to better effect.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/how-meal-planning-can-save-money">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Meal planning is a great way to save money and reduce stress. It allows you to avoid the temptation of ready-made meals, which often include lots of extra calories, fat and salt.<br><br>Here are some key benefits:<br><br><strong>Saves time</strong>. You can prepare your meals for the week ahead in advance and store them in the fridge or freezer.<br><br><strong>Reduces stress</strong>. Knowing what you’re having for dinner means you don’t have to think about it at the end of a busy day.<br><br><strong>Reduces waste</strong>. Having less food hanging around will help you avoid throwing things away that have gone out of date.<br><br>Helps keep track of finances. If you tend to overspend on food, by writing a list and sticking to it, you’ll be able to see where you can cut back on costs.</p>
<p>Plan around your schedule. We all have different schedules and routines, so there's no single meal plan that works for everyone. Look at your schedule for the week, and figure out how much time you'll have for cooking each night. Maybe Sunday dinner is a big affair, while Wednesday is always takeout because of sports practice or meetings after work. Set realistic expectations, so you don't end up disappointed or frustrated with yourself if you can't cook an elaborate dinner three nights a week.</p>
<p>Think of a time when you've been so busy during the week, you didn't have time to shop for groceries. When you finally got around to it, you probably grabbed whatever was convenient in order to get through the week. Then, come Friday, you had already eaten almost everything and had to buy more food — and household supplies like toilet paper.<br><br>That's one of the common ways meal planning can save you money on groceries. When you plan your meals weekly (or even monthly), you are less likely to make those kinds of last-minute trips to the store or order takeout because there's nothing in the fridge.<br><br>Another way meal planning saves money is by creating a regular grocery shopping schedule that ensures your fridge will always be stocked with fresh produce and other ingredients. And if you're not running out for a quick late-night snack at the grocery store, you won't pick up snacks that aren't on your list or eat unhealthy food just because it's there.<br><br>There are many great apps that help with meal planning and organizing your shopping list, but if you don't want one more thing on your phone, it can be as simple as writing things down in an old-fashioned notebook.</p>
<p>Here is an example grocery list:</p>
<div style="text-align: start;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0444/1256/7702/files/Flybird_Fitness_meal_plan.jpg?v=1645616264" alt="Flybird Fitness meal plan"></div>
<div style="text-align: start;">You're probably already familiar with the concept of meal planning — you know, deciding what to eat for the week and then making a grocery list from those meals so you don't end up at the store without a clue. But aside from saving you time (and energy) on busy days, it can also help you save money. Here's how.<br><br><strong>Keeps food waste to a minimum</strong><br><br>One of the worst feelings is throwing out perfectly good food that went bad before you could eat it. How many times have you bought a bag of lettuce only to have it wilt in your fridge before you could finish it? Too many? Yeah, us too. With meal planning, though, that doesn't happen because you're only buying ingredients for meals that are planned out for the week. Eating whatever is left in your fridge when it gets down to the wire is fine once in a while, but if you're doing that every week, things are bound to go bad.<br><br><strong>Prevents impulse buys</strong><br><br>We swear we have self-control when we walk into Trader Joe's or Target — but somehow we always leave with way more than we needed. A new kitchen item here and there is fine, but those little purchases can really add up over time if they're not budgeted</div>
<div style="text-align: start;"></div>
<div style="text-align: start;">Besides, with a meal plan, you can make your <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/beginners-guide-to-fitness-how-to-start-working-out-1" title="Beginners' Guide to Fitness - How to Start Working Out">workout </a>more effectively. A meal plan is the foundation of a great workout plan. The right diet will help your body recover more quickly from your sessions, which will lead to greater results more quickly. Be careful not to let your diet get in the way of your exercise however. </div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/what-are-the-best-adjustable-dumbbells-to-buy</id>
    <published>2022-02-23T23:00:00+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-02-23T23:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/what-are-the-best-adjustable-dumbbells-to-buy"/>
    <title>What are the Best Adjustable Dumbbells to Buy</title>
    <author>
      <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Now that you've made the decision to buy adjustable dumbbells, how can you be sure you're getting the best deal? With so many brands and styles available, it's important to consider ease of use, weight ranges, construction quality and other factors. Newcomers to workout equipment may find themselves overwhelmed with options.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/what-are-the-best-adjustable-dumbbells-to-buy">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Adjustable dumbbells give you the freedom of adjusting the weight with ease.  Instead of having to go out and buy a bunch of different dumbbells and other weights, these are one product which will solve your problem. You no longer have to spend extra money on dumbbells which use to take up a lot of space in your house and gym. Now, these <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/dumbbells" title="Flybird adjustable dumbbells">adjustable dumbbells</a> will solve all your needs as they are created for people like you.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Q1: Dumbbell purchase advice?</h2>
<p> </p>
<h3><strong>Type: Adjustable dumbbells</strong></h3>
<h3><strong>Weight: Men's 11 lb- 20 lb; Women's 5 lb - 25 lb.</strong></h3>
<p><br><br><strong>√. Adjustable dumbbells, adjust the bell piece to adjust the weight.</strong><br><br>Maybe some of you will ask, do I really need this much weight? I probably won't even lift them, and I won't even use them for training, right? Weight is definitely required for training, and depending on the target muscle group and movement, weight should also be adjusted. Training weight at least 20% to 35% 1RM or more in order to have a certain effect on muscle building and losing weight.<br><br>No specific weight stimulation can have a minimal effect when women train their chest, buttocks, and these large muscle groups. When we run, jump, or walk with tens of kilograms of weight every day, the instantaneous impact that occurs may be several times to a dozen times the weight. Training it effectively cannot be achieved by exercising with a 2-pound mineral water bottle.<br><br>At first, many people feel the <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/products/flybird-adjustable-dumbbell-25-lbs-2-pieces" title="FLYBIRD Adjustable Dumbbell 25 LBS">25 lb dumbbell</a> is too heavy to lift. Instead of testing whether muscle strength is not sufficient, we can see if the force or training method needs to be mastered. Within a week or two, you will soon realize that 25 lb is not enough if you practice the right way.<br><br></p>
<h2>Q2: Dumbbells, how to choose the material?</h2>
<p> </p>
The most common dumbbell shell materials on the market are electroplated, baked enamel, plastic-coated, plastic dipped, and sponge. In general, I recommend buying electroplated or baked paint, which has no scent, is small, and won't rust. The only problem is they make it easy to scratch the floor or bump the table and chairs.<br><br>Dumbbells made of rubber and plastic are easy to smell. Some dumbbells can be expensive, but they're cost-effective in the sense that the outer layer of rubber protects the floor from damage.<br><br>It's true that the sponge dumbbells have a sponge cushion on the outside, so they look safe and won't damage furniture, but the problem is that they're a bit low-weight and can only be used for HIIT or training small muscle groups<br><br>
<h3><strong>√. Dumbbell material comparison.</strong></h3>
<p>Electroplating, baking paint: odorless, easy to scratch the floor.<br><br>Plastic coated, dipping: cheap smell, high price is low cost.<br><br>Sponge: safe and injury-free, the weight is too small.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Q3: What workout, with how much weight?</h2>
<p> </p>
<p>Rather than worrying about the weight of dumbbells, many people are concerned with how to choose the correct weight when exercising. Weight selection should be different based on muscle groups and workout.<br><br><br>General trunk muscle groups, large muscle groups, lower limbs, and multi-joint movements require relatively heavyweights. Deep squats, deadlifts, etc., are basically performed by people with training experience over 150kg; large muscle groups of the upper body such as bench press, high pull-down, etc., can also be performed at 100kg.<br><br>Because the arm, shoulder, and other small muscle groups at the end are small, and the muscle strength is small, the weight used to generate force is small. Biceps curls, arm flexors, etc., generally can bench press 100kg training people, and curls with 10kg training can be.<br><br>To avoid injury, posture correction training and exercises with smaller weights are recommended for some parts of the body that are easily injured.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2>Q4: What is the weight of dumbbell press for beginners?</h2>
<p> </p>
<p>Weight percentage refers to the percentage of maximum dumbbell weight. Boys are allowed to lift dumbbells up to 20kg and girls are allowed to lift dumbbells up to 10kg.</p>
<h2>Recommend: </h2>
<h3 class="product__title"><a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/products/flybird-adjustable-dumbbell-25lbs" title="FLYBIRD Adjustable Dumbbell 25 LBS">Flybird Adjustable Dumbbell 25 LBS</a></h3>
<h3 class="product__title"><a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/products/flybird-55lbs-adjustable-dumbbell" title="Flybird  Adjustable Dumbbell 55 LBS">Flybird  Adjustable Dumbbell 55 LBS</a></h3>
<div class="no-js-hidden" id="price-template--14932627980481__main">
<div class="price price--large price--on-sale ">
<div class="price__sale"></div>
</div>
</div>
<p> </p>
<div class="no-js-hidden" id="price-template--14932618117313__main">
<div class="price price--large price--on-sale ">
<div class="price__sale"></div>
</div>
</div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/roadtrip-workout-routines-how-to-stay-fit-when-roadtripping</id>
    <published>2022-02-22T23:00:00+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-03-01T15:13:40+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/roadtrip-workout-routines-how-to-stay-fit-when-roadtripping"/>
    <title>Roadtrip Workout Routines: How to Stay Fit When Roadtripping</title>
    <author>
      <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[When going on a road trip, the one thing you want to be sure of is that you can have fun while also staying fit. After all, who wants to spend an entire vacation stuck in their hotel room? The good news is that there are plenty of affordable and fun ways to stay fit on a road trip.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/guide/roadtrip-workout-routines-how-to-stay-fit-when-roadtripping">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>You've finally saved up enough money and vacation time to take that road trip you've been dreaming about. You can't wait to hit the open road, see new things and meet some interesting people along the way.<br><br>However, with all the excitement of your upcoming trip, you might be feeling a bit nervous about how this adventure will affect your fitness routine.<br><br>Staying fit is always a challenge, but you'll face an even bigger struggle if you're planning to hit the road for an extended period of time. After all, a lot of people think that the most important part about road tripping is eating and drinking at all those awesome roadside restaurants and bars. Even if you manage to get in a workout before you leave, how can you be sure to stick to your routine when you're on the road?<br><br>Well, there are a couple of ways that you can stay fit while on the road. The first one involves simply finding hotels and stops along the way that have gyms. However, this isn't always possible and it can also be quite expensive over the course of your trip. Another option is to bring your own fitness equipment with you. This could include a yoga mat, resistance bands or even a <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/weight-benches" title="Flybird weight bench">Flybird weight bench</a>!</p>
<p>Cody and Kellie Oden. The husband and wife team – a mild-mannered accountant and dental assistant, respectively, by day – slip into their camping and kayaking alter egos every weekend. </p>
<div style="text-align: left;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0444/1256/7702/files/3_106ff9c2-9722-4f2a-aadc-b651d21ed360.jpg?v=1645444102" alt="Flybird Fitness" style="float: none;"></div>
<p><span>Being outdoors in nature is a way to recharge your mind, body, and soul! We enjoy hiking, mountain biking, cooking, and kayaking!</span></p>
<p>Follow them on Youtube channel <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCRDJcwYEWmDPSmYd3lsBtvg/featured" target="_blank" title="DOME LIFE" rel="noopener noreferrer">Dome Life</a>.</p>
<p><span><br>Now the first one is a great one because it's going to work your core, your quads, your glutes, and your hamstrings. All you have to do is find an elevated surface like this picnic table, place one foot on top of it, then jump up and go into that lunge position. Make sure that you're not leaning forward or backward. Do a nice controlled lunge and then jump back up to the original position with both feet on the ground. You can also switch legs after you do 20 of them. So we're just going to add this in so that we work all of our legs evenly.<br><br>The next exercise is an awesome way to work your core and obliques because you're gonna get those knees moving side to side and engaging your obliques as well as engaging your core during those jumps. So what you're gonna do is get down into a squat position with arms straight out in front of you, then jump up and take those knees across yourself side to side, alternating which knee goes across first each time.</span></p>
<p>A great solution is the <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/weight-benches" title="Flybird workout bench">FlyBird workout bench</a>. It's a adjustable and portable workout bench, easy to fold to store in car. You can use it to do push-ups and sit-ups outside. If you more space, you can buy a set of <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/dumbbells" title="Flybrid adjustable dumbbells">Flybird adjustable dumbbells</a> to do some <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/workouts/4-popular-exercise-you-can-do-with-flybird-adjustable-dumbbells" title="4 Popular Exercise You Can Do With Flybird Adjustable Dumbbells">dumbbell exercise</a> to increase strength.</p>
<div style="text-align: left;"><img src="https://cdn.shopify.com/s/files/1/0444/1256/7702/files/2_bca5699b-c7d9-474a-a020-fafaa19b19b0.jpg?v=1645444890" alt="Flybrid Fitness" style="float: none;"></div>
<p><span> </span></p>
<p><span><br>You could even take it camping and use it as a camping bench for hiking or lightweight fitness routines (although I don't recommend hiking on an incline with a 10-pound backpack!).</span></p>
<p> <iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/680263346?h=9d2369d532" width="640" height="360" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<p><span>Of course, this is in no way a comprehensive look at road trip fitness routines. These are only a few ideas that you can incorporate into your vacation trips to keep your body moving while on the road. Be sure to throw in some extra time at rest stops, and to plan ahead. If the opportunity arises, look for parks or sidewalk trails to stretch out any sore muscles. And if you're in an RV, try to find a spot near a lake or a river so you can catch some exercise by water sports as well!</span></p>
<p><span>These routines are just part of what it takes to staying fit and healthy on vacation. You’ll also need to maintain a proper diet, because what you put into your body has an impact on how the rest of your body functions. Last but not least, you need to be careful about the amount of time you spend in your vehicle each day and how it impacts your sleep cycle. All in all, these workouts are designed to help keep your focus on fitness while you are traveling and will hopefully provide some new ideas that you can use when you're out of town.</span></p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
