<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xml:lang="en-US" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:opensearch="http://a9.com/-/spec/opensearch/1.1/" xmlns:s="http://jadedpixel.com/-/spec/shopify">
  <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/workouts.atom</id>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/workouts"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/workouts.atom"/>
  <title>Flybird Fitness - Workouts</title>
  <updated>2022-03-17T20:29:11+08:00</updated>
  <author>
    <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
  </author>
  <entry>
    <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/workouts/everyone-s-favorite-ab-workout-you-can-do-it-at-home</id>
    <published>2022-03-17T20:29:11+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-03-17T20:29:11+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/workouts/everyone-s-favorite-ab-workout-you-can-do-it-at-home"/>
    <title>Everyone’s Favorite Ab Workout – You can do it at home!</title>
    <author>
      <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Our Favorite Ab Workout - You can do it at home!<p><a class="read-more" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/workouts/everyone-s-favorite-ab-workout-you-can-do-it-at-home">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<p>Finding the time to work out can be hard. Between work, family, and friends you can feel like you have no extra time to find individually for each. If you’re looking for a way to stay in shape that doesn’t take a lot of time and effort, we’ve found that the <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/weight-benches" title="Flybird Adjustable weight bench">flybird weight bench</a> has been a great option to consider. It will help you build your abs, increase your strength and improve your performance also. When it comes to being able to lose weight effectively, Flybird Weight Bench has proven to get results while saving you time.</p>
<p>Finally, a home ab workout that works! Not only is this workout simple and easy to follow but it will get you great results. It's a favorite because it's so effective.</p>
<h2>Warm Up</h2>
<p>The most important part of your workout is your warm up! It gets your blood pumping, your muscles activated and helps protect you from injuries.<br><br>My simple warm up routine:</p>
<ul>
<li>20 Push Ups</li>
<li>20 Squats</li>
<li>20 Rows</li>
</ul>
<p><br>Getting your body moving the right way from the start is going to give you a better workout!</p>
<p><iframe width="684" height="385" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cAFdjeXhaoI" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></p>
<h2>Bench Crunch</h2>
<p>A bench crunch is great for your upper abs. Start by putting your feet on the bench. Hold yourself up with your arms straight behind you and then crunch up towards the ceiling. Go slowly so that you feel the burn in your abs rather than momentum doing the work. Do three sets of 15-20 reps.</p>
<h2>Leg Raises</h2>
<p>The leg raise is one of the easiest exercises you can perform in your home to strengthen and tone your lower abdominal muscles. Begin by lying on the floor with your back flat against it. Place your hands palms down at your sides. Slowly raise both legs straight up towards the ceiling until they are perpendicular to the floor. Return to the starting position, but stop just short of touching the floor (this will prevent momentum from taking over). Complete three sets of 12-15 reps.</p>
<h2>Sit-ups</h2>
<p>Sit-ups are the most common abdominal exercise and perhaps the most effective.<br><br>Lie down on your back, with your knees bent and your hands behind your head. Tighten your abdominals, exhaling as you lift your body up and forward until you touch your knees with your elbows. Lower yourself back down, inhaling as you do so. Repeat.</p>
<h2>Decline Reverse Crunches</h2>
<p>The Decline Reverse Crunches are a great exercise to strengthen your lower abs. Here's how to do it properly:<br><br>Lie on the bench with your head hanging off the end and hold a <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/dumbbells" title="Flybird adjustable dumbbell">dumbbell</a> between your feet.<br><br>With your lower back pressed flat into the bench and your hips off the end, raise your legs until they're perpendicular to the floor. Make sure you don't arch or strain your back during this movement.<br><br>Contract your abdominal muscles and slowly lower your legs as far as you can without lifting the butt off the bench.<br><br>Pause and return to the starting position. Do not rest at any point in this exercise.</p>
<p> </p>
<p>I hope you enjoyed this workout! Start an in-home ab workout routine today with the Flybird weight bench.</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/workouts/5-workouts-you-can-do-during-your-lunch-break</id>
    <published>2022-02-24T22:30:01+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-02-24T22:30:01+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/workouts/5-workouts-you-can-do-during-your-lunch-break"/>
    <title>5 Workouts You Can Do During Your Lunch Break</title>
    <author>
      <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[You don't have a lot of time to spare. You may have heard that working out is good for your physical health, but did you know that it can also increase your productivity? Let's talk about the top 5 lunchtime workouts, and how they can help you during the work day!<p><a class="read-more" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/workouts/5-workouts-you-can-do-during-your-lunch-break">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h2>1. Flybird Bench Press</h2>
<p><br>The <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/weight-benches" title="Flybrid workout bench">Flybird Weight Bench</a> is one of our best-selling products because it is incredibly versatile and can be used for a full-body workout. If you only have <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/workouts/20-minute-home-workout-flybird-55lb-adjustable-dumbbells-only" title="20-Minute Home Workout with Flybird Adjustable Dumbbells 55 lb ">20</a> minutes before you need to get back to the office, try this quick but effective chest workout.<br><br>The Flybird Bench Press is an excellent exercise for building strength in your chest, shoulders, and arms. Because it's adjustable, it's also great for targeting different muscle groups depending on what angle you use.<br><br>Here's how:<br><br>Lie down on the weight bench and adjust the pad if necessary so that it is level with your lower pec line (slightly below your nipples.) Grab the barbell with both hands slightly wider than shoulder-width apart, making sure your arms are perpendicular to the floor.</p>
<h2>2. Dumbbell Workouts</h2>
<p><br>If your job keeps you chained to a desk all day, try packing one or two sets of the <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/dumbbells" title="Flybird adjustable dumbbells">Flybird Adjustable Dumbbells</a> in your work bag to squeeze in a quick workout during lunch. For example, you can try the following workout routine:<br><br><strong>5 minutes of stretching and warmup exercises</strong><br><br></p>
<ul>
<li>10 reps each x 3 rounds:</li>
<li>Squats with overhead press</li>
<li>Overhead triceps extension</li>
<li>Bicep curl into overhead press</li>
<li>Reverse lunge into bicep curl*</li>
</ul>
<h2>3. Strength Training</h2>
<p><br>What You'll Need: A set of dumbbells (adjustable weights are great for at-home use) and something to sit on.<br><br>50 Pushups, 50 Situps, 50 Bodyweight Squats. Repeat up to 10 times. This is a great strength workout that can be done anywhere and doesn't require any equipment! If you really want to push yourself, add some extra weight using dumbbells or a kettlebell (or even a bag of flour!).</p>
<h2>4. Circuit Training</h2>
<p>If you're strapped for time and want to maximize your fitness, circuit training is the perfect workout for you. Circuit training combines cardiovascular exercise with strength training. It's an intense workout that builds muscle and burns fat.</p>
<p><br><strong>How it works:</strong><br><br>Circuit training is any type of exercise in which you move from one activity to the next with little or no rest in between. To keep things interesting and prevent your muscles from reaching a plateau, you will typically change your routine every six weeks or so.<br><br><strong>The Benefits:</strong><br><br>Circuit training allows you to work for several major muscle groups at once, so it can save time while giving you a great workout. You can also burn more calories when working out on a circuit compared to performing individual exercises.<br><br>You will see great results in both physical strength and endurance as long as you stick with the program.</p>
<h2>5. Balance Workout</h2>
<p>For this workout, you’ll need two chairs of equal height.</p>
<p><br>Set up the chairs facing each other and sit comfortably in one with both feet on the ground.<br><br>Lift one leg and extend it out straight in front of you, pointing it toward the ceiling. Hold it there for three seconds, then repeat with the opposite leg. Keep alternating legs until you’ve done 20 total reps (10 on each leg).<br><br>Then, bring both legs to a 90-degree angle so they’re parallel to the floor. Lower one leg until your foot is flat on the floor, then hold it there for three seconds before switching to the other side. Repeat 20 times (10 on each side).</p>
<p>There’s a full range of exercises you can do on a <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/weight-benches" title="Flybird weight bench">weight bench</a>. So, definitely bring it to the office. And make use of those lunch hours!</p>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/workouts/20-minute-home-workout-flybird-55lb-adjustable-dumbbells-only</id>
    <published>2022-02-16T23:00:00+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-02-16T23:00:00+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/workouts/20-minute-home-workout-flybird-55lb-adjustable-dumbbells-only"/>
    <title>20-Minute Home Workout with Flybird 55 lb Adjustable Dumbbells</title>
    <author>
      <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[Today I bring to you a fitness routine I’ve been using for 3 years. It takes 20-minutes and requires a set of Flybird Adjustable Dumbbells.<p><a class="read-more" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/workouts/20-minute-home-workout-flybird-55lb-adjustable-dumbbells-only">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;">Today we're giving you our favorite dumbbell workout for getting solid, lean, definition. I LOVE these <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/collections/dumbbells" title="Flybird adjustable dumbbells">adjustable dumbbells</a> from <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/" title="Flybird Fitness">FlyBird</a>, and use them in my own home gym. From this set of weights to a jump rope and some apps - you can totally work up a sweat, and feel great in your own home! </div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<div style="text-align: center;"><iframe width="1182" height="665" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/_OQaEz5WazU" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;"></div>
<div style="text-align: center;">Dumbbell Workout V.1 - Exercise List</div>
<div style="text-align: center;"></div>
<div style="text-align: left;">-Rules:</div>
<div style="text-align: left;">
<ul>
<li>Complete each "block" before moving onto the next</li>
<li>30-45 seconds of rest between exercises</li>
<li>45-60 seconds of rest between sets/blocks</li>
<li>Heavier weight = less reps, Lighter weights = more reps</li>
<li>Emphasis on proper form!</li>
</ul>
<p>-Equipment: <a href="https://flybirdfitness.com/products/flybird-55lbs-adjustable-dumbbell" title="Flybird 55lbs Adjustable Dumbbell">Flybird 55 lb Adjustable Dumbbell</a></p>
<p>-A-Block: x 2-4 Sets</p>
<p>A1) Goblet Squat x 6-8</p>
<p>A2) Floor Press 10-12</p>
<p>A3) High Plank Pull-Through x 8-10 Ea. Direction</p>
<p>-B-Block: 2-4 Sets</p>
<p>B1) Romanian Deadlift (RDL) x 6-8 </p>
<p>B2) Single-Arm Row x 10-12 Ea. Arm</p>
<p>B3) Russian Twist x 15-20 Ea. Direction</p>
<p>-C-Block: 2-4 Sets</p>
<p>C1) Lateral Raise x 12-15 </p>
<p>C2) Alternating Bicep Curl x 12-15</p>
<p>C3) Narrow-Grip Pushup x A.M.R.A.P (To Failure, Proper Form)</p>
</div>]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <id>https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/workouts/4-popular-exercise-you-can-do-with-flybird-adjustable-dumbbells</id>
    <published>2020-11-03T18:08:18+08:00</published>
    <updated>2022-02-22T14:42:52+08:00</updated>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/workouts/4-popular-exercise-you-can-do-with-flybird-adjustable-dumbbells"/>
    <title>4 Popular Exercise You Can Do With Flybird Adjustable Dumbbells</title>
    <author>
      <name>Flybird Fitness</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">
      <![CDATA[<span>Ever thought about getting a workout bench for your home fitness center? If you have, then you need to know about some of the popular exercises you can do with a workout bench. There are multiple types of exercise that you can perform with a workout bench. You should consider which exercise will work well with your fitness level and physical needs.</span><p><a class="read-more" href="https://flybirdfitness.com/blogs/workouts/4-popular-exercise-you-can-do-with-flybird-adjustable-dumbbells">More</a></p>]]>
    </summary>
    <content type="html">
      <![CDATA[<h2><strong>EXERCISE 1: BENCH PRESS WITH DUMBBELLS</strong></h2>
Even if you cannot lift as much as with a barbell, the bench press with dumbbells allows you to work your pecs differently, with better range and a more natural movement.<br><br><strong>Main targeted muscles: pectorals, shoulders, triceps.</strong><br><br>Performing the exercise: lie on your weights bench, slightly arch your back and put your feet flat on the ground. Take a dumbbell in each hand. Stretch your arms out vertically, bringing the dumbbells together. Remember to pull your shoulders back and contract your pectoral muscles. From this high position, slowly lower the dumbbells down to each side of your chest. Without bouncing back, contract your pecs and press (push) the dumbbells back up, bringing them together as they reach the top (the dumbbells should touch at the end of movement = converging movement).<br> <br>Safety instructions: your head, shoulders and buttocks must remain resting against the bench. They help to anchor you. Without this stability, there is no strength. When you bring the dumbbells down, keep your elbows in line with your shoulders. In the high position, do not lock your elbows in order not to damage the elbow joint.<br> <br>
<h2>EXERCISE 2: INCLINED PRESS WITH DUMBBELLS</h2>
This exercise with dumbbells allows a more comprehensive and natural movement than with a barbell. It is useful as a complement to the bench press to rebalance your pectoral muscles, as it focuses more on the upper part.<br><br><strong>Main targeted muscles: pectorals, shoulders, triceps.</strong><br><br>Performing the exercise: lie on your weights bench, inclined between 15° to 45°. Slightly arch your back and put your feet flat on the ground. Take a dumbbell in each hand. Stretch your arms out vertically, bringing the dumbbells together. Remember to pull your shoulders back and contract your pectoral muscles. From this high position, breathe in and then slowly lower the dumbbells down to each side of your chest. Without bouncing back, contract your pecs and press (push) the dumbbells back up, bringing them together as they reach the top (the dumbbells should touch at the end of movement = converging movement).<br><br>Safety tips: your head, shoulders and buttocks must remain resting against the bench. They help to anchor you. Without this stability, there is no strength. When you bring the dumbbells down, keep your elbows in line with your shoulders. In the high position, do not lock your elbows in order not to damage the elbow joint.<br>
<h4></h4>
<h2><strong>EXERCISE 3: DUMBBELL PULLOVER</strong></h2>
<p><br><strong>Main targeted muscles: pectoralis major, long head of the triceps, teres major, latissimus dorsi.</strong><br> <br>Performing the exercise: lay down on your weights bench. Pick up a dumbbell with both hands and extend your arms above your head. Take a deep breath and lower the dumbbell behind your head, with your elbows slightly bent. Breathe out whilst returning to your starting position.<br><br>Safety tips: your head, shoulders and buttocks must remain resting against the bench.</p>
<p> </p>
<h2><strong>EXERCISE 4: DUMBBELL ROW</strong></h2>
<strong>Main targeted muscles: latissimus dorsi, teres major, posterior deltoid (back of shoulder), brachioradialis (supinator longus).</strong><br> <br>Performing the exercise: stand up next to your weights bench. Put one knee on the bench, leave your other foot on the ground. Take a dumbbell in one hand, steady yourself against the bench with the other hand. Contract your back then bring your elbow back, as high as you can go, to raise the dumbbell.<br><br>Safety tips: to protect your lower back, keep your back flat during the exercise. With each rep, lift the dumbbell without any jerky movements.]]>
    </content>
  </entry>
</feed>
